# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.1.0
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.1.0.0
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.1.0.0.1
# text = Good morning, everyone, the session begins.
1	Good	good	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	morning	morning	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	everyone	everyone	PRON	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	begins	begin	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.1.0.1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.1.0.1.1
# text = Before we begin the agenda, however, I would like to greet on behalf of the House the representatives of Parliament, the representative of the Generality, ex- MPs and authorities who are accompanying us today.
1	Before	before	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	begin	begin	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	agenda	agenda	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	however	however	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	would	would	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	like	like	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	greet	greet	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	behalf	behalf	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
19	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	representatives	representative	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	representative	representative	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	Generality	Generality	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	ex	ex	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	MPs	mp	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	authorities	authority	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	who	who	PRON	WP	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	accompanying	accompany	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	us	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	today	today	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
40	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.0
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.0.1
# text = Esther Niubó Cidoncha : « No. »
1	Esther	Esther	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Niubó	Niubó	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Cidoncha	Cidoncha	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.1.1
# text = Joan Josep Nuet i Pujals: "No. »
1	Joan	Joan	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Josep	Josep	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Nuet	Nuet	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Pujals	Pujal	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
6	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	No	no	INTJ	UH	Polarity=Neg	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.2
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.2.1
# text = Óscar Ordeig i Molist : « No. »
1	Óscar	Óscar	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Ordeig	Ordeig	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Molist	Molist	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.3
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.3.1
# text = Mònica Palacín Paris : « Yes. »
1	Mònica	Mònica	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
2	Palacín	Palacín	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Paris	Paris	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.4
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.4.1
# text = Teresa Pallarès Piqué: "Yes. »
1	Teresa	Teresa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Pallarès	Pallarès	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Piqué	Piqué	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.5
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.5.1
# text = Ferran Pedret i Santos: "No. »
1	Ferran	Ferran	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Pedret	Pedret	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Santos	Santos	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	No	no	INTJ	UH	Polarity=Neg	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.6
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.6.1
# text = Óscar Peris and Ròdenas : « Yes. »
1	Óscar	Óscar	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Peris	Peris	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Ròdenas	Ròdenas	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.7
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.7.1
# text = Carles Puigdemont and Casamajó. ( Elsa Artadi and Vila said: "Yes. ')
1	Carles	Carles	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Puigdemont	Puigdemont	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Casamajó	Casamajó	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	(	(	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Elsa	Elsa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
8	Artadi	Artadi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
9	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Vila	Vila	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
11	said	say	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	')	')	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.8
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.8.1
# text = Eduard Pujol i Bonell: "Yes. »
1	Eduard	Eduard	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Pujol	Pujol	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Bonell	Bonell	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.9
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.9.1
# text = Xavier Quinquillà Durich: "Yes. »
1	Xavier	Xavier	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Quinquillà	Quinquillà	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Durich	Durich	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.10
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.10.1
# text = Marta Ribas Frías : « No. »
1	Marta	Marta	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Ribas	Ribas	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Frías	Frías	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.11
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.11.1
# text = Rut Ribas i Martí: "Yes. »
1	Rut	Rut	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Ribas	Ribas	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Martí	Martí	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.12
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.12.1
# text = Carles Riera Albert : « Abstention. »
1	Carles	Carles	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Riera	Riera	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Albert	Albert	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Abstention	abstention	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.13
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.13.1
# text = Josep Riera i Font : « Yes. »
1	Josep	Josep	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Riera	Riera	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Font	Font	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.14
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.14.1
# text = Javier Rivas Escamilla: "No. »
1	Javier	Javier	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Rivas	Rivas	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Escamilla	Escamilla	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.15
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.15.1
# text = Manuel Rodríguez de l'Hotellerie de Fallois : « No. »
1	Manuel	Manuel	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Rodríguez	Rodríguez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	de	de	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	l'Hotellerie	l'Hotellerie	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
5	de	de	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
6	Fallois	Fallois	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
7	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.16
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.16.1
# text = David Rodríguez i González: "Yes. »
1	David	David	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Rodríguez	Rodríguez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	González	González	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.17
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.17.1
# text = Santi Rodríguez i Serra : « No. »
1	Santi	Santi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Rodríguez	Rodríguez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Serra	Serra	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.18
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.18.1
# text = Lorena Roldán Suárez : « No. »
1	Lorena	Lorena	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Roldán	Roldán	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Suárez	Suárez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.19
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.19.1
# text = Alicia Romero Llano : « No. »
1	Alicia	Alicia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Romero	Romero	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Llano	Llano	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.20
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.20.1
# text = Raül Romeva i Rueda. ( Sergi Sabria and Benito said: "Yes. ')
1	Raül	Raül	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Romeva	Romeva	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Rueda	Rueda	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	(	(	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Sergi	Sergi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
8	Sabria	Sabria	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
9	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Benito	Benito	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
11	said	say	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	')	')	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.21
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.21.1
# text = Ferran Roquer i Padrosa: "Yes. »
1	Ferran	Ferran	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Roquer	Roquer	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Padrosa	Padrosa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.22
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.22.1
# text = Josep Rull and Andreu. ( Elsa Artadi and Vila said: "Yes. ')
1	Josep	Josep	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Rull	Rull	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Andreu	Andreu	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	(	(	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Elsa	Elsa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
8	Artadi	Artadi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
9	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Vila	Vila	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
11	said	say	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	')	')	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.23
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.23.1
# text = Sergi Sabria and Benito: "Yes. »
1	Sergi	Sergi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Sabria	Sabria	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Benito	Benito	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.24
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.24.1
# text = Mònica Sales de la Cruz : « Yes. »
1	Mònica	Mònica	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
2	Sales	sale	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
3	de	de	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
4	la	la	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-LOC
5	Cruz	Cruz	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-LOC
6	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.25
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.25.1
# text = Josep Lluís Salvató i Tenesa : « Yes. »
1	Josep	Josep	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Lluís	Lluís	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Salvató	Salvató	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Tenesa	Tenesa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
6	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.26
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.26.1
# text = Natalia Sánchez Dipp : « Abstention. »
1	Natalia	Natalia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Sánchez	Sánchez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Dipp	Dipp	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Abstention	abstention	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.27
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.27.1
# text = Alfonso Sánchez Fisac: "No. »
1	Alfonso	Alfonso	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Sánchez	Sánchez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Fisac	Fisac	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.28
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.28.1
# text = Jordi Sánchez and Picanyol. ( Elsa Artadi and Vila said: "Yes. ')
1	Jordi	Jordi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Sánchez	Sánchez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Picanyol	Picanyol	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	(	(	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Elsa	Elsa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
8	Artadi	Artadi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
9	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Vila	Vila	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
11	said	say	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	')	')	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.29
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.29.1
# text = Carlos Sánchez Martín: "No. »
1	Carlos	Carlos	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Sánchez	Sánchez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Martín	Martín	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.30
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.30.1
# text = Sergio Sanz Jiménez: "No. »
1	Sergio	Sergio	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Sanz	Sanz	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Jiménez	Jiménez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.31
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.31.1
# text = Susana Segovia Sánchez: "No. »
1	Susana	Susana	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Segovia	Segovia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Sánchez	Sánchez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.32
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.32.1
# text = Sonia Sierra Infante: "No. »
1	Sonia	Sonia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Sierra	Sierra	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Infante	Infante	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.33
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.33.1
# text = Beatriz Silva Gallardo : « No. »
1	Beatriz	Beatriz	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Silva	Silva	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Gallardo	Gallardo	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.34
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.34.1
# text = Maria Sirvent Scrig : « Abstention. »
1	Maria	Maria	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Sirvent	Sirvent	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Scrig	Scrig	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Abstention	abstention	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.35
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.35.1
# text = Bernat Sole i Barril: "Yes. »
1	Bernat	Bernat	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Sole	Sole	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Barril	Barril	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.36
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.36.1
# text = Jorge Soler González: "No. »
1	Jorge	Jorge	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Soler	Soler	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	González	González	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.37
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.37.1
# text = Marc Solsona and Aixalà: "Yes. »
1	Marc	Marc	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Solsona	Solsona	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Aixalà	Aixalà	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.38
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.38.1
# text = Anna Tarrés i Campà: "Yes. »
1	Anna	Anna	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Tarrés	Tarré	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Campà	Campà	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.39
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.39.1
# text = Francesc Ten i Costa : « Yes. »
1	Francesc	Francesc	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Ten	ten	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Costa	Costa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.40
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.40.1
# text = Jordi Terrades i Santacreu: "No. »
1	Jordi	Jordi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Terrades	Terrade	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Santacreu	Santacreu	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.41
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.41.1
# text = Quim Torra i Pla: "Yes. »
1	Quim	Quim	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Torra	Torra	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Pla	Pla	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.42
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.42.1
# text = Jordi Tourull and Black. ( Elsa Artadi and Vila said: "Yes. ')
1	Jordi	Jordi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Tourull	Tourull	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Black	Black	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	(	(	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Elsa	Elsa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
8	Artadi	Artadi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
9	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Vila	Vila	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
11	said	say	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	')	')	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.43
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.43.1
# text = Elisabeth Valencia Mimbrero : « No. »
1	Elisabeth	Elisabeth	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Valencia	Valencia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Mimbrero	Mimbrero	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.44
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.44.1
# text = María Francisca Valle Fuentes : « No. »
1	María	María	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Francisca	Francisca	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Valle	Valle	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	Fuentes	Fuentes	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.45
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.45.1
# text = Francesc Viaplana Manresa : « Yes. »
1	Francesc	Francesc	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Viaplana	Viaplana	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Manresa	Manresa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.46
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.46.1
# text = Laura Vílchez Sánchez: "No. »
1	Laura	Laura	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Vílchez	Vílchez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Sánchez	Sánchez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.47
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.47.1
# text = Ruben Wagensberg Ramon : « Yes. »
1	Ruben	Ruben	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Wagensberg	Wagensberg	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Ramon	Ramon	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.48
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.48.1
# text = Elisenda Alamany Gutiérrez : « No. »
1	Elisenda	Elisenda	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Alamany	Alamany	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Gutiérrez	Gutiérrez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.49
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.49.1
# text = Jordi Albert i Caballero : « Yes. »
1	Jordi	Jordi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Albert	Albert	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Caballero	Caballero	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.50
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.50.1
# text = Jessica Albiach Satorres: "No. »
1	Jessica	Jessica	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Albiach	Albiach	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Satorres	Satorres	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No	no	INTJ	UH	Polarity=Neg	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.51
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.51.1
# text = Matías Alonso Ruiz : « No. »
1	Matías	Matías	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Alonso	Alonso	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Ruiz	Ruiz	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.52
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.52.1
# text = Héctor Amello Montiu : « No. »
1	Héctor	Héctor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Amello	Amello	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Montiu	Montiu	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.53
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.53.1
# text = Vidal Aragonese Chicharro : « Abstention. »
1	Vidal	Vidal	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
2	Aragonese	Aragonese	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
3	Chicharro	Chicharro	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Abstention	abstention	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.54
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.54.1
# text = Inés Arrimadas García : « No. »
1	Inés	Iné	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Arrimadas	Arrimadas	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	García	García	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.55
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.55.1
# text = Elsa Artadi i Vila: "Yes. »
1	Elsa	Elsa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Artadi	Artadi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Vila	Vila	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.56
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.56.1
# text = Eva Baró Ramos : « Yes. »
1	Eva	Eva	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Baró	Baró	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Ramos	Ramos	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.57
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.57.1
# text = Martin Eusebio Barra López : « No. »
1	Martin	Martin	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Eusebio	Eusebio	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Barra	Barra	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	López	López	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.58
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.58.1
# text = Albert Batet i Canadell: "Yes. »
1	Albert	Albert	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Batet	Batet	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Canadell	Canadell	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.59
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.59.1
# text = Susana Beltrán García : « No. »
1	Susana	Susana	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Beltrán	Beltrán	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	García	García	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.60
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.60.1
# text = David Bertran Román: "No. »
1	David	David	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Bertran	Bertran	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Román	Román	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.61
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.61.1
# text = Laura Borràs and Castanyer: "Yes. »
1	Laura	Laura	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Borràs	Borràs	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Castanyer	Castanyer	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.62
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.62.1
# text = Marina Bravo Sobrino: "No. »
1	Marina	Marina	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Bravo	Bravo	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Sobrino	Sobrino	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.63
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.63.1
# text = Rafel Bruguera Batalla: "No. »
1	Rafel	Rafel	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Bruguera	Bruguera	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Batalla	Batalla	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.64
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.64.1
# text = José María Cano Navarro: "No. »
1	José	José	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	María	María	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Cano	Cano	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	Navarro	Navarro	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.65
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.65.1
# text = Carlos Carrizosa Torres : « No. »
1	Carlos	Carlos	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Carrizosa	Carrizosa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Torres	Torres	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.66
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.66.1
# text = Magda Casamitjana and Aguilà: "Yes. »
1	Magda	Magda	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Casamitjana	Casamitjana	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Aguilà	Aguilà	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.67
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.67.1
# text = Alba Vergés i Bosch: "Yes. »
1	Alba	Alba	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Vergés	Vergé	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Bosch	Bosch	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.68
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.68.1
# text = Joan García González: "No. »
1	Joan	Joan	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	García	García	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	González	González	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.69
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.69.1
# text = David Pérez Ibáñez: "No. »
1	David	David	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Pérez	Pérez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Ibáñez	Ibáñez	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.70
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.70.1
# text = Eusebi Campdepadrós and Pucurull: "Yes. »
1	Eusebi	Eusebi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Campdepadrós	Campdepadrós	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Pucurull	Pucurull	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.71
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.71.1
# text = José María Espejo-Saavedra Conesa : « No. »
1	José	José	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	María	María	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	Espejo-	Espejo-	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	Saavedra	Saavedra	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
5	Conesa	Conesa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
6	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	No.	no.	NOUN	NN	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.72
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.72.1
# text = Josep Costa i Rossello : « Yes. »
1	Josep	Josep	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Costa	Costa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	i	I	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Rossello	Rossello	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	«	«	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.73
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.70.0.73.1
# text = Roger Torrent and Ramío: "Yes. »
1	Roger	Roger	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	Torrent	Torrent	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Ramío	Ramío	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	"	"	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	»	»	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.71.0
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.71.0.0
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.71.0.0.1
# text = The result of the vote was the following: 66 votes 'yes'; 65 votes and 4 abstentions.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	result	result	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	vote	vote	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	was	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	66	66	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	votes	vote	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	'	'	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	yes	yes	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	'	'	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	;	;	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	65	65	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	votes	vote	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	4	4	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	abstentions	abstention	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.71.0.1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.71.0.1.1
# text = Therefore, since Mr Quim Torra and Pla in this vote did not obtain the absolute majority required by Article 4.3 of the Law of Presidency of the Generality and Government, and according to Article 4.4 of the Law, the candidate may submit to a _second debate and a _second vote, in which the simple majority will suffice.
1	Therefore	therefore	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	since	since	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Mr	Mr	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Quim	Quim	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
6	Torra	Torra	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
7	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Pla	Pla	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
9	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	vote	vote	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	did	do	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	obtain	obtain	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	absolute	absolute	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	majority	majority	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	required	require	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	4.3	4.3	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
25	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Presidency	Presidency	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
27	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
28	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Generality	Generality	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
30	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Government	Government	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
32	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	according	accord	VERB	VBG	ExtPos=ADP|VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	4.4	4.4	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	candidate	candidate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	may	may	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	submit	submit	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	_second	_second	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	debate	debate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
51	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
52	_second	_second	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
53	vote	vote	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
54	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
55	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
56	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
57	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
58	simple	simple	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
59	majority	majority	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
60	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
61	suffice	suffice	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
62	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.71.0.2
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.71.0.2.1
# text = This second debate and this second vote will resume the session on May 14 at 10.30 a.m.
1	This	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	second	second	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	debate	debate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	second	second	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	vote	vote	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	resume	resume	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	May	May	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	14	14	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	at	at	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	10.30	10.30	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	a.m	a.m	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.71.0.3
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-CT_2018-05-12-0901.71.0.3.1
# text = Raise the session.
1	Raise	raise	VERB	VB	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

