# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.u1
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg1.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 4.388
# text = Good morning, fellow Members!
1	Good	good	ADJ	Z4	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	morning	morning	NOUN	Z4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	fellow	fellow	ADJ	S5p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Members	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg2
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg2.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 4.192
# text = There's a quorum.
1	There	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	quorum	quorum	NOUN	G2.1|S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg3
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg3.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.826
# text = I'm opening the plenary session.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	'm	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	opening	open	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	plenary	plenary	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	session	session	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg3.2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.153
# text = Messages:
1	Messages	message	NOUN	Q1.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg4
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg4.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.300
# text = On the basis of art. 65, para. 1 of the Law on Defence and Armed Forces of the Republic of Bulgaria on 9 and 10 May 2017, with. No AD 703-09-1 and No 703-09-4 were notified by the Minister of Defence to the National Assembly.
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	basis	basis	NOUN	A2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	art	art	NOUN	C1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	65	65	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	para	para	NOUN	G3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	1	1	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	Law	Law	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
15	on	on	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Defence	Defence	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Armed	armed	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Forces	Force	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
22	Republic	Republic	PROPN	S5p|M7	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
23	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
24	Bulgaria	Bulgaria	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
25	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	9	9	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
27	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	10	10	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
29	May	May	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	2017	2017	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	No	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	AD	ad	NOUN	I2.2|Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
36	703-09	703-09	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	-	-	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
38	1	1	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
39	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	No	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	703-09	703-09	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
43	4	4	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
44	were	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
45	notified	notify	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
46	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
48	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
49	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
50	Defence	Defence	PROPN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
51	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
52	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
53	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
54	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
55	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg4.2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.986
# text = They were granted to the Defence Commission.
1	They	they	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	were	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	granted	grant	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Defence	Defence	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	Commission	Commission	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg5
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg5.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.332
# text = We continue with the next item on the agenda:
1	We	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	continue	continue	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	next	next	ADJ	T1.1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
6	item	item	NOUN	T1.1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	on	on	ADP	A7p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	A7p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	agenda	agenda	NOUN	A7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg6
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg6.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.769
# text = SELECTION OF STANDING DELEGATIONS OF PEOPLE'S COLLECTION IN INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS.
1	SELECTION	selection	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	OF	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	STANDING	stand	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	DELEGATIONS	delegation	NOUN	S7.4p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
5	OF	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	PEOPLE'S	people	NOUN	S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
7	COLLECTION	collection	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	IN	in	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	INTERNATIONAL	international	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
10	ORGANIZATIONS	organidation	NOUN	S5p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg7
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg7.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.987
# text = There are submitted drafts for decisions with the representatives of the National Assembly Krasimir Velchev and Stanislav Ivanov.
1	There	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	are	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	submitted	submit	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
4	drafts	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
5	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	decisions	decision	NOUN	X6p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
7	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	representatives	representative	NOUN	Q2.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Krasimir	Krasimir	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Velchev	Velchev	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Stanislav	Stanislav	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
18	Ivanov	Ivanov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
19	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg8
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg8.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.179
# text = The first one:
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	first	first	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
3	one	one	NOUN	N1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg9
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg9.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.785
# text = Project!
1	Project	project	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg10
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg10.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.293
# text = DECISION
1	DECISION	decision	NOUN	X6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg12
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg12.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.119
# text = The National Assembly on the basis of art. 86, para. 1 of the Constitution of the Republic of Bulgaria and art. 38 of the Rules of Procedure of the National Assembly in relation to Art. 25 letters.................................................................................................... 26 of the Statute of the Council of Europe
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	basis	basis	NOUN	A2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	art	art	NOUN	C1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	86	86	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	para	para	NOUN	G3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	1	1	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
15	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Constitution	Constitution	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
18	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Republic	Republic	PROPN	S5p|M7	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Bulgaria	Bulgaria	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	art.	art.	PROPN	Z99	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	38	38	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
28	Rules	rule	PROPN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
29	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	Procedure	Procedure	PROPN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
31	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
32	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
33	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
34	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
35	in	in	ADP	A6.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	relation	relation	NOUN	A6.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
37	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	Art.	Art.	PROPN	Z2	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
39	25	25	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
40	letters	letter	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	....................................................................................................	....................................................................................................	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	26	26	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
43	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
45	Statute	Statute	PROPN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
46	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
47	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
48	Council	Council	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
49	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
50	Europe	Europe	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg13
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg13.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.935
# text = HAS DECIDED
1	HAS	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	DECIDED	decive	VERB	X6p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg14
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg14.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.890
# text = 1. elect a permanent delegation of the National Assembly to the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe in a composition of 6 main representatives and 6 alternate representatives as follows:
1	1.	1.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	elect	elect	VERB	G1.2|X7p	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	permanent	permanent	ADJ	T2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	delegation	delegation	NOUN	S7.4p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Council	Council	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Europe	Europe	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	composition	composition	NOUN	N5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	6	6	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
24	main	main	ADJ	N1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
25	representatives	representative	NOUN	Q2.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
26	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	6	6	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
28	alternate	alternate	ADJ	N1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
29	representatives	representative	NOUN	Q2.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
30	as	as	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	follows	follow	VERB	M1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg15
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg15.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.716
# text = - for the political party's parliamentary group GERB, two main and one substitute;
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	political	political	ADJ	G1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	party	party	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
8	group	group	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	GERB	GERB	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	two	two	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
12	main	main	ADJ	N1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
13	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	one	one	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
15	substitute	substitute	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg16
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg16.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.720
# text = - for the parliamentary group of BSP for Bulgaria
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	group	group	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	BSP	BSP	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Bulgaria	Bulgaria	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg17
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg17.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.640
# text = - for the parliamentary group of
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	group	group	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg18
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg18.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.579
# text = - for the parliamentary group of
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	group	group	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg19
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg19.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.692
# text = - for the political party's parliamentary group
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	political	political	ADJ	G1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	party	party	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
8	group	group	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg20
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg20.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.703
# text = 2. Selects the composition of the delegation as follows.
1	2.	2.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Selects	select	VERB	X7p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	composition	composition	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	delegation	delegation	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	as	as	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	follows	follow	VERB	M1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg21
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg21.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.322
# text = You have the floor for suggestions.
1	You	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	have	have	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	floor	floor	NOUN	H2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	suggestions	suggestion	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg22
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg22.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.681
# text = Here you go, Mr. Ivanov.
1	Here	here	ADV	M6	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	go	go	VERB	M1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Ivanov	Ivanov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.u2
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg23
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg23.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = positive
# senti_n = 4.689
# text = Thank you.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg24
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg24.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 4.410
# text = Dear Mr. Chairman, honourable Members!
1	Dear	dear	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Chairman	Chairman	PROPN	S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	honourable	honourable	ADJ	G2.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Members	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg24.2
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.543
# text = From the Political Party GERB we offer the following name composition of the permanent delegation of the National Assembly in the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe: Milena Tsvetanova Damyanova
1	From	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Political	political	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	GERB	GERB	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	offer	offer	VERB	A9n	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	following	follow	VERB	N4	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
10	name	name	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	composition	composition	NOUN	N5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	permanent	permanent	ADJ	T2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
15	delegation	delegation	NOUN	S7.4p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
19	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
23	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
24	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Council	Council	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
27	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
28	Europe	Europe	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
29	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	Milena	Milena	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
31	Tsvetanova	Tsvetanova	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
32	Damyanova	Damyanova	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg24.3
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = positive
# senti_n = 4.689
# text = Thank you.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.u109
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg374
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg374.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = positive
# senti_n = 4.859
# text = Thank you, Mr. Tsonev.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Tsonev	Tsonev	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg375
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg375.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.745
# text = We vote on the proposals.
1	We	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	vote	vote	VERB	G1.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	proposals	proposal	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg376
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg376.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.543
# text = Please vote.
1	Please	please	INTJ	E4.2p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	vote	vote	VERB	G1.2	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg377
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg377.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.455
# text = Vote 181 MPs: 174, against 3, abstention 4.
1	Vote	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	181	181	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
3	MPs	mp	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	174	174	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	against	against	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	3	3	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	abstention	abstention	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	4	4	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg378
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg378.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.908
# text = The proposals for changes have been adopted.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	proposals	proposal	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	changes	change	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
5	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	been	be	AUX	A3p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
7	adopted	adopt	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg379
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg379.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.557
# text = We already have a proposal for a leader, so we vote on the project in its entirety after the changes have been made.
1	We	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	already	already	ADV	T1.1.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	have	have	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	proposal	proposal	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	for	for	ADP	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	a	a	DET	T1.3	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	leader	leader	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	so	so	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
12	vote	vote	VERB	G1.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	project	project	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	its	its	PRON	Z8	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
18	entirety	entirety	NOUN	N5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	after	after	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	changes	change	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
22	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
23	been	be	AUX	A3p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
24	made	make	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
25	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg380
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg380.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.543
# text = Please vote.
1	Please	please	INTJ	E4.2p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	vote	vote	VERB	G1.2	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg381
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg381.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.196
# text = Vote 182 MPs: for 176, against 1, abstention 5.
1	Vote	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	182	182	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
3	MPs	mp	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	176	176	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	against	against	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	1	1	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	abstention	abstention	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	5	5	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg382
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg382.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 4.234
# text = The decision's been made.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	decision	decision	NOUN	X6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	been	be	AUX	A3p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
5	made	make	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg383
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg383.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.220
# text = Parliamentary Control Communication on 12 May 2017 Friday:
1	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
2	Control	Control	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
3	Communication	Communication	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	12	12	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
6	May	May	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	2017	2017	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Friday	Friday	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg384
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg384.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.795
# text = - Interior Minister Valentin Radev will answer one question from the MP Krasimir Yankov.
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Interior	Interior	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Minister	Minister	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Valentin	Valentin	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
5	Radev	Radev	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
6	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
7	answer	answer	VERB	Q2.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
8	one	one	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
9	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	MP	mp	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Krasimir	Krasimir	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
14	Yankov	Yankov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg385
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg385.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 1.884
# text = On the basis of art. 96, para. Art. 3 and Art. OJ L 268, 18.10.2003, p. 29. 2 of the Rules of Organization and Activity of the National Assembly adjourned responses by seven days have requested:
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	basis	basis	NOUN	A2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	art	art	NOUN	C1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	96	96	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	para	para	PROPN	G3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Art.	Art.	PROPN	Z2	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	3	3	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
13	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	Art.	Art.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	OJ	OJ	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
16	L	L	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	268	268	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	18.10.2003	18.10.2003	NUM	Z99	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	p.	P.	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	29	29	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
25	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Rules	rule	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
28	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Organization	Organization	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Activity	activity	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
32	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
34	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
35	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
36	adjourned	adjourn	VERB	T2n|G2.1	Mood=Ind|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
37	responses	response	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
38	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	seven	seven	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
40	days	day	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
41	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
42	requested	request	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
43	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg386
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg386.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.674
# text = - Minister of Energy Temenuzhka Petkova on one question from the National Representative Vasil Antonov;
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Energy	Energy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Temenuzhka	Temenuzhka	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
6	Petkova	Petkova	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
7	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	one	one	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
9	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Representative	Representative	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Vasil	Vasil	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
15	Antonov	Antonov	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
16	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg387
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg387.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.462
# text = - Minister of Education and Science Krasimir Valchev to a question written by the National Representative Anelia Klisarova;
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Education	Education	PROPN	P1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Science	Science	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Krasimir	Krasimir	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Valchev	Valchev	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	written	write	VERB	Q1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
13	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
16	Representative	Representative	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Anelia	Anelia	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Klisarova	Klisarova	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
19	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg388
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg388.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.639
# text = - Minister of Agriculture, Food and Forestry Rumen Porozhanov on five questions from the MPs Georgi Gokov; Svetla Bachvarova, who has two questions; Dora Yankova; and Krastina Taskova;
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Agriculture	Agriculture	PROPN	F4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Food	food	PROPN	F1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Forestry	Forestry	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Rumen	Rumen	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
10	Porozhanov	Porozhanov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
11	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	five	five	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
13	questions	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
14	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	MPs	mp	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Georgi	Georgi	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
18	Gokov	Gokov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
19	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Svetla	Svetla	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
21	Bachvarova	Bachvarova	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
24	has	have	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
25	two	two	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
26	questions	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	Dora	Dora	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
29	Yankova	Yankova	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
30	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	Krastina	Krastina	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
33	Taskova	Taskova	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
34	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg389
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg389.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.731
# text = - Minister of Economy Emil Karanikolov to a question from the National Representative Dimitar Danchev;
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Economy	economy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Emil	Emil	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
6	Karanikolov	Karanikolov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
7	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Representative	Representative	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Dimitar	Dimitar	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
15	Danchev	Danchev	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
16	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg390
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg390.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.660
# text = - Minister of Health Nikolay Petrov to a question from the National Representative Georgi Yordanov;
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Health	Health	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Nikolay	Nikolay	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
6	Petrov	Petrov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
7	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Representative	Representative	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Georgi	Georgi	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
15	Yordanov	Yordanov	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
16	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg391
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg391.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.661
# text = - Minister of Regional Development and Public Works Nikolay Nankov on three issues from the MPs Vasil Antonov, Nikolai Ivanov and Georgi Gokov;
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Regional	Regional	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	Development	Development	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Public	Public	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Works	Works	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Nikolay	Nikolay	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
10	Nankov	Nankov	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
11	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	three	three	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
13	issues	issue	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
14	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	MPs	mp	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Vasil	Vasil	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
18	Antonov	Antonov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
19	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Nikolai	Nikolai	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
21	Ivanov	Ivanov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
22	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Georgi	Georgi	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
24	Gokov	Gokov	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
25	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg392
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg392.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.874
# text = - Minister of Labour and Social Policy Biser Petkov to a question from the National Representative Dzhevdet Chakarov.
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Labour	Labour	PROPN	G1.2|Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Social	social	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Policy	Policy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Biser	Biser	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Petkov	Petkov	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
16	Representative	Representative	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Dzhevdet	Dzhevdet	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
18	Chakarov	Chakarov	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
19	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg393
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg393.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.117
# text = Due to the exhaustion of the agenda for today, I am closing the meeting.
1	Due	due	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	to	to	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	exhaustion	exhaustion	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	agenda	agenda	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	today	today	NOUN	T1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
12	am	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	closing	close	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	meeting	meeting	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.u110
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg394
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg394.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.348
# text = Tomorrow we continue with parliamentary control at 11:00.
1	Tomorrow	tomorrow	NOUN	T1.1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	continue	continue	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
6	control	control	NOUN	S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	11:00	11:00	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg395
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2017-05-11.seg395.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.590
# text = We're adjourned.
1	We	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	're	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	adjourned	adjourn	VERB	T2n|G2.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

