# newdoc id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0001
# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0001.seg0
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0001-000010
# text = I am opening the 26th Union of the Grand National Assembly of Turkey.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	am	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	opening	open	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	26th	26th	ADJ	Z99	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Union	Union	PROPN	Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Grand	Grand	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Turkey	Turkey	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0002.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0002-000010
# text = There's enough for a meeting, we're on the agenda.
1	There	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	enough	enough	ADJ	N5p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
4	for	for	ADP	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	a	a	DET	T1.3	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	meeting	meeting	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	're	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
10	on	on	ADP	A7p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	A7p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	agenda	agenda	NOUN	A7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0003.seg2
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0003-000010
# text = Members of parliament, according to our agenda, we will continue talks on the 2015 Central Management Budget Bill and the 2013 Central Management Computation Bill.
1	Members	member	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	G1.1|S2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	parliament	parliament	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	according	accord	VERB	A9n	ExtPos=ADP|VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
6	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	our	we	PRON	Z8	Number=Plur|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
8	agenda	agenda	NOUN	Q1.2|X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
11	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
12	continue	continue	VERB	T2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
13	talks	talk	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
14	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
18	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
19	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
20	Bill	Bill	PROPN	I1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
21	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
24	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
25	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
26	Computation	Computation	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
27	Bill	Bill	PROPN	I1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
28	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0004.seg3
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0004-000010
# text = According to the program, we'll be interviewing in round one today.
1	According	accord	VERB	A9n	ExtPos=ADP|VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
2	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	program	program	NOUN	Y2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	'll	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
9	interviewing	interview	VERB	Q2.1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
10	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	round	round	ADJ	N5	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
12	one	one	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
13	today	today	NOUN	T1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0005.seg4
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0005-000010
# text = The first round includes the presidency of Turkey, the Grand National Assembly, the Public Control Agency, the Court, the Constitutional Court, the Supreme Court, the Prosecutor's Office, the Office of the Prime Ministership, National Intelligence Agency, the Secretary General of the National Security Board, the President of the Religious Affairs, the General Directorate of the Foundation, and the budget and final accounts of the Human Rights Institution of Turkey.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	first	first	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
3	round	round	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	includes	include	VERB	A1.8p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	presidency	presidency	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Turkey	Turkey	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Grand	Grand	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
12	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Public	Public	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
17	Control	Control	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Agency	Agency	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
19	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Court	Court	PROPN	S3.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	Constitutional	constitutional	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
25	Court	Court	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
28	Supreme	Supreme	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
29	Court	Court	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
30	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
32	Prosecutor	Prosecutor	PROPN	G2.1|I3.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
33	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
34	Office	Office	PROPN	I2.1|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
37	Office	Office	PROPN	I2.1|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
38	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
39	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
40	Prime	Prime	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
41	Ministership	Ministership	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
42	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
44	Intelligence	Intelligence	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
45	Agency	Agency	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
46	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
48	Secretary	Secretary	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
49	General	General	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
50	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
51	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
52	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
53	Security	Security	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
54	Board	Board	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
55	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
57	President	President	PROPN	G1.1|S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
58	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
59	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
60	Religious	Religious	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
61	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
62	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
63	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
64	General	General	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
65	Directorate	Directorate	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
66	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
67	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
68	Foundation	Foundation	PROPN	T2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
69	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
70	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
71	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
72	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
73	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
74	final	final	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
75	accounts	account	NOUN	I1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
76	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
77	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
78	Human	human	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
79	Rights	Right	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
80	Institution	Institution	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
81	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
82	Turkey	Turkey	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
83	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0011.seg5
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0011-000010
# text = 1) Presidentship Central Management Budget 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Presidentship	Presidentship	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
4	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
5	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
6	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
7	2015	2015	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0012.seg6
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0012-000010
# text = 2) Presidential Central Management Final Account for 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Presidential	presidential	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
4	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
5	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
6	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
7	Account	account	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0014.seg7
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0014-000010
# text = 1) Turkey's Grand National Assembly Central Management Budget for 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Turkey	Turkey	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
4	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Grand	Grand	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
6	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
7	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
8	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
9	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
10	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
11	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0015.seg8
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0015-000010
# text = 2) Turkey's Grand National Assembly Central Management Final Account for 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Turkey	Turkey	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
4	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Grand	Grand	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
6	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
7	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
8	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
9	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
10	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
11	Account	account	PROPN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0017.seg9
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0017-000010
# text = 1) Public Control Agency Central Management Budget 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Public	Public	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	Control	Control	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Agency	Agency	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0018.seg10
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0018-000010
# text = 2) The Public Control Agency's Central Management Final Account for 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Public	Public	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	Control	Control	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Agency	Agency	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
9	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
10	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
11	Account	account	PROPN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
12	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0020.seg11
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0020-000010
# text = 1) The Court's Central Management Budget for 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Court	court	NOUN	S3.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0021.seg12
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0021-000010
# text = 2) The Court's Final Account for Central Management in 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Court	court	NOUN	S3.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Account	account	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
10	Management	management	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0023.seg13
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0023-000010
# text = 1) Constitutional Court Central Management Budget for 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Constitutional	constitutional	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Court	Court	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0024.seg14
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0024-000010
# text = 2) Constitutional Court Final Account for Central Management in 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Constitutional	constitutional	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Court	Court	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Account	account	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0026.seg15
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0026-000010
# text = 1) Supreme Court Central Management Budget for 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Supreme	Supreme	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	Court	Court	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0027.seg16
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0027-000010
# text = 2) Supreme Court Central Management Final Account for 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Supreme	Supreme	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	Court	Court	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Account	account	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0029.seg17
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0029-000010
# text = 1) District Attorney's Office's Central Management Budget for 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	District	District	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Attorney	Attorney	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Office	Office	PROPN	I2.1|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0030.seg18
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0030-000010
# text = 2) Prosecutor's Office's Central Management Final Account for 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Prosecutor	Prosecutor	PROPN	G2.1|I3.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Office	Office	PROPN	I2.1|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
8	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
9	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
10	Account	account	PROPN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
11	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0032.seg19
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0032-000010
# text = 1) Prime Ministership Central Management Budget 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Prime	Prime	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Ministership	Ministership	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0033.seg20
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0033-000010
# text = 2) The Prime Minister's Office Final Account for Central Management in 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Prime	Prime	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Minister	Minister	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Office	Office	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Account	account	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
12	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0034.seg21
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0034-000010
# text = THE MILITARY RESPONSIBILITY OF THE MILITARY INVESTIGATION
1	THE	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	MILITARY	military	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	RESPONSIBILITY	responsibility	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	OF	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	THE	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	MILITARY	military	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
7	INVESTIGATION	investigation	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0035.seg22
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0035-000010
# text = 1) Undersecretary of National Intelligence Agency 2015 Central Management Budget
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Undersecretary	Undersecretary	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Intelligence	Intelligence	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Agency	Agency	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
10	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0036.seg23
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0036-000010
# text = 2) Undersecretary of the National Intelligence Agency
1	2)	2)	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Undersecretary	Undersecretary	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Intelligence	Intelligence	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Agency	Agency	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0038.seg24
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0038-000010
# text = 1) National Security Board General Secretaryship 2015 Central Management Budget
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	Security	Security	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Board	Board	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	General	General	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Secretaryship	Secretaryship	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0039.seg25
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0039-000010
# text = 2) National Security Board General Secretary for Central Management Final Account for 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	Security	Security	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Board	Board	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	General	General	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Secretary	Secretary	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
10	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
11	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
12	Account	account	PROPN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0041.seg26
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0041-000010
# text = 1) The President of the Religious Works' budget for Central Management in 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	President	President	PROPN	G1.1|S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Religious	Religious	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
8	Works	Works	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0042.seg27
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0042-000010
# text = 2) The Head of Religious Affairs for the 2013 Central Management Final Account
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Head	Head	NOUN	S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Religious	Religious	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Affairs	affair	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
12	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Account	account	PROPN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0044.seg28
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0044-000010
# text = 1) General Directorate of Foundations 2015 Central Management Budget
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	General	General	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	Directorate	Directorate	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Foundations	foundation	PROPN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	2015	2015	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	Management	management	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Budget	budget	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0045.seg29
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0045-000010
# text = 2) General Directorate of the Foundations Central Management Final Account for 2013
1	2)	2)	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
2	General	General	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Directorate	Directorate	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Foundations	foundation	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
7	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
8	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
9	Final	final	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
10	Account	account	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
11	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0047.seg30
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0047-000010
# text = 1) Human Rights Institution of Turkey Central Management Budget 2015
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Human	human	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	Rights	Right	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Institution	Institution	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Turkey	Turkey	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Budget	Budget	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	2015	2015	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0048.seg31
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0048-000010
# text = 2) Turkey's Human Rights Agency for Central Management Investigative Account for 2013
1	2	2	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Turkey	Turkey	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
4	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Human	human	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Rights	Right	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Agency	Agency	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Central	Central	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Investigative	investigative	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Account	account	PROPN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	2013	2013	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0049.seg32
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0049-000010
# text = Commission?
1	Commission	commission	NOUN	I2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
2	?	?	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0049-000020
# text = Here.
1	Here	here	ADV	M6	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0050.seg33
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0050-000010
# text = Government?
1	Government	government	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	?	?	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0050-000020
# text = Here.
1	Here	here	ADV	M6	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0051.seg34
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0051-000010
# text = Members of parliament, the budget talks have decided that the questions must be asked without justification and the question-answer process for each round is 20 minutes.
1	Members	member	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	G1.1|S2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	parliament	parliament	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	talks	talk	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
8	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
9	decided	decide	VERB	X6p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
10	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	questions	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
13	must	must	AUX	S6p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
14	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
15	asked	ask	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
16	without	without	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	justification	justification	NOUN	G2.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
20	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	answer	answer	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	process	process	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
24	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	each	each	DET	N6p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	round	round	NOUN	N6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
27	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
28	20	20	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
29	minutes	minute	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0052.seg35
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0052-000010
# text = According to this, lawmakers who want to ask questions about budgets involved in the tour must enter the system.
1	According	accord	VERB	A9n	ExtPos=ADP|VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
2	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	this	this	PRON	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	lawmakers	lawmaker	NOUN	Z99	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
6	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
7	want	want	VERB	X7p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	ask	ask	VERB	Q2.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
10	questions	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
11	about	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	budgets	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
13	involved	involve	VERB	A1.8p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
14	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	tour	tour	NOUN	M1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	must	must	AUX	S6p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
18	enter	enter	VERB	M1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
20	system	system	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0052-000020
# text = After the talks on the tour are over, the questioners will ask their questions in order of order on the screen.
1	After	after	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	talks	talk	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
4	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	tour	tour	NOUN	M1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	over	over	ADV	N5.2p	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	questioners	questioner	NOUN	Z99	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
12	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	ask	ask	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
14	their	they	PRON	A5.4p	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
15	questions	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
16	in	in	ADP	A5.3p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	order	order	NOUN	A5.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	order	order	NOUN	S7.1p|Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	screen	screen	NOUN	Y2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0052-000030
# text = The question will be completed in ten minutes.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
5	completed	complete	VERB	T2n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
6	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	ten	ten	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	minutes	minute	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0052-000040
# text = Ten minutes to respond will be given.
1	Ten	ten	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
2	minutes	minute	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	respond	respond	VERB	S1.1.2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
5	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
7	given	give	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0052-000050
# text = It's for your information.
1	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	your	you	PRON	Z8	Person=2|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
5	information	information	NOUN	X2.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0053.seg36
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0053-000010
# text = In the first round, I read the names of the members who were spoken for by their groups and individuals:
1	In	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	first	first	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
4	round	round	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	read	read	VERB	Q3	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	names	name	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	members	member	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
13	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
14	were	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
15	spoken	speak	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
16	for	for	ADP	A9p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	by	by	ADP	S5n	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	their	they	PRON	S5n	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
19	groups	group	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
20	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	individuals	individual	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0054.seg37
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0054-000010
# text = On behalf of the National Movement Party Group, Atila Kaya will speak for İstanbul, Mehmet Shandir Mersin, Oktay Özturk Erzurum, Ismet Bünataman Bursa, Mustafa Erdem Ankara MPs.
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	behalf	behalf	NOUN	S1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Movement	Movement	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Group	Group	PROPN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Atila	Atila	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
11	Kaya	Kaya	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
12	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	speak	speak	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
14	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	İstanbul	İstanbul	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Mehmet	Mehmet	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
18	Shandir	Shandir	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
19	Mersin	Mersin	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Oktay	Oktay	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
22	Özturk	Özturk	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Erzurum	Erzurum	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Ismet	Ismet	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
26	Bünataman	Bünataman	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
27	Bursa	Bursa	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Mustafa	Mustafa	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
30	Erdem	Erdem	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Ankara	Ankara	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
32	MPs	mp	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0055.seg38
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0055-000010
# text = On behalf of the Republican People's Party Group, Atilla Kart Konya, Ali Haydar Öner Öner Isparta, Hüseyin Aygün Tunceli, Reza Türmen İzmir, Ali İhsan İkturk Zonguldak, Dilek Akagün Yılmaz İçe, Kamer Yüç Tunceli, Mehmet Şeker Gaziantep, İhsan Özkes İstanbul, Aylin Nazlıaka Ankara, Mahmut Tanal İstanbul MPs will speak.
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	behalf	behalf	NOUN	S1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Republican	Republican	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	People	People	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Group	Group	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Atilla	Atilla	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
12	Kart	Kart	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
13	Konya	Konya	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Ali	Ali	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
16	Haydar	Haydar	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
17	Öner	Öner	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
18	Öner	Öner	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
19	Isparta	Isparta	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Hüseyin	Hüseyin	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
22	Aygün	Aygün	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Tunceli	Tunceli	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Reza	Reza	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
26	Türmen	Türmen	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
27	İzmir	İzmir	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Ali	Ali	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
30	İhsan	İhsan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
31	İkturk	İkturk	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
32	Zonguldak	Zonguldak	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
33	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	Dilek	Dilek	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
35	Akagün	Akagün	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
36	Yılmaz	Yılmaz	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
37	İçe	İçe	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
38	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	Kamer	Kamer	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
40	Yüç	Yüç	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
41	Tunceli	Tunceli	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
42	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	Mehmet	Mehmet	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
44	Şeker	Şeker	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
45	Gaziantep	Gaziantep	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
46	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	İhsan	İhsan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
48	Özkes	Özkes	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
49	İstanbul	İstanbul	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
50	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
51	Aylin	Aylin	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
52	Nazlıaka	Nazlıaka	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
53	Ankara	Ankara	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
54	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
55	Mahmut	Mahmut	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
56	Tanal	Tanal	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
57	İstanbul	İstanbul	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
58	MPs	mp	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
59	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
60	speak	speak	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
61	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0056.seg39
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0056-000010
# text = On behalf of Peoples' Democratic Party Group, Sırrı Surayya Önder will speak for İstanbul, Adil Zozani Hakkari, Ayla Akat Ata Batman; Altan Tan Diyarbakır, Gülser Yıldırım.
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	behalf	behalf	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Peoples	people	PROPN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
5	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Democratic	Democratic	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Group	Group	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Sırrı	Sırrı	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
11	Surayya	Surayya	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Önder	Önder	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
14	speak	speak	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
15	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	İstanbul	İstanbul	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Adil	Adil	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
19	Zozani	Zozani	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
20	Hakkari	Hakkari	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	Ayla	Ayla	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
23	Akat	Akat	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
24	Ata	Ata	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
25	Batman	Batman	PROPN	Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
26	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Altan	Altan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
28	Tan	Tan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
29	Diyarbakır	Diyarbakır	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
30	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Gülser	Gülser	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
32	Yıldırım	Yıldırım	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0057.seg40
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0057-000010
# text = On behalf of the AK PARTI Group, Hilmi Bilgin Sivas, Nevzat Pakdil Kahramanmarash, Fahrettin Poyraz Bilecik, Shuay Alpay Elazığ, Mustafa Kemal Sherbetçioğlu Bursa, Adem Yeşdal Hatay, Ali Ercoshkun Bolu, Bkent Turan İstanbul, İdris Şahin Çanırı, Murat Gökturk Nevşehir, İsmail Aydın Bursa, Cem Zor Konya, Hasan Karal Rize, Ömer Faruk Öz Malatya, Mehmet Sarı Gaziantep, Mehmet Kerim Yıldız.
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	behalf	behalf	NOUN	S1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	AK	AK	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	PARTI	PARTI	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Group	Group	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Hilmi	Hilmi	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
10	Bilgin	Bilgin	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Sivas	Sivas	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Nevzat	Nevzat	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
14	Pakdil	Pakdil	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Kahramanmarash	Kahramanmarash	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Fahrettin	Fahrettin	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
18	Poyraz	Poyraz	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Bilecik	Bilecik	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Shuay	Shuay	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
22	Alpay	Alpay	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Elazığ	Elazığ	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Mustafa	Mustafa	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
26	Kemal	Kemal	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
27	Sherbetçioğlu	Sherbetçioğlu	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
28	Bursa	Bursa	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
29	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	Adem	Adem	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
31	Yeşdal	Yeşdal	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
32	Hatay	Hatay	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
33	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	Ali	Ali	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
35	Ercoshkun	Ercoshkun	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
36	Bolu	Bolu	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
37	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	Bkent	Bkent	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
39	Turan	Turan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
40	İstanbul	İstanbul	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	İdris	İdris	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
43	Şahin	Şahin	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
44	Çanırı	Çanırı	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
45	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	Murat	Murat	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
47	Gökturk	Gökturk	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
48	Nevşehir	Nevşehir	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
49	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
50	İsmail	İsmail	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
51	Aydın	Aydın	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
52	Bursa	Bursa	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
53	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
54	Cem	Cem	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
55	Zor	Zor	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
56	Konya	Konya	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
57	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
58	Hasan	Hasan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
59	Karal	Karal	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
60	Rize	Rize	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
61	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
62	Ömer	Ömer	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
63	Faruk	Faruk	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
64	Öz	Öz	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
65	Malatya	Malatya	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
66	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
67	Mehmet	Mehmet	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
68	Sarı	Sarı	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
69	Gaziantep	Gaziantep	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
70	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
71	Mehmet	Mehmet	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
72	Kerim	Kerim	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
73	Yıldız	Yıldız	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
74	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0058.seg41
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0058-000010
# text = On behalf of the individuals, Zülfü Demirbağ Elazığ will speak against Malik Ecder Özdemir Sivas MPs.
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	behalf	behalf	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	individuals	individual	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Zülfü	Zülfü	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
8	Demirbağ	Demirbağ	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
9	Elazığ	Elazığ	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
10	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	speak	speak	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
12	against	against	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Malik	Malik	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
14	Ecder	Ecder	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
15	Özdemir	Özdemir	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
16	Sivas	Sivas	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	MPs	mp	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0059.seg42
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0059-000010
# text = On behalf of the government, Deputy Prime Minister Bulent Arinc will speak.
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	behalf	behalf	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	government	government	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Deputy	deputy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Prime	Prime	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Minister	Minister	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Bulent	Bulent	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
11	Arinc	Arinc	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
12	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	speak	speak	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0060.seg43
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0060-000010
# text = On behalf of the National Movement Party Group, the first word is Mr. Atila Kaya.
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	behalf	behalf	NOUN	S1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Movement	Movement	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Group	Group	PROPN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	first	first	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
12	word	word	NOUN	Q3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
14	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Atila	Atila	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
16	Kaya	Kaya	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
17	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0061.seg44
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0061-000010
# text = Here you go.
1	Here	here	ADV	M6	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	go	go	VERB	M1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0063.seg45
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0001par0063-000010
# text = Your time is 11 minutes.
1	Your	you	PRON	Z8	Person=2|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	time	time	NOUN	T1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	11	11	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
5	minutes	minute	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0064
# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0064.seg0
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0064-000010
# text = Mr. President, I have made a commitment to express the views of the National Movement Party on the presidential budget.
1	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	President	President	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
5	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	made	make	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
7	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	commitment	commitment	NOUN	S6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	express	express	VERB	Q1.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	views	view	NOUN	X2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
13	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
16	Movement	Movement	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
18	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
20	presidential	presidential	ADJ	G1.1|S7.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
21	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0064-000020
# text = I salute the High Council.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	salute	salute	VERB	S1.1.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	High	high	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	Council	Council	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0064-000030
# text = The 2015 central management budget we're talking about is a blessing for our nation, for our country.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
3	central	central	ADJ	N1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
4	management	management	NOUN	S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	're	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	talking	talk	VERB	Q2.1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
9	about	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	blessing	blessing	NOUN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	our	we	PRON	Z8	Number=Plur|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
15	nation	nation	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	our	we	PRON	Z8	Number=Plur|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
19	country	country	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0065.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0065-000010
# text = Dear MPs, I am a congressman who has repeatedly criticised the current President's predecessor, who has expressed my criticism in an open letter addressed to the president's budget and to the person I share with the public.
1	Dear	dear	ADJ	E2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	MPs	mp	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
5	am	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	congressman	congressman	NOUN	G1.2|S2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
9	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
10	repeatedly	repeatedly	ADV	N6p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	criticised	criticise	VERB	Q2.2|E2n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
13	current	current	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
14	President	President	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	predecessor	predecessor	NOUN	N4|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
19	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
20	expressed	express	VERB	A5.4p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
21	my	my	PRON	A5.4p	Number=Sing|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
22	criticism	criticism	NOUN	Q2.2|E2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	an	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
25	open	open	ADJ	A10p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
26	letter	letter	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
27	addressed	address	VERB	Q1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
28	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	president	president	NOUN	G1.1|S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
36	person	person	NOUN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
37	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
38	share	share	VERB	S1.1.2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
39	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
41	public	public	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0065-000020
# text = During the seven years of the presidency, I believed that there could be no worse than the late President, who could not go beyond loyalty to my brother Abdullah Gül, and today I am a congressman who understood that he was wrong.
1	During	during	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	seven	seven	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
4	years	year	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	presidency	presidency	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	I	I	PRON	Z4	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
10	believed	believe	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	there	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	could	could	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
14	be	be	VERB	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
15	no	no	ADV	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	worse	bad	ADJ	A5.1n	Degree=Cmp	0	_	_	NER=O
17	than	than	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
19	late	late	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
20	President	President	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
23	could	could	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
24	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	go	go	VERB	M1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
26	beyond	beyond	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	loyalty	loyalty	NOUN	S6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
28	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	my	my	PRON	Z8	Number=Sing|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
30	brother	brother	NOUN	S4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Abdullah	Abdullah	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
32	Gül	Gül	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
33	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	today	today	NOUN	T1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
36	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
37	am	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
38	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	congressman	congressman	NOUN	G1.2|S2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
40	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
41	understood	understand	VERB	X2.5p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
42	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
44	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
45	wrong	wrong	ADJ	A5.3n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
46	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0066.seg2
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0066-000010
# text = Dear lawmakers, after leaving their post, you also served in the former President Gul, who gave an interview to the newspaper Saudi El Hayat, and you also served in opposition, and you lived in the Presidential Mansion, which was more difficult? The Presidential Mansion was the hardest.
1	Dear	dear	ADJ	E2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	lawmakers	lawmaker	NOUN	Z99	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	after	after	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	leaving	leave	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
6	their	they	PRON	A5.4p	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	post	post	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
10	also	also	ADV	N5p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	served	serve	VERB	S8p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
12	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	former	former	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
15	President	President	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Gul	Gul	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
19	gave	give	VERB	A9n	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
20	an	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	interview	interview	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	newspaper	newspaper	NOUN	Q4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Saudi	Saudi	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
26	El	El	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
27	Hayat	Hayat	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
31	also	also	ADV	N5p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	served	serve	VERB	S8p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
33	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	opposition	opposition	NOUN	S8n|E2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
38	lived	live	VERB	H4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
39	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
41	Presidential	presidential	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
42	Mansion	Mansion	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
43	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
45	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
46	more	more	ADV	A13.3	Degree=Cmp	0	_	_	NER=O
47	difficult	difficult	ADJ	A12n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
48	?	?	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
49	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
50	Presidential	presidential	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
51	Mansion	Mansion	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
52	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
53	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
54	hardest	hard	ADJ	O4.5	Degree=Sup	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
55	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0066-000020
# text = You represent everyone, and if you are aware of that, the presidency is the most difficult; it's easy if you don't realize it.
1	You	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	represent	represent	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	everyone	everyone	PRON	A5.4p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	if	if	SCONJ	Z7	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
8	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
9	aware	aware	ADJ	X2.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	that	that	PRON	Z5	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	presidency	presidency	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
17	most	most	ADV	A13.2	Degree=Sup	0	_	_	NER=O
18	difficult	difficult	ADJ	A12n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
22	easy	easy	ADJ	A12p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
23	if	if	SCONJ	Z7	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
25	do	do	AUX	S1.1.3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	n't	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	realize	realize	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
28	it	it	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0066-000030
# text = Mr. Erdogan, who took into account the warnings of the challenge of his neutral presidency, has eliminated this challenge in his own way, as he continues to act as AKP President rather than try to be neutral.
1	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Erdogan	Erdogan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
5	took	take	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	into	into	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	account	account	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	warnings	warning	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	challenge	challenge	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	his	he	PRON	Z8	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
15	neutral	neutral	ADJ	S5n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
16	presidency	presidency	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
19	eliminated	eliminate	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
20	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
21	challenge	challenge	NOUN	A12n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	his	he	PRON	Z8	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
24	own	own	ADJ	A9p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
25	way	way	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	as	as	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
29	continues	continue	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
30	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	act	act	VERB	A1.1.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
32	as	as	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	AKP	AKP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
34	President	President	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
35	rather	rather	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	than	than	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	try	try	VERB	X8p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
38	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
40	neutral	neutral	ADJ	S5n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0066-000040
# text = In accordance with Article 103 of the Constitution, he saw that swearing on honor and honor that he would be neutral was clearly a trivial matter.
1	In	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	accordance	accordance	NOUN	S7.1n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Article	article	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
5	103	103	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Constitution	constitution	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
11	saw	see	VERB	X3.4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
12	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	swearing	swear	NOUN	Q2.2|S1.2.4n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	honor	honor	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	honor	honor	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	that	that	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
19	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
20	would	would	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
21	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
22	neutral	neutral	ADJ	S5n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
23	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
24	clearly	clearly	ADV	A7p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
26	trivial	trivial	ADJ	A11.1n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
27	matter	matter	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0067.seg3
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0067-000010
# text = Despite his oath of honor and honor, the President did not feel the need to change himself.
1	Despite	despite	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	his	he	PRON	Z8	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	oath	oath	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	honor	honor	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	honor	honor	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	President	President	PROPN	G1.1|S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	did	do	AUX	A1.1.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
12	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	feel	feel	VERB	X2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	need	need	NOUN	S6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	change	change	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
18	himself	himself	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs|Reflex=Yes	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0067-000020
# text = If his oath and authority have not changed him, then if he is determined to be as he was, then it is up to us to continue to see him as he was.
1	If	if	SCONJ	Z7	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	his	he	PRON	Z8	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	oath	oath	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	authority	authority	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
7	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	changed	change	VERB	A5.4p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
9	him	he	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	then	then	ADV	N4	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
12	if	if	SCONJ	Z7	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
14	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
15	determined	determine	VERB	X6p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
16	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	be	be	VERB	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
18	as	as	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
20	was	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	then	then	ADV	N4	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
23	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
24	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
25	up	up	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	us	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
28	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	continue	continue	VERB	T2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
30	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	see	see	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
32	him	he	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
33	as	as	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
35	was	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0067-000030
# text = We must remember for a moment that Mr. Recep Tayyip Erdogan is what he was before he became President.
1	We	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	must	must	AUX	S6p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	remember	remember	VERB	X2.2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
4	for	for	ADP	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	a	a	DET	T1.3	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	moment	moment	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Recep	Recep	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
10	Tayyip	Tayyip	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
11	Erdogan	Erdogan	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
12	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	what	what	PRON	Z8	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
14	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
15	was	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
16	before	before	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
18	became	become	VERB	A2.1p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
19	President	President	PROPN	G1.1|S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0067-000040
# text = So again, it's the polarist, it's the separatist, it's the separatist, it's the aberrant again, it's the one who ignores national interests for personal gains, it's the one who doesn't hesitate to use religious values, it's the one who cares about neither judicial independence nor press freedom, it's the one who wants to drown every criticism with pride.
1	So	so	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	again	again	ADV	N6p	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	polarist	polarist	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	separatist	separatist	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
17	separatist	separatist	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	aberrant	aberrant	NOUN	A6.2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	again	again	ADV	N6p	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
28	one	one	NOUN	Z8	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
29	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
30	ignores	ignore	VERB	X5.1n	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
31	national	national	ADJ	M7|N5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
32	interests	interest	NOUN	X5.2p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
33	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	personal	personal	ADJ	S5n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
35	gains	gain	NOUN	X9.2p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
38	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
39	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
40	one	one	NOUN	Z8	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
41	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
42	does	do	AUX	A1.1.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
43	n't	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	hesitate	hesitate	VERB	A7n	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
45	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	use	use	VERB	A1.5.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
47	religious	religious	ADJ	S9	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
48	values	value	NOUN	A11.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
49	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
50	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
51	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
52	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
53	one	one	NOUN	N1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
54	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
55	cares	care	VERB	E6n	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
56	about	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
57	neither	neither	CCONJ	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
58	judicial	judicial	ADJ	G2.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
59	independence	independence	NOUN	S5n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
60	nor	nor	CCONJ	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
61	press	press	NOUN	Q4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
62	freedom	freedom	NOUN	A1.7n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
63	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
64	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
65	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
66	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
67	one	one	NOUN	Z8	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
68	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
69	wants	want	VERB	X7p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
70	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
71	drown	drown	VERB	L1n	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
72	every	every	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
73	criticism	criticism	NOUN	Q2.2|E2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
74	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
75	pride	pride	NOUN	E4.2p|S1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
76	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0068.seg4
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0068-000010
# text = I pray for the American soldiers who turn the Middle East into a pool of blood. The person who says, "I'm responsible for marketing my country." The person who says, "I'm the co-chair of the Great Middle East Project." The person who says, "I'm the wife of the Great Middle East Project." The person who says, "I've never been in contact with a terrorist organization. I pray for American soldiers to return to their countries."
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	pray	pray	VERB	S9|Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	American	American	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
6	soldiers	soldier	NOUN	G3|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
7	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
8	turn	turn	VERB	M2	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Middle	Middle	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
11	East	East	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
12	into	into	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	pool	pool	NOUN	W3|M4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	blood	blood	NOUN	B1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
19	person	person	NOUN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
21	says	say	VERB	Q2.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
25	'm	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
26	responsible	responsible	ADJ	A2.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
27	for	for	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	marketing	market	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
29	my	my	PRON	A5.4p	Number=Sing|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
30	country	country	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	person	person	NOUN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
35	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
36	says	say	VERB	Q2.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	I'm	iem	AUX	Z99	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
40	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
41	co-chair	co-chair	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
42	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
44	Great	great	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
45	Middle	Middle	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
46	East	East	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
47	Project	Project	PROPN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
48	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
49	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
50	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
51	person	person	NOUN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
52	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
53	says	say	VERB	Q2.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
54	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
55	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
56	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
57	'm	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
58	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
59	wife	wife	NOUN	S4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
60	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
61	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
62	Great	great	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
63	Middle	Middle	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
64	East	East	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
65	Project	Project	PROPN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
66	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
67	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
68	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
69	person	person	NOUN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
70	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
71	says	say	VERB	Q2.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
72	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
73	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
74	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
75	've	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
76	never	never	ADV	T1|Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
77	been	be	AUX	A3p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
78	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
79	contact	contact	NOUN	S1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
80	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
81	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
82	terrorist	terrorist	NOUN	G2.1n|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
83	organization	organization	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
84	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
85	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
86	pray	pray	VERB	S9|Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
87	for	for	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
88	American	American	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
89	soldiers	soldier	NOUN	G3|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
90	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
91	return	return	VERB	M1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
92	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
93	their	they	PRON	Z8	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
94	countries	country	NOUN	M7	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
95	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
96	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0068-000020
# text = It's a disgrace to say so. The person who said, "It's a solution" is the person who puts the country's reputation in shoeboxes, and it's the human president who's going to stay in our memories, and we're talking about his budget.
1	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	disgrace	disgrace	NOUN	S7.2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	say	say	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
7	so	so	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	person	person	NOUN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
12	said	say	VERB	Q2.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
17	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	solution	solution	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	person	person	NOUN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
24	puts	put	VERB	M2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
25	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
26	country	country	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	reputation	reputation	NOUN	I3.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
29	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	shoeboxes	shoebox	NOUN	Z99	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
34	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
36	human	human	ADJ	S2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
37	president	president	NOUN	G1.1|S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
38	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
40	going	go	VERB	T1.1.3	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
41	to	to	PART	T1.1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	stay	stay	VERB	M8	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
43	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	our	we	PRON	Z8	Number=Plur|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
45	memories	memory	NOUN	X2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
46	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
49	're	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
50	talking	talk	VERB	Q2.1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
51	about	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
52	his	he	PRON	Z8	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
53	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
54	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0069.seg5
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0069-000010
# text = It's a fact that a man who doesn't feel that he belongs to Turkish history, a great Turkish nation and his history, has taken an oath of honor and honor, and his budget is being discussed.
1	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	fact	fact	NOUN	A5.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	man	man	NOUN	S2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
9	does	do	AUX	A1.1.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	n't	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	feel	feel	VERB	X2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
12	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
14	belongs	belong	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
15	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Turkish	Turkish	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
17	history	history	NOUN	T1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
20	great	great	ADJ	A5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Turkish	Turkish	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
22	nation	nation	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	his	he	PRON	Z8	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
25	history	history	NOUN	T1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
28	taken	take	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
29	an	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	oath	oath	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
31	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	honor	honor	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	honor	honor	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	his	he	PRON	Z8	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
38	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
39	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
40	being	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
41	discussed	discuss	VERB	Q2.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0070.seg6
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0070-000010
# text = We all know that under the circumstances, living in a mansion or in a palace, raising its budget by 50 or 100 per cent, and since the Court's reports didn't come to Parliament, it's only a matter of time now that we won't know where this budget will go.
1	We	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	all	all	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	know	know	VERB	X2.2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	under	under	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	circumstances	circumstance	NOUN	O4.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	living	live	VERB	H4	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
10	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	mansion	mansion	NOUN	H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	or	or	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	palace	palace	NOUN	H1|S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	raising	raise	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
19	its	its	PRON	A5.4p	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
20	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	50	50	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
23	or	or	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	100	100	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
25	per	per	NOUN	Z5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	cent	cent	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	since	since	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Court	court	NOUN	S3.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
32	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	reports	report	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
34	did	do	AUX	A1.1.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	n't	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	come	come	VERB	M1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
37	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
42	only	only	ADV	A14	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
44	matter	matter	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
45	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	time	time	NOUN	T1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
47	now	now	ADV	T1.1.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
49	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
50	wo	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
51	n't	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
52	know	know	VERB	X2.2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
53	where	where	SCONJ	M6	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
54	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
55	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
56	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
57	go	go	VERB	M1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
58	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0071.seg7
# lang = en
# sent_id = tbmm-2014-12-11sit01spe0002par0071-000010
# text = Congressmans, the government's skirts are on fire to prevent waste in public, while the public institutions' funds are expected to increase only 4-4.5%, while the presidential budget is nearly doubled compared to the previous year, because it was made for the president's office, not for the president's office.
1	Congressmans	Congressmans	PROPN	Z99	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	government	government	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	skirts	skirt	NOUN	B5	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
7	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	fire	fire	NOUN	O4.6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	prevent	prevent	VERB	S8n	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
12	waste	waste	NOUN	N5.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	public	public	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	while	while	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	public	public	ADJ	S5p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
19	institutions	institution	NOUN	S5p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	funds	fund	NOUN	I1.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
22	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
23	expected	expect	VERB	X2.6p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
24	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	increase	increase	VERB	N5p|A2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
26	only	only	ADV	A14	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	4	4	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	-	-	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	4.5	4.5	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	%	%	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	while	while	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	presidential	presidential	ADJ	G1.1|S7.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
35	budget	budget	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
36	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
37	nearly	nearly	ADV	A13.4	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	doubled	double	VERB	N5p|A2.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
39	compared	compare	VERB	A6.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
40	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
42	previous	previous	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
43	year	year	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
44	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
45	because	because	SCONJ	Z5|A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
47	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
48	made	make	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
49	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
50	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
51	president	president	NOUN	G1.1|S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
52	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
53	office	office	NOUN	I2.1|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
54	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
55	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
57	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
58	president	president	NOUN	G1.1|S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
59	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
60	office	office	NOUN	I2.1|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
61	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
