# newdoc id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1
# newpar id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.1
# text = Good morning, honourable Members!
1	Good	good	ADJ	Z4	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	morning	morning	NOUN	Z4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	honourable	honourable	ADJ	G2.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Members	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.2
# text = I invite you to take your seats in the Saeima Meeting Room so that we can begin the Meeting of the Saeima of the Republic of Latvia on 13 October 2022.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	invite	invite	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	you	you	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	take	take	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
6	your	you	PRON	A5.4p	Person=2|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	seats	seat	NOUN	H5	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
8	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Saeima	Saeima	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
11	Meeting	Meeting	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
12	Room	Room	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
13	so	so	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
16	can	can	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
17	begin	begin	VERB	T2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Meeting	meeting	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
22	Saeima	Saeima	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
23	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
24	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
25	Republic	Republic	PROPN	S5p|M7	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
26	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
27	Latvia	Latvia	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
28	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	13	13	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
30	October	October	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
31	2022	2022	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.3
# text = First of all, the amendments tabled to the Bureau's agenda.
1	First	first	ADV	N4	NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	all	all	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	amendments	amendment	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
7	tabled	tab	VERB	Q1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
8	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Bureau	Bureau	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
11	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	agenda	agenda	NOUN	Q1.2|X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.4
# text = The Legal Commission asks to include in the agenda of the sitting the draft decision “On confirmation of Jānis Plapa as a judge of the Supreme Court”.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Legal	legal	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	Commission	Commission	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	asks	ask	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	include	include	VERB	A1.8p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
7	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	agenda	agenda	NOUN	Q1.2|X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	sitting	sit	VERB	M8	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	decision	decision	NOUN	X6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	“	“	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	confirmation	confirmation	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Jānis	Jānis	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
21	Plapa	Plapa	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
22	as	as	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	judge	judge	NOUN	G2.1|I3.2|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Supreme	Supreme	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
28	Court	Court	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
29	”	”	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.5
# text = Are Members opposed to this amendment of the agenda?
1	Are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Members	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	opposed	oppose	VERB	S8n|E2n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
6	amendment	amendment	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	agenda	agenda	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	?	?	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.6
# text = There is no objection.
1	There	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	is	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	no	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	objection	objection	NOUN	E2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.7
# text = The order of business has been amended.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	order	order	NOUN	S7.1p|Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	business	business	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	been	be	AUX	A3p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
7	amended	amend	VERB	A2.1p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.8
# text = And the Budget and Finance (tax) Commission asks to include in the agenda the draft law “Amendments to the law “On Monitoring of State Prove”” on the agenda of the sitting.
1	And	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Budget	Budget	PROPN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Finance	Finance	PROPN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	tax	tax	NOUN	I1.1|G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
8	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Commission	commission	NOUN	I2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	asks	ask	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	include	include	VERB	A1.8p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
13	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	agenda	agenda	NOUN	Q1.2|X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
17	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	“	“	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	Amendments	amendment	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
21	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
24	“	“	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
25	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	Monitoring	monitoring	NOUN	X2.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
27	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
28	State	state	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Prove	prove	VERB	Z1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
30	”	”	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	”	”	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	on	on	ADP	A7p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	A7p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	agenda	agenda	NOUN	A7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
35	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
37	sitting	sitting	NOUN	M8	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
38	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.9
# text = Are Members opposed to this amendment of the agenda?
1	Are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Members	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	opposed	oppose	VERB	S8n|E2n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
6	amendment	amendment	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	agenda	agenda	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	?	?	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.10
# text = There is no objection.
1	There	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	is	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	no	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	objection	objection	NOUN	E2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.11
# text = The order of business has been amended.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	order	order	NOUN	S7.1p|Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	business	business	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	been	be	AUX	A3p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
7	amended	amend	VERB	A2.1p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.12
# text = Let us start by looking at the amended agenda.
1	Let	let	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	us	we	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	start	start	VERB	T2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
4	by	by	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	looking	look	VERB	A8	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
6	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	amended	amend	VERB	A2.1p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
9	agenda	agenda	NOUN	Q1.2|X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.13
# text = On the agenda - reports from the Bureau on draft laws submitted.
1	On	on	ADP	A7p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	A7p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	agenda	agenda	NOUN	A7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	reports	report	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
6	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Bureau	Bureau	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	laws	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
12	submitted	submit	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.14
# text = The Presidium of the Saeima proposes the Member Viktoras Valaiņa, Armands Krauze, Ulda Augulis, Jānis Dūklavs, Jānis Vacāns and other draft laws submitted “Amendments to the Law on Value Added Tax” (No. 1659/Lp13) transferred to the Budget and Financial (Tax) Commission with responsibility for the Commission. ‘
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Presidium	Presidium	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Saeima	Saeima	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	proposes	propose	VERB	Q2.2|X7p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Member	member	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	Viktoras	Viktoras	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Valaiņa	Valaiņa	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	Armands	Armand	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Krauze	Krauze	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Ulda	Ulda	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
16	Augulis	Augulis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Jānis	Jānis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
19	Dūklavs	Dūklavs	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Jānis	Jānis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
22	Vacāns	Vacān	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	other	other	ADJ	A6.1n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
25	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	laws	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
27	submitted	submit	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
28	“	“	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	Amendments	amendment	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
30	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
32	Law	law	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	on	on	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	Value	value	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
35	Added	add	VERB	Z1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
36	Tax	tax	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	”	”	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	No.	no.	NOUN	Z99	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
40	1659	1659	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	/	/	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	Lp13	lp13	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
43	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	transferred	transfer	VERB	M6|A2.1p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
45	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
47	Budget	Budget	PROPN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
48	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
49	Financial	Financial	ADJ	I1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
50	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
51	Tax	Tax	PROPN	I1.1|G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
52	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
53	Commission	Commission	PROPN	I2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
54	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
55	responsibility	responsibility	NOUN	S6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
56	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
57	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
58	Commission	commission	NOUN	I2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
59	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
60	‘	‘	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U1-P1.15
# text = For” applied to speak Member Viktors Valainis.
1	For	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	”	”	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	applied	apply	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	speak	speak	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Member	member	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Viktors	Viktor	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
8	Valainis	Valaini	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2
# newpar id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.1
# text = Very respectful Speaker of the Saeima!
1	Very	very	ADV	A13.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	respectful	respectful	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Speaker	Speaker	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Saeima	Saeima	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
7	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.2
# text = Dear colleagues,
1	Dear	dear	ADJ	E2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	colleagues	colleague	NOUN	I3.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.3
# text = A week ago, we had the opportunity to vote in favour of two relevant draft laws, and I am very pleased that at least one of them - the reduction of VAT on medicinal products - managed to hand over to the Budget and Financial (Tax) Commission and started work on this draft law.
1	A	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	week	week	NOUN	T1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	ago	ago	ADV	T1.1.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
6	had	have	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	opportunity	opportunity	NOUN	A1.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	vote	vote	VERB	G1.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
11	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	favour	favour	NOUN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	two	two	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
15	relevant	relevant	ADJ	N1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
16	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	laws	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
21	am	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
22	very	very	ADV	A13.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	pleased	pleased	ADJ	E4.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
24	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	at	at	ADP	Z5	ExtPos=ADV	0	_	_	NER=O
26	least	least	ADJ	N5.1n	Degree=Sup	0	_	_	NER=O
27	one	one	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
28	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	them	they	PRON	Z8	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
30	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
32	reduction	reduction	NOUN	N5n|A2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	VAT	vat	NOUN	G1.1|I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
35	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	medicinal	medicinal	ADJ	B3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
37	products	product	NOUN	O2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
38	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	managed	manage	VERB	S7.1p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
40	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	hand	hand	VERB	A9n	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
42	over	over	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
45	Budget	Budget	PROPN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
46	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
47	Financial	Financial	ADJ	I1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
48	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
49	Tax	Tax	PROPN	I1.1|G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
50	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
51	Commission	Commission	PROPN	I2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
52	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
53	started	start	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
54	work	work	NOUN	I3.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
55	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
57	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
58	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
59	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.4
# text = And I very much hope that today too...
1	And	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	very	very	ADV	A13.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	much	much	ADV	A13.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	hope	hope	VERB	X2.6p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	today	today	NOUN	T1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	too	too	ADV	N5p	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	...	...	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.5
# text = that colleagues have had the opportunity to think in a week's time and make their own choice with regard to this draft law as well.
1	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	colleagues	colleague	NOUN	I3.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	had	have	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	opportunity	opportunity	NOUN	A1.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	think	think	VERB	X2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
9	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	week	week	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	time	time	NOUN	T1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	make	make	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
16	their	they	PRON	A5.4p	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
17	own	own	ADJ	A9p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
18	choice	choice	NOUN	X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	regard	regard	NOUN	Z5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
23	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
24	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	as	as	ADV	N5p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	well	well	ADV	N5p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.6
# text = I call on the Conservative Group, however, to take part in the vote - unlike last week - and to support the transfer of this draft law to the Commission; this is about reduced VAT on food products.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	call	call	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Conservative	Conservative	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Group	Group	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	however	however	ADV	Z4	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	take	take	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
12	part	part	NOUN	N5.1n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	vote	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	unlike	unlike	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	last	last	ADJ	T1.1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
19	week	week	NOUN	T1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	support	support	VERB	S8p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
25	transfer	transfer	NOUN	M6|A2.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
28	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
29	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
32	Commission	commission	NOUN	I2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
33	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	this	this	PRON	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
35	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
36	about	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	reduced	reduce	VERB	N5n|A2.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
38	VAT	vat	NOUN	G1.1|I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
39	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	food	food	NOUN	F1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
41	products	product	NOUN	O2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.7
# text = This draft law is based on an information report, which is a conceptual report prepared by the Ministry of Agriculture.
1	This	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
2	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	based	base	VERB	T2p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
6	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	an	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	information	information	NOUN	X2.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	report	report	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
12	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	conceptual	conceptual	ADJ	X4.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
15	report	report	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	prepared	prepare	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
17	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Agriculture	Agriculture	PROPN	F4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
22	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.8
# text = I invite you to start this discussion in this Saeima so that the next Saeima can either take over...
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	invite	invite	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	you	you	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	start	start	VERB	T2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
6	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
7	discussion	discussion	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Saeima	Saeima	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
11	so	so	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	next	next	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Saeima	Saeima	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
16	can	can	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
17	either	either	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	take	take	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
19	over	over	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	...	...	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.9
# text = to have at least some input.
1	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	have	have	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
3	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	least	least	ADJ	N5.1n	Degree=Sup	0	_	_	NER=O
5	some	some	DET	N5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	input	input	NOUN	O2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U2-P1.10
# text = Thank you.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U395
# newpar id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U395-P1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U395-P1.1
# text = Colleagues!
1	Colleagues	colleague	NOUN	I3.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U395-P1.2
# text = Not registered: Uldis Augulis, Krista Baumane, Uldis Budriķis, Boriss Cilevičs, Gundars Dauge, Marija Golubeva, Artuss Kaimiņš, Inese Lībiņa-Egne, Linda Medne, Ivans Ribakovs, Julija Stepanenko and Edvins Šnore.
1	Not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	registered	register	VERB	Q1.2|G1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Uldis	Uldis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
5	Augulis	Augulis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Krista	Krista	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
8	Baumane	Baumane	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Uldis	Uldis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
11	Budriķis	Budriķis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Boriss	Boriss	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
14	Cilevičs	Cilevičs	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Gundars	Gundar	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
17	Dauge	Dauge	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Marija	Marija	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
20	Golubeva	Golubeva	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	Artuss	Artuss	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
23	Kaimiņš	Kaimiņš	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Inese	Inese	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
26	Lībiņa	Lībiņa	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
27	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	Egne	Egne	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
29	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	Linda	Linda	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
31	Medne	Medne	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
32	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	Ivans	Ivan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
34	Ribakovs	Ribakovs	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	Julija	Julija	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
37	Stepanenko	Stepanenko	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
38	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	Edvins	Edvins	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
40	Šnore	Šnore	ADV	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U395-P1.3
# text = Thank you.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U395-P1.4
# text = The Bible says: “Do not be afraid. ” — Deb. I. Ribakov: “Ribakov!”
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Bible	Bible	PROPN	S9|Q4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
3	says	say	VERB	Q2.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	“	“	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	Do	do	AUX	S1.1.3p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
7	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	be	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
9	afraid	afraid	ADJ	E5n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	”	”	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	—	—	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Deb.	Deb.	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	I.	i.	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
15	Ribakov	Ribakov	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
16	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	“	“	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	Ribakov	Ribakov	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
19	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	”	”	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U395-P1.5
# text = ) Ribakov is.
1	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Ribakov	Ribakov	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
3	is	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U396
# newpar id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U396-P1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U396-P1.1
# text = Thank you.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-LV_2022-10-13-PT13-2412-U396-P1.2
# text = I'm closing the sitting.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	'm	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	closing	close	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	sitting	sitting	NOUN	M8	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

