# newdoc id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d7e383
# newpar id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e192
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e192.s1
# text = The 108.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	108	108	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e192.s2
# text = The meeting of the National Council is open.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	meeting	meeting	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Council	Council	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	open	open	ADJ	A10p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e194
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e194.s1
# text = Deputies Donabauer, Dr. Spindelegger, Arbitrators and Mag.
1	Deputies	deputy	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Donabauer	Donabauer	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Dr.	Dr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
5	Spindelegger	Spindelegger	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Arbitrators	Arbitrator	PROPN	G2.1|X6|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
8	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Mag	Mag	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
10	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e194.s2
# text = Worm.
1	Worm	Worm	NOUN	L2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e199
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e199.s1
# text = Entry and allocations
1	Entry	entry	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	allocations	allocation	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d7e414
# newpar id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e204
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e204.s1
# text = As regards the negotiated items and their allocations, I refer to them according to ยง 23 para. 4 of the Rules of Procedure to the communication distributed at the meeting room.
1	As	as	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	regards	regards	NOUN	X2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	negotiated	negotiate	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
5	items	item	NOUN	O2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
6	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	their	they	PRON	Z8	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
8	allocations	allocation	NOUN	N5	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
11	refer	refer	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
12	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	them	they	PRON	Z8	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
14	according	accord	VERB	A9n	ExtPos=ADP|VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
15	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	ยง	ยง	SYM	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	23	23	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
18	para	para	NOUN	G3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	4	4	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
21	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Rules	rule	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
24	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
26	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
28	communication	communication	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
29	distributed	distribute	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
30	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
32	meeting	meeting	NOUN	H2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	room	room	NOUN	H2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
34	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e206
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-AT_2005-04-27-022-XXII-NRSITZ-00108_d2e206.s1
# text = The written communication shall contain the following text:
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	written	write	VERB	Q1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
3	communication	communication	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	shall	shall	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	contain	contain	VERB	A1.8p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	following	follow	VERB	N4	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
8	text	text	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

