# newdoc id = ParlaMint-PL_2022-06-23-sejm-57-2.u1
# newpar id = seg963379
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963379.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 4.049
# text = Resume session.
1	Resume	resume	VERB	Q1.2	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	session	session	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963380
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963380.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.239
# text = I would like to call Members Paulina Matysiak, Aleksandra Szcudło, Konrad Frysztak and Daniel Milewski to the secretaries of today's proceedings.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	would	would	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	like	like	VERB	E2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	call	call	VERB	Q2.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Members	Member	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Paulina	Paulina	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
8	Matysiak	Matysiak	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Aleksandra	Aleksandra	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
11	Szcudło	Szcudło	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Konrad	Konrad	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
14	Frysztak	Frysztak	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
15	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Daniel	Daniel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
17	Milewski	Milewski	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
18	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
20	secretaries	secretary	NOUN	I3.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
21	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	today	today	NOUN	T1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	proceedings	proceedings	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
25	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963381
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963381.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.934
# text = In the first part of the session, the secretaries will be Alexander Szczudło and Daniel Milewski.
1	In	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	first	first	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
4	part	part	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	session	session	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	secretaries	secretary	NOUN	I3.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
11	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
12	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Alexander	Alexander	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
14	Szczudło	Szczudło	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
15	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Daniel	Daniel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
17	Milewski	Milewski	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
18	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963382
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963382.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.306
# text = The minutes and the list of speakers will be led by Alexander Szczudko and Konrad Frysztak.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	minutes	minute	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	list	list	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	speakers	speaker	NOUN	Q2.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
8	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
9	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
10	led	lead	VERB	S7.1p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
11	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	Alexander	Alexander	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
13	Szczudko	Szczudko	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
14	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Konrad	Konrad	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
16	Frysztak	Frysztak	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
17	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963383
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963383.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.499
# text = I ask the Secretary to read the messages.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	ask	ask	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Secretary	secretary	NOUN	I3.2|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	read	read	VERB	Q3	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	messages	message	NOUN	Q1.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-PL_2022-06-23-sejm-57-2.u2
# newpar id = seg963384
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963384.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.025
# text = I would like to inform you that the following Commission meetings will be held today:
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	would	would	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	like	like	VERB	E2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	inform	inform	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
6	you	you	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	following	follow	VERB	M1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Commission	commission	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
11	meetings	meeting	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
12	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
14	held	hold	VERB	M2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
15	today	today	NOUN	T1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963385
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963385.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.869
# text = - Education, Science and Youth - hour 9,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Education	education	NOUN	P1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	Science	science	NOUN	Y1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Youth	youth	NOUN	T3n|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	9	9	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963386
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963386.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.528
# text = - Public Finance - hour. 9,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Public	Public	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	Finance	finance	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	9	9	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963387
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963387.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.891
# text = - Infrastructure - hour 9,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Infrastructure	infrastructure	NOUN	I2.1|S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	9	9	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963388
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963388.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.880
# text = - Culture and Media - hour 9,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Culture	Culture	NOUN	L1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	Media	media	NOUN	Q4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	9	9	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963389
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963389.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.932
# text = - Health-- hour. 9,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Health	health	NOUN	B2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	--	--	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	9	9	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963390
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963390.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.856
# text = - Economy and Development - h.m. 10,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Economy	economy	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	Development	development	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	h.m.	h.m.	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	10	10	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963391
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963391.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.936
# text = - Maritime Affairs and Inland Navigation - h.m. 10,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Maritime	maritime	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	Affairs	affair	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Inland	inland	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Navigation	navigation	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	h.m.	h.m.	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	10	10	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963392
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963392.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.266
# text = - Communication with Poles abroad - hour. 10,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Communication	Communication	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Poles	Poles	PROPN	Z2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
5	abroad	abroad	ADV	M7	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	10	10	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963393
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963393.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.958
# text = - Local Government and Regional Policy - h.m. 10,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Local	local	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	Government	government	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Regional	Regional	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Policy	policy	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	h.m.	h.m.	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	10	10	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963394
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963394.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.909
# text = - to the European Union, at 3 p.m. 10.30,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	European	European	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	Union	Union	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	3	3	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
9	p.m.	p.m.	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	10.30	10.30	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963395
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963395.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.988
# text = - Digitization, Innovation and Modern Technologies - h.m. 13,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Digitization	Digitization	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Innovation	innovation	NOUN	T3n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Modern	modern	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Technologies	Technology	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	h.m.	h.m.	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	13	13	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963396
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963396.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.992
# text = - to the European Union, at 3 p.m. 13,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	European	European	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	Union	Union	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	3	3	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
9	p.m.	p.m.	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	13	13	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963397
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963397.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.594
# text = - Public Finance - hour. 13,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Public	Public	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	Finance	finance	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	13	13	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963398
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963398.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.788
# text = - Infrastructure together with the Committee on Territorial Government and Regional Policy - h.m. 13,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Infrastructure	infrastructure	NOUN	I2.1|S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	together	together	ADV	S5p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Committee	Committee	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	on	on	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Territorial	territorial	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Government	Government	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Regional	Regional	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Policy	Policy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	h.m.	h.m.	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	13	13	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963399
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963399.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.806
# text = - Foreign Affairs - hour 13,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Foreign	foreign	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Affairs	affair	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
4	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	13	13	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963400
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963400.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.836
# text = - Legal notice - hour. 13,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Legal	legal	ADJ	G2.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	notice	notice	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	13	13	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963401
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963401.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.403
# text = - Public Finance - hour. 14,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Public	Public	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	Finance	finance	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	14	14	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963402
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963402.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.823
# text = - Culture and Media - hour 14,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Culture	Culture	NOUN	L1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
4	Media	media	NOUN	Q4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	14	14	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963403
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963403.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.600
# text = - Rules of Procedure, Parliamentary and Immunity Affairs - hour. 14,
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Rules	rule	NOUN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Immunity	immunity	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Affairs	affair	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	14	14	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963404
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963404.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.989
# text = - Digitization, Innovation and Modern Technologies - h.m. 14.15.
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Digitization	Digitization	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Innovation	innovation	NOUN	T3n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Modern	modern	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Technologies	Technology	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	h.m.	h.m.	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	14.15	14.15	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg963405
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg963405.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.154
# text = A joint meeting of the Parliamentary Team for the Development of Electromobility and Prosumer Energy will also be held today and the Parliamentary Group for the Development of Electromobility and Prosumer Energy. Energy and Energy and Mining Transformation in Poland - hour 14.
1	A	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	joint	joint	ADJ	S5p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	meeting	meeting	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	Team	Team	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Development	Development	PROPN	A2.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Electromobility	Electromobility	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Prosumer	Prosumer	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Energy	Energy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
17	also	also	ADV	N5p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
19	held	hold	VERB	M2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
20	today	today	NOUN	T1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
24	Group	Group	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Development	Development	PROPN	A2.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
28	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Electromobility	Electromobility	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Prosumer	Prosumer	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
32	Energy	Energy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
34	Energy	energy	NOUN	X5.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
35	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
36	Energy	Energy	PROPN	X5.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
37	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
38	Mining	Mining	NOUN	I4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
39	Transformation	Transformation	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
40	in	in	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	Poland	Poland	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
42	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	hour	hour	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
44	14	14	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
45	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg963405.2
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = positive
# senti_n = 4.600
# text = Thank you.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-PL_2022-06-23-sejm-57-2.u393
# newpar id = seg965343
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg965343.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.134
# text = On 23 June 2022, I declare that, due to technical problems, I could not give my vote correctly during the vote at the 57th meeting of the Sejm - vote No 54 - Report of the Committee on Education, Science and Youth on the Government draft law amending the Act - Teacher Charter and some other laws (prints No. 2351, 2357, 2357-A) - vote on the entire draft law.
1	On	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	23	23	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
3	June	June	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	2022	2022	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	declare	declare	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	due	due	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	to	to	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	technical	technical	ADJ	Y1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
13	problems	problem	NOUN	A12n	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
16	could	could	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
17	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	give	give	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
19	my	my	PRON	A5.4p	Number=Sing|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
20	vote	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	correctly	correctly	ADV	A5.3p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	during	during	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	vote	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	57th	57th	ADJ	Z99	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
28	meeting	meeting	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
29	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Sejm	Sejm	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
32	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	vote	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
34	No	no	DET	Z6	PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
35	54	54	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
36	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	Report	report	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
38	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
40	Committee	Committee	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
41	on	on	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
42	Education	Education	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
43	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
44	Science	Science	PROPN	Y1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
45	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
46	Youth	Youth	PROPN	T3n|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
47	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
48	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
49	Government	government	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
50	draft	draft	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
51	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
52	amending	amend	VERB	A2.1p	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
53	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
54	Act	act	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
55	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	Teacher	teacher	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
57	Charter	Charter	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
58	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
59	some	some	DET	N5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
60	other	other	ADJ	A6.1n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
61	laws	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
62	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
63	prints	print	NOUN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
64	No.	no.	NOUN	Z2	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
65	2351	2351	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
66	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
67	2357	2357	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
68	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
69	2357	2357	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
70	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
71	A	a	NOUN	Z5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
72	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
73	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
74	vote	vote	VERB	G1.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
75	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
76	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
77	entire	entire	ADJ	N5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
78	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
79	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
80	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg965344
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg965344.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 1.775
# text = My intention was to vote against, but as a result of the problems it was counted by the system as a pro.
1	My	my	PRON	Z8	Number=Sing|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	intention	intention	NOUN	X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	was	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	vote	vote	VERB	G1.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
6	against	against	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	but	but	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	as	as	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	result	result	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	problems	problem	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
15	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
16	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
17	counted	count	VERB	N2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
18	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
20	system	system	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	as	as	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	pro	pro	NOUN	I3.2p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-PL_2022-06-23-sejm-57-2.u394
# newpar id = seg965345
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg965345.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 4.071
# text = Mrs. Marshal!
1	Mrs.	Mrs.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
2	Marshal	Marshal	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
3	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965345.2
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.696
# text = High Izbo! 230 years ago on June 22, 1792, King Stanisław August Poniatowski, after his victory in the Battle of Greens, during the war in defence of the Constitution on May 3, established the Order of Virtuti Militari.
1	High	high	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Izbo	Izbo	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
3	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	230	230	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
5	years	year	NOUN	T1.1.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
6	ago	ago	ADV	T1.1.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	June	June	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	22	22	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	1792	1792	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	King	King	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	Stanisław	Stanisław	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
15	August	August	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
16	Poniatowski	Poniatowski	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	after	after	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	his	he	PRON	Z8	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
20	victory	victory	NOUN	X9.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Battle	Battle	PROPN	X8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
24	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	Greens	Greens	PROPN	O4.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	during	during	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
29	war	war	NOUN	G3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	defence	defence	NOUN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
32	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	Constitution	Constitution	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
35	on	on	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	May	May	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
37	3	3	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
38	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	established	establish	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
40	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
41	Order	Order	PROPN	S7.1p|Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
42	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
43	Virtuti	Virtuti	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
44	Militari	Militari	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
45	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965345.3
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.976
# text = Over the next 200 years, it honored heroes of all wars in defence of Polish sovereignty.
1	Over	over	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	next	next	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
4	200	200	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
5	years	year	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
8	honored	honor	VERB	Z99	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
9	heroes	heroe	NOUN	Q4.1|S2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	N6p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	all	all	DET	N6p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	wars	war	NOUN	N6p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
13	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	defence	defence	NOUN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Polish	Polish	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
17	sovereignty	sovereignty	NOUN	S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965346.2
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.661
# text = To date, the highest Polish military award has been awarded about 26 thousand. persons.
1	To	to	ADP	T1.1.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	date	date	NOUN	T1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	highest	high	ADJ	N3.7p	Degree=Sup	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Polish	Polish	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
7	military	military	ADJ	G3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
8	award	award	NOUN	A5.1p|A9n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
10	been	be	AUX	A3p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
11	awarded	award	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
12	about	about	ADV	A13.4	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	26	26	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
14	thousand	thousand	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	persons	person	NOUN	S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965346.3
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.254
# text = It was received by Kościuszko, insurgents: November, January, Greater Poland, Silesia and Warsaw, participants in the fight for independence of Poland, Polish-Bolshevik war, campaign 1939, soldiers of the Polish Armed Forces in the West and the National Army.
1	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	received	receive	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
4	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Kościuszko	Kościuszko	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	insurgents	insurgent	NOUN	Z99	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	November	November	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	January	January	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Greater	Great	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
14	Poland	Poland	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Silesia	Silesia	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
17	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Warsaw	Warsaw	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
19	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	participants	participant	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
21	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	fight	fight	NOUN	S8n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
24	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	independence	independence	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Poland	Poland	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Polish	Polish	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
30	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	Bolshevik	bolshevik	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
32	war	war	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	campaign	campaign	NOUN	X7p|Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
35	1939	1939	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	soldiers	soldier	NOUN	G3|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
38	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
40	Polish	Polish	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
41	Armed	armed	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
42	Forces	Force	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
43	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
45	West	West	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
46	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
48	National	National	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
49	Army	Army	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
50	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965346.4
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.265
# text = The youngest bachelor of the order is 13-year-old Antek Petrykiewicz, who was mortally wounded during the fight for Lviv in 1918, and the first woman Joanna Żubrowa, soldier of the Army of the Duchy of Warsaw.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	youngest	young	ADJ	T3n	Degree=Sup	0	_	_	NER=O
3	bachelor	bachelor	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	order	order	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	13	13	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	year	year	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	old	old	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Antek	Antek	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
14	Petrykiewicz	Petrykiewicz	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
17	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
18	mortally	mortally	ADV	L1n	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	wounded	wound	VERB	B2n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
20	during	during	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	fight	fight	NOUN	S8n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	Lviv	Lviv	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
25	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	1918	1918	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	first	first	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
31	woman	woman	NOUN	S2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
32	Joanna	Joanna	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
33	Żubrowa	Żubrowa	X	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
34	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	soldier	soldier	NOUN	G3|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
36	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
38	Army	Army	PROPN	G3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
39	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
40	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
41	Duchy	Duchy	PROPN	M7|S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
42	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	Warsaw	Warsaw	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
44	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965347.2
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 0.863
# text = Since 1989, the Order of Virtuti Militari has not been awarded.
1	Since	since	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	1989	1989	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Order	Order	PROPN	S7.1p|Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Virtuti	Virtuti	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Militari	Militari	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
10	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	been	be	AUX	A3p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
12	awarded	award	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965347.3
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.457
# text = The 1992 Law establishes that it will be broadcast only during the war or no later than 5 years after its completion.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	1992	1992	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Law	Law	PROPN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
4	establishes	establish	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
9	broadcast	broadcast	VERB	Q4.3	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
10	only	only	ADV	A14	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	during	during	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
13	war	war	NOUN	G3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	or	or	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	no	no	ADV	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	later	late	ADV	T4n	Degree=Cmp	0	_	_	NER=O
17	than	than	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	5	5	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
19	years	year	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
20	after	after	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	its	its	PRON	Z8	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
22	completion	completion	NOUN	T2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965347.4
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = negative
# senti_n = 0.383
# text = The complicated history of this award reflects the changing and tragic fate of Poland.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	complicated	complicated	ADJ	A12n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	history	history	NOUN	T1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
6	award	award	NOUN	A5.1p|A9n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	reflects	reflect	VERB	A10p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	changing	change	VERB	A2.1p	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
10	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	tragic	tragic	ADJ	E4.1n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
12	fate	fate	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	Poland	Poland	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = seg965348
# lang = en
# sent_id = seg965348.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 4.444
# text = High Izbo!
1	High	high	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Izbo	Izbo	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	!	!	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965348.2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.953
# text = It is worth mentioning that in 1995 the Chapter of the Order of Virtuti Militari explained the legality of the awards of this award in the period of the People's Poland.
1	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	worth	worth	ADJ	I1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
4	mentioning	mention	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
5	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	1995	1995	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Chapter	Chapter	PROPN	Q4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Order	Order	PROPN	S7.1p|Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Virtuti	Virtuti	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Militari	Militari	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	explained	explain	VERB	Q2.2|A7p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	legality	legality	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	awards	award	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
22	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
24	award	award	NOUN	A5.1p|A9n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	period	period	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
28	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	People	People	PROPN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
31	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
32	Poland	Poland	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = seg965348.3
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = negative
# senti_n = 0.183
# text = In a special document, she also stated:...) in defence and respect for these undoubted merits of Polish soldiers fighting on all fronts in defence of their homeland, however, we state loudly and clearly that the practice of giving the Orders of Virtuti Militari to the people of Poland, especially the highest classes given in an unprecedented number to representatives of foreign power, is an insult of the honor of the Polish soldier.
1	In	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	special	special	ADJ	A4.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
4	document	document	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	she	she	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Fem|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	also	also	ADV	N5p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	stated	state	VERB	Q2.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	...	...	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	defence	defence	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	respect	respect	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	these	this	DET	Z5	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
18	undoubted	undoubted	ADJ	Z99	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
19	merits	merit	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Polish	Polish	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
22	soldiers	soldier	NOUN	G3|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
23	fighting	fight	VERB	S8n	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
24	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	all	all	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	fronts	front	NOUN	M6	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
27	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	defence	defence	NOUN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
29	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	their	they	PRON	Z8	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
31	homeland	homeland	NOUN	M7	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	however	however	ADV	Z4	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
34	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
36	state	state	VERB	Q2.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
37	loudly	loudly	ADV	X3.2p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	clearly	clearly	ADV	A7p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
42	practice	practice	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
43	of	of	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	giving	give	VERB	A9n	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
45	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
46	Orders	order	NOUN	S7.1p|Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
47	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	Virtuti	Virtuti	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
49	Militari	Militari	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
50	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
51	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
52	people	people	NOUN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
53	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
54	Poland	Poland	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
55	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	especially	especially	ADV	A14	_	0	_	_	NER=O
57	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
58	highest	high	ADJ	A5.1p	Degree=Sup	0	_	_	NER=O
59	classes	class	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
60	given	give	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
61	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
62	an	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
63	unprecedented	unprecedented	ADJ	A6.2n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
64	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
65	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
66	representatives	representative	NOUN	Q2.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
67	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
68	foreign	foreign	ADJ	M7	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
69	power	power	NOUN	S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
70	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
71	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
72	an	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
73	insult	insult	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
74	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
75	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
76	honor	honor	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
77	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
78	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
79	Polish	Polish	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
80	soldier	soldier	NOUN	G3|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
81	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

