# newdoc id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.u1
# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg1.1
# text = Ladies and gentlemen, the meeting begins.
1	Ladies	lady	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	gentlemen	gentleman	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	meeting	meeting	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	begins	begin	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg2
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg2.1
# text = First, let me announce the topical and urgent question report on Thursday 5 December 2019.
1	First	first	ADV	N4	NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	let	let	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	me	I	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
5	announce	announce	VERB	Q2.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	topical	topical	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
8	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	urgent	urgent	ADJ	A11.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
10	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	report	report	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Thursday	Thursday	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	5	5	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
15	December	December	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	2019	2019	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg3
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg3.1
# text = A. FURTHER REQUIREMENTS First Circle (Articles 130(2) and (3) and 132(2) of Parliament's Rules of Procedure)
1	A.	A.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	FURTHER	further	ADJ	N5p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	REQUIREMENTS	REQUIREMENTS	PROPN	Z99	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
4	First	first	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Circle	Circle	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Articles	Article	PROPN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
8	130	130	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
9	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	3	3	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	132	132	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	Parliament	parliament	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	Rules	rule	NOUN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
25	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
26	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
27	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg4
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg4.1
# text = 1. The question by No 276/2-12-2019 by MP Carditsa of New Democracy Mrs.Asina Skondras to the Minister of Labour and Social Affairs, on the subject: "Serious malfunction due to the subordination of the services of the FOCA farmers of Thessaly".
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	No	no	DET	Z4	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	276/2-12-2019	276/2-12-2019	NUM	Z99	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	MP	MP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Carditsa	Carditsa	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	New	New	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Democracy	Democracy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Mrs.Asina	Mrs.Asina	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Skondras	Skondras	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Labour	Labour	PROPN	G1.2|Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
21	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Social	social	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Affairs	affair	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	Serious	Serious	ADJ	A11.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
31	malfunction	malfunction	NOUN	A1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
32	due	due	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	to	to	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
35	subordination	subordination	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
36	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
38	services	service	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
39	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
41	FOCA	FOCA	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
42	farmers	farmer	NOUN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
43	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	Thessaly	Thessaly	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
45	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
46	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg5
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg5.1
# text = 2. (') OJ No L 2. 2. 1990, p. 2. The question raised by Mr Constantine Barkas, Member of the Radical Left, to the Minister of Labour and Social Affairs, on the extension of the Joint Projects.
1	2.	2.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	(')	(')	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	OJ	oj	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	No	no	ADV	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	L	l	SYM	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	2	2	NUM	T1.3	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	1990	1990	NUM	T1.3	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	p.	P.	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	2	2	NUM	N1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	raised	raise	VERB	M2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
18	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Constantine	Constantine	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
21	Barkas	Barkas	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Member	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
24	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
26	Radical	Radical	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
27	Left	Left	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
32	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
33	Labour	Labour	PROPN	G1.2|Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
34	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
35	Social	social	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
36	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
37	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
40	extension	extension	NOUN	H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
41	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
43	Joint	Joint	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
44	Projects	Project	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
45	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg6
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg6.1
# text = 3. The question by No 265/27-11-2019 of the Member of the State of Change Movement Mr. Georgios Kaminis Kaminis to the Minister of the Interior, on the subject: "Association of public bodies with merital criteria".
1	3	3	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	No	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	265/27-11-2019	265/27-11-2019	NUM	Z99	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Member	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
11	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	State	State	PROPN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Change	Change	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Movement	Movement	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Georgios	Georgios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
19	Kaminis	Kaminis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
20	Kaminis	Kaminis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
21	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
24	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
26	Interior	Interior	PROPN	M6	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	Association	association	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
34	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
35	public	public	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
36	bodies	body	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
37	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	merital	merital	ADJ	Z99	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
39	criteria	criterion	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
40	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg7
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg7.1
# text = 4. The 283/12-2019 topical question by MP Heraklion of the Communist Party of Greece, Manolis Synthraki to the Minister of the Interior, on the subject: "Direct restoration of the damage caused by the catastrophic floods in Chania, support and compensation for the injured".
1	4	4	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	283/12-2019	283/12-2019	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
5	topical	topical	ADJ	N1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
6	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	MP	MP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	Heraklion	Heraklion	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	Communist	Communist	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Greece	Greece	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Manolis	Manolis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
18	Synthraki	Synthraki	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
19	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	Interior	Interior	PROPN	M6	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
25	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
28	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	Direct	direct	ADJ	M6	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
32	restoration	restoration	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
35	damage	damage	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
36	caused	cause	VERB	A2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
37	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	catastrophic	catastrophic	ADJ	A5.1n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
40	floods	flood	NOUN	W4	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
41	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	Chania	Chania	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
43	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	support	support	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
45	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	compensation	compensation	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
47	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
49	injured	injure	VERB	B2n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
50	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
51	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg8
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg8.1
# text = B. PERSONS OF 2nd Cycle QUESTIONS (Articles 130(2) and (3) and 132(2) of Parliament's Rules of Procedure)
1	B.	B.	X	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	PERSONS	person	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	OF	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	2nd	2nd	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Cycle	cycle	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	QUESTIONS	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
7	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	Articles	Article	PROPN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
9	130	130	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	3	3	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	132	132	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Parliament	parliament	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Rules	rule	NOUN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
26	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
27	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
28	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg9
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg9.1
# text = 1. Evangelos Evangelos Apostolos to the Minister of Labour and Social Affairs, on the subject: "Prolonging employment through the programmes of a mutual nature in the protection of forest ecosystems in the country".
1	1.	1.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Evangelos	Evangelos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
3	Evangelos	Evangelos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
4	Apostolos	Apostolos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
5	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Labour	Labour	PROPN	G1.2|Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
10	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Social	social	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Affairs	affair	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	Prolonging	prolong	VERB	T1.3p	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
20	employment	employment	NOUN	I3.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	through	through	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	programmes	programme	NOUN	X7p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
24	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
26	mutual	mutual	ADJ	S1.1.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
27	nature	nature	NOUN	W5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
28	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	protection	protection	NOUN	S8p|A15p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
31	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	forest	forest	NOUN	W3|L3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	ecosystems	ecosystem	NOUN	W5	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
34	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
36	country	country	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
38	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg10
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg10.1
# text = 2. (') OJ No L 2. 2. 1990, p. 2. The question raised by Mr Georgios Mulkiotis under No 266/28-11-2019 by Mr Georgios Mulkiotis to the Minister of Labour and Social Affairs on the subject: ‘Is there finally a securitisation and sale of outstanding debts of the Centre for the Collection of Insurance Debts?’.
1	2.	2.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	(')	(')	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	OJ	oj	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	No	no	ADV	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	L	l	SYM	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	2	2	NUM	N1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	2	2	NUM	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	1990	1990	NUM	T1.3	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	p.	P.	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	2	2	NUM	N1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	raised	raise	VERB	M2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
18	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Georgios	Georgios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
21	Mulkiotis	Mulkiotis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
22	under	under	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	No	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	266/28-11-2019	266/28-11-2019	NUM	Z99	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
25	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Georgios	Georgios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
28	Mulkiotis	Mulkiotis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
29	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
32	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	Labour	Labour	PROPN	G1.2|Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
34	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
35	Social	social	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
36	Affairs	affair	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
37	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
40	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	‘	‘	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	Is	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
43	there	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	finally	finally	ADV	N4	_	0	_	_	NER=O
45	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
46	securitisation	securitisation	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
47	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	sale	sale	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
49	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
50	outstanding	outstanding	ADJ	A5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
51	debts	debt	NOUN	I1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
52	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
53	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
54	Centre	centre	NOUN	M6	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
55	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
56	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
57	Collection	Collection	NOUN	A9p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
58	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
59	Insurance	insurance	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
60	Debts	debt	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
61	?’.	?’.	PUNCT	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg11
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg11.1
# text = 3. The 284/3-12-2019 topical question by Piraeus II of the Communist Party of Greece Mr Diamantos Manolakos to the Minister of Labour and Social Affairs, on the subject: "The workers in the programme of public work on forest protection".
1	3	3	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	284/3-12-2019	284/3-12-2019	NUM	Z99	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
5	topical	topical	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
6	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Piraeus	Piraeus	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	II	ii	NUM	Z1	NumForm=Roman|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	Communist	Communist	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Greece	Greece	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Diamantos	Diamantos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
18	Manolakos	Manolakos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
19	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Labour	Labour	PROPN	G1.2|Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
24	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	Social	social	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Affairs	affair	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	workers	worker	NOUN	I3.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
35	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
37	programme	programme	NOUN	X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
38	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	public	public	ADJ	S5p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
40	work	work	NOUN	I3.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
41	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	forest	forest	NOUN	W3|L3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
43	protection	protection	NOUN	S8p|A15p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
44	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
45	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg12
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg12.1
# text = 4. The question under number 273/2-12-2019 by MP Larissa of the Radical Left Coalition Mr Vassilis Kossilis to the Minister for Rural Development and Food, on the subject: "Public Agricultural Land: Great opportunities to support young farmers and professional farmers, but the Ministry of Rural Development and Food (YPAF) is deaf".
1	4	4	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	under	under	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	273/2-12-2019	273/2-12-2019	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	MP	MP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
10	Larissa	Larissa	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
11	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Radical	Radical	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
14	Left	Left	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Coalition	Coalition	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Vassilis	Vassilis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
18	Kossilis	Kossilis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
19	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Rural	rural	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
24	Development	Development	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Food	food	PROPN	F1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	Public	Public	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
34	Agricultural	agricultural	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
35	Land	land	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	Great	great	ADJ	A5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
38	opportunities	opportunity	NOUN	A1.4	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
39	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	support	support	VERB	S8p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
41	young	young	ADJ	T3n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
42	farmers	farmer	NOUN	F4|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
43	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	professional	professional	ADJ	I3.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
45	farmers	farmer	NOUN	F4|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
46	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	but	but	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
49	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
50	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
51	Rural	rural	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
52	Development	Development	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
53	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
54	Food	food	NOUN	F1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
55	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
56	YPAF	YPAF	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
57	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
58	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
59	deaf	deaf	ADJ	X3.2n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
60	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
61	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg13
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg13.1
# text = 5. The question raised by Mr Georgios Mulkiotis, Member of the European Parliament, Mr Georgios Mulkiotis, Minister for Labour and Social Affairs, on the subject: "In the air, workers in the social programme for the protection of forest ecosystems in the country".
1	5	5	NUM	N1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	raised	raise	VERB	M2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
6	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Georgios	Georgios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
9	Mulkiotis	Mulkiotis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Member	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	European	European	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
15	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Georgios	Georgios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
19	Mulkiotis	Mulkiotis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Labour	Labour	PROPN	G1.2|Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
24	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	Social	social	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	In	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
35	air	air	NOUN	O1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	workers	worker	NOUN	I3.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
38	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
40	social	social	ADJ	S1.1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
41	programme	programme	NOUN	X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
42	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
44	protection	protection	NOUN	S8p|A15p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
45	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	forest	forest	NOUN	W3|L3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
47	ecosystems	ecosystem	NOUN	W5	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
48	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
49	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
50	country	country	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
51	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
52	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg14
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg14.1
# text = Ladies and gentlemen, we are entering the agenda of the LEGISLATIVE WORK
1	Ladies	lady	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	gentlemen	gentleman	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
6	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
7	entering	enter	VERB	M1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	agenda	agenda	NOUN	Q1.2|X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	LEGISLATIVE	legislative	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	WORK	work	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg15
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg15.1
# text = The only debate and vote on the principle of the articles and the whole draft law of the Ministry of Labour and Social Affairs: "Following the Agreement between the Hellenic Republic and the Republic of Serbia in the area of social security and its Administrative Rules".
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	only	only	ADJ	A14	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	debate	debate	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	vote	vote	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	principle	principle	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	articles	article	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
12	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	whole	whole	ADJ	N5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
15	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Labour	Labour	PROPN	G1.2|Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
22	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Social	social	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
24	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
25	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	Following	follow	VERB	M1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Agreement	agreement	NOUN	A6.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	between	between	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
32	Hellenic	Hellenic	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
33	Republic	Republic	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
34	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
36	Republic	Republic	PROPN	S5p|M7	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
37	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
38	Serbia	Serbia	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
39	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
41	area	area	NOUN	M7	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
42	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	social	social	ADJ	S1.1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
44	security	security	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
45	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	its	its	PRON	Z8	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
47	Administrative	administrative	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
48	Rules	rule	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
49	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
50	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg16
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg16.1
# text = The draft was adopted by a majority in the Standing Committee.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	adopted	adopt	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
5	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	majority	majority	NOUN	N5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Standing	Standing	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
11	Committee	Committee	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
12	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg16.2
# text = It is introduced to the House in accordance with the procedure laid down in Rule 108 of the Rules of Procedure, namely those who object to the ratification of this agreement.
1	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	introduced	introduce	VERB	S1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	House	House	PROPN	H4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	accordance	accordance	NOUN	S7.1n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	procedure	procedure	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	laid	lay	VERB	M2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
13	down	down	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Rule	rule	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
16	108	108	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
17	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Rules	rule	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	namely	namely	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	those	that	PRON	Z5	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
25	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
26	object	object	VERB	A6.1n	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
27	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
29	ratification	ratification	NOUN	S7.4p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
32	agreement	agreement	NOUN	A6.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg17
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg17.1
# text = Does the House agree?
1	Does	do	AUX	S1.1.3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	House	House	PROPN	H4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	agree	agree	VERB	A6.1p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	?	?	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.u2
# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg18
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg18.1
# text = The House has agreed.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	House	House	PROPN	H4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	agreed	agree	VERB	A6.1p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg19
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg19.1
# text = New Democracy, SYRIZA and the Change Movement have voted in favour.
1	New	New	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
2	Democracy	Democracy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	SYRIZA	SYRIZA	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Change	Change	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
8	Movement	Movement	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
10	voted	vote	VERB	G1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
11	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	favour	favour	NOUN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg20
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg20.1
# text = He had the Communist Party of Greece.
1	He	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	had	have	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Communist	Communist	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Greece	Greece	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg21
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg21.1
# text = Mr Kattotis, you have the floor for five minutes.
1	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Kattotis	Kattotis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
5	have	have	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	floor	floor	NOUN	H2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	five	five	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
10	minutes	minute	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.u51
# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg212
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg212.1
# text = The House therefore approved the requested permission.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	House	House	PROPN	H4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
3	therefore	therefore	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	approved	approve	VERB	S7.4p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	requested	request	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
7	permission	permission	NOUN	S7.4p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg213
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg213.1
# text = Ladies and gentlemen, do you accept that we shall be able to resolve the meeting here?
1	Ladies	lady	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	gentlemen	gentleman	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	do	do	AUX	S1.1.3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	accept	accept	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
8	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
10	shall	shall	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
12	able	able	ADJ	X9.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
13	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	resolve	resolve	VERB	X6p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	meeting	meeting	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	here	here	ADV	M6	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	?	?	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.u52
# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg214
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2019-12-04-S1-commons.seg214.1
# text = With the consent of the House at 10.13 p.m. the sitting is closed for tomorrow, Thursday 5 December 2019 at 9 p.m., on the subject of Parliament's work: (a) parliamentary scrutiny, topical debate, and (b) legislative work, only discussion and vote at first, articles and all the draft law of the Ministry of Finance: "Forum reform with a development dimension for Greece of tomorrow".
1	With	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	consent	consent	NOUN	S7.4p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	House	House	PROPN	H4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	10.13	10.13	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
9	p.m.	p.m.	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	sitting	sitting	NOUN	M8	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	closed	close	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
14	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	tomorrow	tomorrow	NOUN	T1.1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Thursday	Thursday	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	5	5	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
19	December	December	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	2019	2019	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
21	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	9	9	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
23	p.m.	p.m.	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	subject	subject	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
28	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	work	work	NOUN	I3.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
34	a	a	NUM	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
37	scrutiny	scrutiny	NOUN	X2.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
38	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	topical	topical	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
40	debate	debate	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
44	b	b	NUM	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
45	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	legislative	legislative	ADJ	G2.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
47	work	work	NOUN	I3.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
48	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
49	only	only	ADV	A14	_	0	_	_	NER=O
50	discussion	discussion	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
51	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
52	vote	vote	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
53	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
54	first	first	ADV	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
55	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	articles	article	NOUN	Q4.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
57	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
58	all	all	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
59	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
60	draft	draft	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
61	law	law	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
62	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
63	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
64	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
65	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
66	Finance	Finance	PROPN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
67	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
68	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
69	Forum	Forum	PROPN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
70	reform	reform	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
71	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
72	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
73	development	development	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
74	dimension	dimension	NOUN	A4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
75	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
76	Greece	Greece	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
77	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
78	tomorrow	tomorrow	NOUN	T1.1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
79	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
80	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

