# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.u1
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg1.1
# text = There's a quorum.
1	There	there	PRON	EX	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	quorum	quorum	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg1.2
# text = I'm opening the meeting.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	'm	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	opening	open	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	meeting	meeting	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg2
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg2.1
# text = We continue with point one for today:
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	continue	continue	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	point	point	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	one	one	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	today	today	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg3
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg3.1
# text = THE SECOND VOICE OF THE LAW FOR CHANGE AND CLEARANCE OF THE LAW OF ATMOSFER AIR.
1	THE	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	SECOND	second	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	VOICE	voice	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	OF	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	THE	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	LAW	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	FOR	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	CHANGE	change	VERB	VB	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	AND	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	CLEARANCE	clearance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	OF	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	THE	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	LAW	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	OF	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	ATMOSFER	atmosfer	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	AIR	AIR	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg4
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg4.1
# text = Importer of the Council of Ministers.
1	Importer	importer	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg5
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg5.1
# text = He was adopted in the first vote on 12 September 2019.
1	He	he	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	was	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	adopted	adopt	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	first	first	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	vote	vote	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	12	12	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	September	September	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	2019	2019	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg6
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg6.1
# text = You have the floor to present the Commission Report, Mr. Grudev.
1	You	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	have	have	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	floor	floor	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	present	present	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Commission	commission	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
9	Report	report	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	Grudev	Grudev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.u2
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg7
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg7.1
# text = Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Chairman	Chairman	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg8
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg8.1
# text = Dear colleagues, on the basis of art. 49, para. 2 of the Rules on Organization and Activity of the National Assembly I propose that Mrs. Atanaska Nikolova be admitted to the Chamber, and Mr. Ivan Angelov, Director of the Department of Air Cleanliness in the Ministry of Environment and Water.
1	Dear	dear	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	colleagues	colleague	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	basis	basis	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	art	art	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	49	49	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	para	para	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	2	2	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
18	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Organization	Organization	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Activity	activity	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
24	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
25	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
26	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	propose	propose	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	Mrs.	Mrs.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	Atanaska	Atanaska	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
31	Nikolova	Nikolova	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
32	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	admitted	admit	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	Chamber	Chamber	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
37	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	Ivan	Ivan	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
41	Angelov	Angelov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
42	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	Director	Director	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	Department	Department	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
47	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
48	Air	Air	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
49	Cleanliness	Cleanliness	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
50	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
51	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
52	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
53	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
54	Environment	environment	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
55	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
56	Water	Water	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
57	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.u82
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg460
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg460.1
# text = Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Chairman	Chairman	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg461
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg461.1
# text = Ladies and gentlemen of the House!
1	Ladies	lady	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	gentlemen	gentleman	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	!	!	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg461.2
# text = I use this text to say that I express on my behalf and on behalf of our parliamentary group satisfaction that we have adopted a good law that has been required.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	use	use	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	text	text	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	say	say	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	express	express	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	my	my	PRON	PRP$	Number=Sing|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	behalf	behalf	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	behalf	behalf	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	our	we	PRON	PRP$	Number=Plur|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	group	group	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	satisfaction	satisfaction	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	adopted	adopt	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	good	good	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	that	that	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	been	be	AUX	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	required	require	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg462
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg462.1
# text = However, I draw attention to the fact that the texts that we have adopted now have created the so-called centres, which was, of course, essential.
1	However	however	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	draw	draw	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	attention	attention	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	fact	fact	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	texts	text	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	that	that	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	adopted	adopt	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	now	now	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	created	create	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	so	so	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	called	call	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	centres	centre	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	was	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	of	of	ADP	IN	ExtPos=ADV	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	course	course	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	essential	essential	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg462.2
# text = Until now, the secret apartments in Bulgaria regarding human trafficking have also been said in the Commission, in the stenogram, I do not reveal any secret... were only in Burgas and Varna.
1	Until	until	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	now	now	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	secret	secret	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	apartments	apartment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Bulgaria	Bulgaria	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
9	regarding	regard	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	human	human	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	trafficking	trafficking	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	also	also	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	been	be	AUX	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	said	say	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Commission	commission	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
19	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	stenogram	stenogram	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	do	do	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	reveal	reveal	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	any	any	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	secret	secret	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	...	...	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	were	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	only	only	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	Burgas	Burgas	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
35	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	Varna	Varna	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
37	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg462.3
# text = There was no safe house in D.C.
1	There	there	PRON	EX	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	was	be	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	no	no	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	safe	safe	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	house	house	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	D.C	D.C	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg463
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg463.1
# text = With the opening of the auxiliary centers now, I hope at least in the big, let's say, six district cities have them, to be financially secured so that there can be a better result than the measures we have just adopted.
1	With	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	opening	opening	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	auxiliary	auxiliary	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	centers	center	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	now	now	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	hope	hope	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	at	at	ADP	IN	ExtPos=ADV	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	least	least	ADJ	JJS	Degree=Sup	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	big	big	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	let	let	VERB	VB	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	's	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	say	say	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	six	six	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	district	district	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	cities	city	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	have	have	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	them	they	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=3|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	financially	financially	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	secured	secure	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	so	so	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	there	there	PRON	EX	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	can	can	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	be	be	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	better	good	ADJ	JJR	Degree=Cmp	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	result	result	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	than	than	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	measures	measure	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	just	just	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	adopted	adopt	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
47	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg463.2
# text = Thank you for your attention.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	your	you	PRON	PRP$	Person=2|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	attention	attention	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.u83
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg464
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg464.1
# text = Thank you, dear Mr. Chenchev.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	dear	dear	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Chenchev	Chenchev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg465
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg465.1
# text = Are there any lines?
1	Are	be	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	there	there	PRON	EX	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	any	any	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	lines	line	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	?	?	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg465.2
# text = I won't.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	wo	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	n't	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg466
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg466.1
# text = Any other speeches?
1	Any	any	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	other	other	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	speeches	speech	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	?	?	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg466.2
# text = I won't.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	wo	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	n't	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg467
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg467.1
# text = I shall put to the vote the text of the importer for ยง 14.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	shall	shall	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	put	put	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	vote	vote	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	text	text	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	importer	importer	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	ยง	ยง	SYM	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	14	14	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg468
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg468.1
# text = Vote 97 MPs: 97, no abstentions.
1	Vote	vote	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	97	97	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	MPs	mp	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	97	97	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	no	no	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	abstentions	abstention	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg469
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg469.1
# text = The motion is accepted.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	motion	motion	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	accepted	accept	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg470
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg470.1
# text = Thank you, dear Mrs. Alexandrova.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	dear	dear	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Mrs.	Mrs.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
6	Alexandrova	Alexandrova	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg471
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg471.1
# text = Parliamentary control messages for 4 October 2019:
1	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	control	control	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	messages	message	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	4	4	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	October	October	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	2019	2019	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg472
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg472.1
# text = 1. Deputy Prime Minister for Economic and Demographic Policy Mariana Nikolova will answer one question from the MP Desislav Chukolov.
1	1.	1.	X	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	Deputy	deputy	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Prime	Prime	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Economic	economic	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
7	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Demographic	Demographic	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Policy	Policy	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Mariana	Mariana	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
11	Nikolova	Nikolova	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
12	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	answer	answer	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	one	one	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	question	question	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	MP	mp	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	Desislav	Desislav	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
20	Chukolov	Chukolov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
21	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg473
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg473.1
# text = 2. The Minister of Health Kiril Ananiev will answer six questions from the MPs Teodora Georgieva, Georgi Yordanov and Ilian Timchev to two questions, Georgi Mihailov, Georgi Yordanov, Ilian Timchev, Anelia Klisarova and Valentina Naydenova.
1	2	2	NUM	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Minister	minister	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Health	Health	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Kiril	Kiril	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
8	Ananiev	Ananiev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
9	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	answer	answer	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	six	six	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	MPs	mp	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Teodora	Teodora	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
17	Georgieva	Georgieva	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	Georgi	Georgi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
20	Yordanov	Yordanov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
21	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	Ilian	Ilian	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
23	Timchev	Timchev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
24	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	two	two	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	Georgi	Georgi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
29	Mihailov	Mihailov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
30	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	Georgi	Georgi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
32	Yordanov	Yordanov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
33	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	Ilian	Ilian	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
35	Timchev	Timchev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
36	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	Anelia	Anelia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
38	Klisarova	Klisarova	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
39	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	Valentina	Valentina	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
41	Naydenova	Naydenova	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
42	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg474
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg474.1
# text = 3. The Minister of Education and Science Krasimir Valchev will answer a question from the National Representative Svetla Bachvarova.
1	3	3	NUM	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Education	Education	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
7	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Science	Science	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Krasimir	Krasimir	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Valchev	Valchev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
11	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	answer	answer	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	question	question	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
18	Representative	Representative	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Svetla	Svetla	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
20	Bachvarova	Bachvarova	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
21	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg475
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg475.1
# text = 4. Culture Minister Boel Banov will answer a question from the National Representative Anton Kutev.
1	4.	4.	X	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	Culture	Culture	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Boel	Boel	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
5	Banov	Banov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
6	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	answer	answer	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	question	question	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Representative	Representative	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Anton	Anton	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
15	Kutev	Kutev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
16	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg476
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg476.1
# text = 5. The Minister of Transport, Information Technology and Communications Rosen Zhelyazkov will answer a question from the MPs Kristina Sidorova and Dimitar Danchev.
1	5	5	NUM	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Transport	Transport	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Information	Information	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Technology	Technology	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Communications	Communication	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Rosen	Rosen	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
13	Zhelyazkov	Zhelyazkov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
14	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	answer	answer	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	question	question	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	MPs	mp	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	Kristina	Kristina	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
22	Sidorova	Sidorova	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
23	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	Dimitar	Dimitar	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
25	Danchev	Danchev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
26	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg477
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg477.1
# text = 6. Economy Minister Emil Karanikolov will answer three questions from the MPs Nikolay Alexandrov, Hristo Prodanov and Georgi Gokov.
1	6.	6.	X	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	Economy	economy	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Emil	Emil	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
5	Karanikolov	Karanikolov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
6	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	answer	answer	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	three	three	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	MPs	mp	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	Nikolay	Nikolay	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
14	Alexandrov	Alexandrov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Hristo	Hristo	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
17	Prodanov	Prodanov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
18	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	Georgi	Georgi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
20	Gokov	Gokov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
21	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg478
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg478.1
# text = On the basis of art. 96, para. Art. 3 and Art. OJ L 268, 18.10.2003, p. 29. 2 of the Rules of Organization and Activity of the National Assembly adjourned responses by seven days have requested:
1	On	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	basis	basis	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	art	art	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	96	96	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	para	para	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Art.	Art.	PROPN	NNP	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	3	3	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	Art.	Art.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	OJ	OJ	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
16	L	L	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	268	268	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	18.10.2003	18.10.2003	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	p.	P.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	29	29	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	2	2	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
28	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Organization	Organization	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
30	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Activity	activity	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
32	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
33	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
34	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
35	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
36	adjourned	adjourn	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	responses	response	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	seven	seven	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	days	day	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	requested	request	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
43	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg479
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg479.1
# text = - the Minister of Interior Mladen Marinov, to two questions from the MPs Diana Savateva and Alexander Paunov;
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Interior	Interior	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Mladen	Mladen	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
7	Marinov	Marinov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	two	two	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	MPs	mp	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	Diana	Diana	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
16	Savateva	Savateva	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
17	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Alexander	Alexander	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
19	Paunov	Paunov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
20	;	;	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg480
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg480.1
# text = - Minister of Environment and Water Neno Dimov to two questions with written answer from the MPs Nadia Klisurska, Georgi Stoilov and Ivan Dimov Ivanov;
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Environment	environment	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
5	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Water	Water	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Neno	Neno	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Dimov	Dimov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	two	two	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	written	write	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	answer	answer	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	MPs	mp	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Nadia	Nadia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
19	Klisurska	Klisurska	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	Georgi	Georgi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
22	Stoilov	Stoilov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
23	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	Ivan	Ivan	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
25	Dimov	Dimov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
26	Ivanov	Ivanov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
27	;	;	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg481
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg481.1
# text = - Minister of Education and Science Krasimir Valchev to two questions from the MPs Stanislav Stanilov, Anelia Klisarova and Nona Yotova.
1	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Education	Education	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
5	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Science	Science	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Krasimir	Krasimir	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
8	Valchev	Valchev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
9	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	two	two	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	MPs	mp	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	Stanislav	Stanislav	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
16	Stanilov	Stanilov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Anelia	Anelia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
19	Klisarova	Klisarova	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
20	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	Nona	Nona	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
22	Yotova	Yotova	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
23	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg482
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg482.1
# text = Due to the absence of the MPs Alexander Matsurev and Georgi Dinev for respectable reasons, their question is postponed to the Minister of Education and Science Krasimir Valchev.
1	Due	due	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	absence	absence	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	MPs	mp	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Alexander	Alexander	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
9	Matsurev	Matsurev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
10	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Georgi	Georgi	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
12	Dinev	Dinev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
13	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	respectable	respectable	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	reasons	reason	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	their	they	PRON	PRP$	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	question	question	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	postponed	postpone	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
24	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
25	Education	Education	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
26	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
27	Science	Science	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
28	Krasimir	Krasimir	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Valchev	Valchev	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
30	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg483
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg483.1
# text = In the absence of the country in the parliamentary control meeting, the Minister of Agriculture, Food and Forests Desislava Taneva and the Minister of Environment and Water Neno Dimov will not participate.
1	In	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	absence	absence	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	country	country	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	control	control	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	meeting	meeting	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
15	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Agriculture	Agriculture	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Food	food	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Forests	Forest	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Desislava	Desislava	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Taneva	Taneva	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	Environment	environment	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
28	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Water	Water	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
30	Neno	Neno	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Dimov	Dimov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
32	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	participate	participate	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg484
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg484.1
# text = Due to an urgent official commitment to the parliamentary control meeting, the Prime Minister of the Republic of Bulgaria Boyko Borisov will not participate.
1	Due	due	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	urgent	urgent	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	official	official	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	commitment	commitment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	control	control	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	meeting	meeting	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	Prime	Prime	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	Minister	Minister	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Republic	Republic	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
19	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Bulgaria	Bulgaria	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Boyko	Boyko	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
22	Borisov	Borisov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
23	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	participate	participate	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg485
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg485.1
# text = The next regular plenary session shall be on 4 October 2019 at 9:00.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	next	next	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	regular	regular	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	plenary	plenary	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	shall	shall	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	4	4	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	October	October	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	2019	2019	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	at	at	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	9:00	9:00	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg486
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BG_2019-10-03.seg486.1
# text = We're adjourned.
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	're	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	adjourned	adjourn	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

