# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.u1
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1.s1
# text = Good morning, let's start the session.
1	Good	good	ADJ	Z4	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	morning	morning	NOUN	Z4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	let	let	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	's	we	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
6	start	start	VERB	T2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	session	session	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg2
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg2.s1
# text = Let us resume the session with agenda item 6, which corresponds to questions for oral reply by the President of the Union.
1	Let	let	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	us	we	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	resume	resume	VERB	T2p|N6p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	session	session	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	agenda	agenda	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	item	item	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	6	6	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
12	corresponds	correspond	VERB	Q1.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	questions	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
15	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	oral	oral	ADJ	B1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
17	reply	reply	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
20	President	President	PROPN	G1.1|S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
21	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Union	Union	PROPN	Z3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg3
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg3.s1
# text = Ask Mr. President of the Galician Council of Da Ana Belén Pontón Mondelo, G.P. of the Galego Nationalist Block, on the actions planned by the Government of Greece to avoid the sale by Ferroatlantica of the hydroelectric power stations of the river Xallas
1	Ask	ask	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	President	President	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Galician	Galician	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	Council	Council	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Da	Da	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Ana	Ana	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Belén	Belén	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Pontón	Pontón	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Mondelo	Mondelo	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	G.P.	G.P.	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
16	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Galego	Galego	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Nationalist	Nationalist	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Block	Block	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	actions	action	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
25	planned	plan	VERB	X7p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
26	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
28	Government	Government	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
29	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	Greece	Greece	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
31	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	avoid	avoid	VERB	A1.9	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	sale	sale	NOUN	I2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
35	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	Ferroatlantica	Ferroatlantica	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
37	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	hydroelectric	hydroelectric	ADJ	Z99	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
40	power	power	NOUN	S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
41	stations	station	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
42	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
44	river	river	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
45	Xallas	Xallas	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.u2
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg4
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg4.s1
# text = You have the floor to Mrs. Pontón.
1	You	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	have	have	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	floor	floor	NOUN	H2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Mrs.	Mrs.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
7	Pontón	Pontón	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.u375
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1156
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1156.s1
# text = They were several.
1	They	they	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	were	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	several	several	ADJ	N5	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.u376
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1157
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1157.s1
# text = No, one.
1	No	no	INTJ	Z4	Polarity=Neg	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	one	one	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1157.s2
# text = No, no, sorry.
1	No	no	INTJ	Z4	Polarity=Neg	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	no	no	INTJ	Z4	Polarity=Neg	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	sorry	sorry	INTJ	Z4	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1157.s3
# text = Look, I'm going to tell you something, we're going to finish this in peace, I'm going to tell you what happened, because I was in the debate.
1	Look	look	VERB	A8	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	'm	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	going	go	VERB	T1.1.3	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
6	to	to	PART	T1.1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	tell	tell	VERB	A5.4p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
8	you	you	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
9	something	something	PRON	Z8	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	're	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	going	go	VERB	T1.1.3	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
14	to	to	PART	T1.1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	finish	finish	VERB	T2n	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
16	this	this	PRON	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
17	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	peace	peace	NOUN	E3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	'm	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
22	going	go	VERB	T1.1.3	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
23	to	to	PART	T1.1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	tell	tell	VERB	Z4	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
25	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
26	what	what	PRON	Z4	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
27	happened	happen	VERB	A2.1p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	because	because	SCONJ	Z5|A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
31	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
32	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	debate	debate	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1157.s4
# text = It was precisely that the People's Parliamentary Group was prepared to vote on its non-law proposal, because it was an inclusive debate, provided that the amendment of En Marea was not included.
1	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	was	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	precisely	precisely	ADV	A4.2p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	People	People	PROPN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Group	Group	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	prepared	prepare	VERB	X7p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
12	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	vote	vote	VERB	G1.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
14	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	its	its	PRON	Z8	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
16	non-law	non-law	ADJ	Z99	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
17	proposal	proposal	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	because	because	SCONJ	Z5|A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
21	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
22	an	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	inclusive	inclusive	ADJ	A1.8p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
24	debate	debate	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
25	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	provided	provide	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
27	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
29	amendment	amendment	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	En	En	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
32	Marea	Marea	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
33	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
34	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	included	include	VERB	A1.8p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1157.s5
# text = This is what happened.
1	This	this	PRON	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
2	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	what	what	PRON	Z8	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
4	happened	happen	VERB	A2.1p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1157.s6
# text = As the amendment of En Marea was included, the proposal to be voted on by the People's Parliamentary Group could not be voted on.
1	As	as	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	amendment	amendment	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	En	En	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Marea	Marea	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	included	include	VERB	A1.8p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	proposal	proposal	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
14	voted	vote	VERB	G1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
15	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	People	People	PROPN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
19	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Group	Group	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
22	could	could	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
23	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
25	voted	vote	VERB	G1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
26	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1157.s7
# text = There was no inaccuracy, I was attentive to the debate.
1	There	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	was	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	no	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	inaccuracy	inaccuracy	NOUN	A5.3n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	attentive	attentive	ADJ	X5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
9	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	debate	debate	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1157.s8
# text = That's right.
1	That	that	PRON	Z5	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	right	right	ADJ	A5.3p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1158
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1158.s1
# text = We're suspending... There wasn't... I'm telling you, there wasn't...
1	We	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	're	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	suspending	suspend	VERB	M2	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	...	...	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	There	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	was	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	n't	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	...	...	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	'm	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	telling	tell	VERB	A5.4p	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
12	you	you	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	there	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	was	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	n't	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	...	...	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1159
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1159.s1
# text = We're suspending the full.
1	We	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	're	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	suspending	suspend	VERB	M2	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	full	full	ADJ	N5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1160
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2017-05-24-DSPG030.seg1160.s1
# text = See you tomorrow.
1	See	see	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	tomorrow	tomorrow	NOUN	T1.1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

