# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.1
# text = I welcome you and open the 60th session of the House of Peoples of the Parliamentary Assembly of Bosnia and Herzegovina.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	welcome	welcome	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	open	open	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	60th	100th	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Peoples	people	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Bosnia	Bosnia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	Herzegovina	Herzegovina	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
22	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.2
# text = There are 12 delegates present at today's session, of which 4 are from the Bosniak people, 4 from Croatia and 4 from the Serb people.
1	There	there	PRON	EX	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	are	be	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	12	12	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	delegates	delegate	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	present	present	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	at	at	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	today	today	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	4	4	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	Bosniak	bosniak	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
18	people	people	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	4	4	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	Croatia	Croatia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
23	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	4	4	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	Serb	serb	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
28	people	people	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.3
# text = The delegates Jukić, Šiljegović and Neimarlija justified their absence.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	delegates	delegate	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Jukić	Jukić	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Šiljegović	Šiljegović	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Neimarlija	Neimarlija	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
8	justified	justify	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	their	they	PRON	PRP$	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	absence	absence	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.4
# text = For today's 60th session, I propose the following updated agenda, 1st. Answering Legislative Questions and Delegative Questions, 2. The adoption of the minutes from the 59th session of the dom of narod, 3. Request of the House of Representatives to consider the Law on Amendments and Supplements of the Tax Act on additional value, by emergency procedure in accordance with Article 100.
1	For	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	today	today	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	60th	100th	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	propose	propose	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	updated	update	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	agenda	agenda	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	1st	1st	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Answering	answer	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	Legislative	legislative	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	Delegative	delegative	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
21	Questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	2	2	NUM	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	adoption	adoption	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	minutes	minute	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	59th	59th	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	dom	dom	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	narod	narod	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	3	3	NUM	LS	NumForm=Digit	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	Request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
46	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
47	Representatives	Representative	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
48	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	consider	consider	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
51	Law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
52	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
53	Amendments	amendment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
54	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
55	Supplements	supplement	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
56	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
57	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
58	Tax	tax	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
59	Act	Act	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
60	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
61	additional	additional	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
62	value	value	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
63	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
64	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
65	emergency	emergency	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
66	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
67	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
68	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
69	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
70	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
71	100	100	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
72	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.5
# text = Rules of Procedure of the House of Peoples, 4. Request of the House of Representatives to consider the Law amending the General Law on Cooperatives, by emergency procedure in accordance with Article 100.
1	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	House	house	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Peoples	people	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	4	4	NUM	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	Request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
16	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Representatives	Representative	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	consider	consider	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	amending	amend	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	General	General	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
25	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
26	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
27	Cooperatives	Cooperatives	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	emergency	emergency	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
36	100	100	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
37	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.6
# text = Rules of Procedure of the House of Peoples, 5. The request of the delegate, Boško Šiljegović, to consider the BiH Defence Law proposal following an emergency procedure in accordance with Article 99.
1	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	House	house	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Peoples	people	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	5	5	NUM	LS	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	delegate	delegate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Boško	Boško	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
19	Šiljegović	Šiljegović	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	consider	consider	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
25	Defence	Defence	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
27	proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	emergency	emergency	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
36	99	99	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
37	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.7
# text = Rules of Procedure of the House of Peoples, 6. The request of delegate Halid Genjac to consider the draft law amending and supplementing the Law on the cornerstones of traffic on the roads of BiH, following an urgent procedure in accordance with Article 99.
1	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	House	house	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Peoples	people	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	6	6	NUM	LS	NumForm=Digit	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	delegate	delegate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Halid	Halid	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
17	Genjac	Genjac	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
18	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	consider	consider	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	draft	draft	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	amending	amend	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	supplementing	supplement	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	Law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	cornerstones	cornerstone	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	traffic	traffic	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	roads	road	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
38	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	urgent	urgent	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
47	99	99	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
48	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.8
# text = Rules of Procedure of the House of Peoples, 7. The request of delegates Halid Genjac and Mustafa Pamuk to consider the Amendments and Supplements Act on traffic safety on the roads to BiH, following an urgent procedure in accordance with Article 99.
1	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	House	house	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Peoples	people	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	7	7	NUM	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	delegates	delegate	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Halid	Halid	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
17	Genjac	Genjac	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
18	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	Mustafa	Mustafa	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
20	Pamuk	Pamuk	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
21	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	consider	consider	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	Amendments	amendment	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
25	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
26	Supplements	Supplements	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
27	Act	Act	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
28	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	traffic	traffic	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	safety	safety	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	roads	road	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
36	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	urgent	urgent	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
45	99	99	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
46	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.9
# text = Imprisonment, 8 / 8 The request of the BiH Council of Ministers for consideration of the Bill on Amendments to the Law on Police Officers of BiH, following an urgent procedure in accordance with Article 99.
1	Imprisonment	imprisonment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	8	8	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	/	/	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	8	8	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
11	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	consideration	consideration	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Bill	Bill	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
19	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
20	Amendments	amendment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
21	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	Law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
24	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
25	Police	police	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Officers	officer	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
27	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
28	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
29	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	urgent	urgent	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
38	99	99	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
39	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.10
# text = The Rules of Procedure of the House of Naorda, 9. The request of the BiH Council of Ministers for consideration of the draft law amending and supplementing the Law on BiH Police Officers by emergency procedure in accordance with Article 99.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	Rules	rule	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
4	Procedure	Procedure	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Naorda	Naorda	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	9	9	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
18	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	consideration	consideration	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	draft	draft	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	amending	amend	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	supplementing	supplement	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
32	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
33	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
34	Police	Police	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
35	Officers	officer	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
36	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	emergency	emergency	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
43	99	99	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
44	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.11
# text = Rules of Procedure of the People's House, Law of 29.05.2006, 10.
1	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	People	People	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	29.05.2006	29.05.2006	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	10	10	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.12
# text = The request of the Council of Ministers to consider the Proposal for a Law amending the Law on the BiH State Border Service, following an urgent procedure in accordance with Article 99.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	consider	consider	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	Law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
15	amending	amend	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
17	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
18	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
21	State	State	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Border	Border	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Service	Service	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	urgent	urgent	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
33	99	99	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
34	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.13
# text = Rules of Procedure of the House of Peoples, 11.
1	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Peoples	people	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	11	11	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.14
# text = The request of the BiH Council of Ministers for consideration of the Proposal for a Law on Higher Education of BiH, following an urgent procedure in accordance with Article 99.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	consideration	consideration	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	Proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
17	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Higher	High	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Cmp	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Education	Education	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	urgent	urgent	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
31	99	99	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
32	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.15
# text = Rules of Procedure of the House of Peoples, 2 12.
1	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
6	House	house	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
8	Peoples	people	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	2	2	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	12	12	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.16
# text = Proposal for a law amending and supplementing the Law on the Security and Security Agency of BiH, first reading, 13.
1	Proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	amending	amend	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	supplementing	supplement	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
10	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Security	Security	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Security	Security	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Agency	Agency	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	first	first	ADV	RB	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	reading	reading	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	13	13	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.17
# text = Proposal for a Law on Amendments and Supplements to the Criminal Law of BiH, First Reading, 14.
1	Proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
5	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
6	Amendments	amendment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
7	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
8	Supplements	supplement	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
9	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Criminal	criminal	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
12	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	First	first	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
17	Reading	Reading	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	14	14	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.18
# text = Proposal for a law on classification of activities in BiH, first reading, 15.
1	Proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	classification	classification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	activities	activity	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	first	first	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	reading	reading	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	15	15	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.19
# text = Information on work in the BiH Prosecutor's Office for 2005, 16.
1	Information	information	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	work	work	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
7	Prosecutor	Prosecutor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
8	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Office	Office	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	2005	2005	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	16	16	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.20
# text = The conclusions of the Commission on Foreign Trade Policy of the People's House on problems with milk exports to countries with which BiH has signed bilateral free trade agreements, 17.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	conclusions	conclusion	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Commission	Commission	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
6	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Foreign	foreign	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Trade	Trade	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Policy	Policy	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	People	People	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
13	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	problems	problem	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	milk	milk	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	exports	export	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	countries	country	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
25	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	signed	sign	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	bilateral	bilateral	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	free	free	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	trade	trade	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	agreements	agreement	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	17	17	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.21
# text = The conclusions and recommendations of the Commission for Foreign and Trade Policy of the People's House on the public debate on the topic of discussing activities to promote economic growth, increase exports, reduce trade deficits and provide additional benefits for foreign investment in BiH, 18.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	conclusions	conclusion	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	recommendations	recommendation	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Commission	Commission	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
8	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Foreign	foreign	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Trade	Trade	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Policy	Policy	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	People	People	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
16	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	public	public	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	debate	debate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	topic	topic	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	of	of	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	discussing	discuss	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	activities	activity	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	promote	promote	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	economic	economic	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	growth	growth	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	increase	increase	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	exports	export	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	reduce	reduce	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	trade	trade	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	deficits	deficit	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	provide	provide	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	additional	additional	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	benefits	benefit	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	foreign	foreign	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	investment	investment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
48	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	18	18	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
50	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.22
# text = Considering the resignations of Jasminka Putica, Blage Bošnjak and Dragica Miletić members of the Office to discuss complaints and learn about the information about the activities so far related to the beginning of the Office's work to consider complaints, 19.
1	Considering	consider	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	resignations	resignation	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Jasminka	Jasminka	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Putica	Putica	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Blage	Blage	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
9	Bošnjak	Bošnjak	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Dragica	Dragica	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
12	Miletić	Miletić	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	members	member	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Office	Office	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
17	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	discuss	discuss	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	complaints	complaint	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	learn	learn	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	about	about	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	information	information	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	about	about	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	activities	activity	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	so	so	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	far	far	ADV	RB	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	related	related	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	beginning	beginning	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	Office	Office	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
37	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	work	work	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	consider	consider	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	complaints	complaint	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	19	19	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
44	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.23
# text = Giving consent to ratifying the Agreement between the Government of BiH and the Government of the Federal Republic of Germany on Financial Co-operation in 2004, 20.
1	Giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	ratifying	ratify	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Agreement	agreement	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	between	between	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	Government	Government	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
10	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
11	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	Government	Government	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
15	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Federal	Federal	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Republic	Republic	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Germany	Germany	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	Financial	Financial	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
23	Co-operation	Co-operation	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
24	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	2004	2004	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	20	20	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.24
# text = Giving consent to the ratification of the Agreement between the Council of Ministers of BiH and the Government of the Republic of Greece on co-operation in the fight against crime, in particular terrorism, illegal drug trafficking and arms and organised crime, 21.
1	Giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	ratification	ratification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Agreement	agreement	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	between	between	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Government	Government	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
19	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Republic	Republic	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Greece	Greece	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
24	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	co-operation	co-operation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	fight	fight	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	against	against	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	crime	crime	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	particular	particular	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	terrorism	terrorism	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	illegal	illegal	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	drug	drug	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	trafficking	trafficking	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	arms	arm	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	organised	organised	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	crime	crime	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
44	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	21	21	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
46	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.25
# text = Giving consent to the ratification of the BiH Agreement with the Belgian-Luxemburg Economic Union on reciprocal improvement and protection of investments, 22.
1	Giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	ratification	ratification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
9	Agreement	agreement	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
10	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	Belgian	Belgian	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
13	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	Luxemburg	Luxemburg	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
15	Economic	economic	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Union	Union	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	reciprocal	reciprocal	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	improvement	improvement	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	protection	protection	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	investments	investment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	22	22	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.26
# text = Giving consent to the ratification of the Agreement between the Council of Ministers of BiH and the Government of the Republic of Greece on the readmission of persons who are illegally staying in the territory of their countries and the protocol for the approval of the Agreement between the Council of Ministers of BiH and the Government of the Republic of Greece on the readmission of persons who are illegally staying in the territory of their countries, 23.
1	Giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	ratification	ratification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Agreement	agreement	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	between	between	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Government	Government	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
19	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Republic	Republic	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Greece	Greece	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
24	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	readmission	readmission	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	persons	person	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	who	who	PRON	WP	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	illegally	illegally	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	staying	stay	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	territory	territory	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	their	they	PRON	PRP$	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	countries	country	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	protocol	protocol	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	approval	approval	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	Agreement	agreement	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	between	between	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
51	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
52	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
53	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
54	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
55	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
56	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
57	Government	Government	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
58	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
59	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
60	Republic	Republic	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
61	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
62	Greece	Greece	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
63	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
64	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
65	readmission	readmission	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
66	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
67	persons	person	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
68	who	who	PRON	WP	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
69	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
70	illegally	illegally	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
71	staying	stay	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
72	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
73	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
74	territory	territory	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
75	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
76	their	they	PRON	PRP$	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
77	countries	country	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
78	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
79	23	23	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
80	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.27
# text = Giving consent to ratification of the Air Traffic Agreement between the Council of Ministers of BiH and the Government of the Republic of Hungary, 24.
1	Giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	ratification	ratification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Air	Air	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
8	Traffic	Traffic	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
9	Agreement	agreement	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
10	between	between	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
13	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	Government	Government	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
20	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Republic	Republic	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
24	Hungary	Hungary	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
25	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	24	24	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.28
# text = Giving consent to the ratification of an addendum that amends and complements the Agreement between the High Representative for BiH and BiH on the establishment of the Office of the Register for War Crimes and the II Department for Organized Crime, Economic Crime and Corruption of the Kyrvic and Appeals Department of the Court of BiH and the Special Department for War Crimes and the Special Department for Organized Crime, Business Crime and Corruption of the Prosecutor's Office of BiH, 25.
1	Giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	ratification	ratification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	addendum	addendum	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	that	that	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	amends	amend	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	complements	complement	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	Agreement	agreement	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	between	between	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	High	high	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
18	Representative	Representative	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	establishment	establishment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	Office	Office	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
29	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
30	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Register	Register	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
32	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
33	War	War	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
34	Crimes	Crimes	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
35	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
36	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
37	II	ii	NUM	CD	NumForm=Roman|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
38	Department	Department	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
39	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
40	Organized	organized	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
41	Crime	crime	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
42	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
43	Economic	economic	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
44	Crime	crime	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
45	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
46	Corruption	Corruption	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
47	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
48	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
49	Kyrvic	Kyrvic	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
50	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
51	Appeals	appeal	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
52	Department	Department	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
53	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
54	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
55	Court	Court	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
56	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
57	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
58	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
59	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
60	Special	special	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
61	Department	Department	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
62	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
63	War	War	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
64	Crimes	Crimes	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
65	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
66	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
67	Special	special	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
68	Department	Department	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
69	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
70	Organized	organized	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
71	Crime	crime	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
72	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
73	Business	Business	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
74	Crime	crime	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
75	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
76	Corruption	Corruption	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
77	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
78	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
79	Prosecutor	Prosecutor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
80	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
81	Office	Office	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
82	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
83	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
84	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
85	25	25	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
86	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.29
# text = Giving consent to ratification of the Intellectual Property Treaty for the Integrated Car of Washington on 25 May of '89, 26.
1	Giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	ratification	ratification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Intellectual	intellectual	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
8	Property	Property	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
9	Treaty	Treaty	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
10	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	Integrated	integrate	VERB	NNP	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
13	Car	car	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
14	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
15	Washington	Washington	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
16	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	25	25	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	May	May	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	'	'	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	89	89	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	26	26	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.30
# text = Giving consent to ratification of the Treaty establishing the Energy Community, 27.
1	Giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	ratification	ratification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Treaty	Treaty	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
8	establishing	establish	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Energy	Energy	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
11	Community	Community	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	27	27	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.31
# text = Giving consent to the ratification of the Rotterdam Convention on the notification procedure for the transport of certain dangerous chemicals and pesticides in international trade, 28.
1	Giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	ratification	ratification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Rotterdam	Rotterdam	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
9	Convention	Convention	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
10	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	notification	notification	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	transport	transport	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	certain	certain	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	dangerous	dangerous	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	chemicals	chemical	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	pesticides	pesticide	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	international	international	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	trade	trade	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	28	28	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.32
# text = A request from the BiH Council of Ministers for consideration of the Proposal for a Law on Medicinal Products and Medical Devices of BiH, following an urgent procedure in accordance with Article 99.
1	A	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	consideration	consideration	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	Proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
17	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Medicinal	Medicinal	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Products	product	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Medical	Medical	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Devices	device	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
24	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
25	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	urgent	urgent	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
34	99	99	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
35	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.33
# text = Rules of Procedure of the House of Peoples, 29.
1	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Peoples	people	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	29	29	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.34
# text = The request of the Council of Ministers for the Review of the Proposal for a Law on the Completion of the Law on Citizenship of BiH, following an urgent procedure in accordance with Article 99.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	request	request	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Review	Review	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Proposal	proposal	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	Completion	Completion	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
20	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
24	Citizenship	Citizenship	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
25	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
26	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	urgent	urgent	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
36	99	99	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
37	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.35
# text = Rules of Procedure of the House of Nations, 3.30.
1	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
6	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
8	Nations	Nation	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	3.30	3.30	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.36
# text = Proposal for a law amending the Law on the admission of cases by the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia to the Prosecutor's Office of BiH, and the use of evidence obtained by the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia in proceedings before the courts in BiH, first reading.
1	Proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	amending	amend	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Law	Law	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	admission	admission	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	cases	case	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	International	International	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
16	Criminal	criminal	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Tribunal	Tribunal	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	former	former	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	Yugoslavia	Yugoslavia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
22	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	Prosecutor	Prosecutor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
25	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Office	Office	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
27	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
28	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
29	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	use	use	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	evidence	evidence	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	obtained	obtain	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	International	International	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
39	Criminal	criminal	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
40	Tribunal	Tribunal	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
41	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	former	former	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	Yugoslavia	Yugoslavia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
45	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	proceedings	proceedings	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	before	before	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	courts	court	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
51	BiH	BiH	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
52	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
53	first	first	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
54	reading	reading	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
55	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.37
# text = I'm opening a debate on the agenda proposal.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	'm	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	opening	open	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	debate	debate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	agenda	agenda	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.38
# text = Is anyone picking up?
1	Is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	anyone	anyone	PRON	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	picking	pick	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	up	up	ADP	RP	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	?	?	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.39
# text = Any changes and additions?
1	Any	any	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	changes	change	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	additions	addition	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	?	?	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.40
# text = I find that there are no changes and additions and that the agenda has been adopted.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	find	find	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	there	there	PRON	EX	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	are	be	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	no	no	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	changes	change	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	additions	addition	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	agenda	agenda	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	been	be	AUX	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	adopted	adopt	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.41
# text = It shall not be voted upon in accordance with Article 45.
1	It	it	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	shall	shall	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	voted	vote	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	upon	upon	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
11	45	45	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
12	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.42
# text = The Rules of Procedure of the House of Peoples.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	Rules	rule	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
4	Procedure	Procedure	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Peoples	people	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
10	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg0.43
# text = Moving to the first point of today's agenda, that's Ad.1. Answers to Legislative Questions and Delegative Questions
1	Moving	move	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	first	first	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	point	point	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	today	today	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	agenda	agenda	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	that	that	PRON	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	's	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	Ad.1.	ad.1.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	Answers	answer	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Legislative	legislative	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	Questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	Delegative	delegative	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
20	Questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC

# newpar id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg1.1
# text = Answering the delegate questions for this session, we haven't received any answers.
1	Answering	answer	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	delegate	delegate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	n't	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	received	receive	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	any	any	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	answers	answer	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg1.2
# text = Any new delegate questions?
1	Any	any	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	new	new	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	delegate	delegate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	?	?	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg1.3
# text = So I'm saying we don't have any delegate questions.
1	So	so	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	'm	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	saying	say	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	do	do	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	n't	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	have	have	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	any	any	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	delegate	delegate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6148.seg1.4
# text = And we're going to the second item of the agenda, that's Ad2. The adoption of the minutes from the 59th session of the House of Peoples
1	And	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	're	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	going	go	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	second	second	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	item	item	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	agenda	agenda	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	that	that	PRON	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	's	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	Ad2	Ad2	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
16	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	adoption	adoption	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	minutes	minute	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	59th	59th	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
29	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
30	Peoples	people	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6152
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6152.seg0
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6152.seg0.1
# text = Thank you, Mr. Chairman, honourable MPs, ladies and gentlemen, I would like to convey the official position of the Council of Ministers that the Council of Ministers supports, therefore, the expropriation of Article 82 of the VAT Act and we have submitted amendments in the context of this earlier.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Chairman	Chairman	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	honourable	honourable	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	MPs	mp	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	ladies	lady	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	gentlemen	gentleman	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	would	would	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	like	like	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	convey	convey	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	official	official	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	position	position	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
25	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
27	that	that	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
30	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
32	supports	support	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	therefore	therefore	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	expropriation	expropriation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	Article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
40	82	82	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
41	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	VAT	vat	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
44	Act	Act	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
45	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	submitted	submit	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	amendments	amendment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
51	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
52	context	context	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
53	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
54	this	this	PRON	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
55	earlier	early	ADV	RBR	Degree=Cmp	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
56	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6152.seg0.2
# text = However, the Council of Ministers also wants to inform you that the Council of Ministers is not able to support any amendments to the law that do not have full consent of the Management Board of the Direct Taxation Board, which is in line with the Transfer of Jurisdiction Agreement on which indirect taxation has passed from entity to state level only and which has been verified or ratified by the State Parliament, including the House of Peoples.
1	However	however	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	also	also	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	wants	want	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	inform	inform	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
15	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	able	able	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	support	support	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	any	any	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	amendments	amendment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	that	that	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	do	do	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	have	have	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	full	full	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	Management	Management	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
36	Board	board	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
37	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
38	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
39	Direct	direct	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
40	Taxation	Taxation	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
41	Board	Board	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
42	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	line	line	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	Transfer	transfer	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
50	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
51	Jurisdiction	jurisdiction	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
52	Agreement	agreement	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
53	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
54	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
55	indirect	indirect	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
56	taxation	taxation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
57	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
58	passed	pass	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
59	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
60	entity	entity	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
61	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
62	state	state	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
63	level	level	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
64	only	only	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
65	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
66	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
67	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
68	been	be	AUX	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
69	verified	verify	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
70	or	or	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
71	ratified	ratify	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
72	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
73	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
74	State	State	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
75	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
76	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
77	including	include	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
78	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
79	House	House	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
80	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
81	Peoples	people	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
82	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6152.seg0.3
# text = We've been in touch with Mr. Nikola.
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	've	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	been	be	AUX	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	touch	touch	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Nikola	Nikola	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6152.seg0.4
# text = Mr. nikol expressed his desire to ensure the implementation of the so-called member, these intentions and article 82 either by amending the Regulation that exists under the Direct Taxation Board and Mr. Čaušević is the director here, and by giving consent to this law at the first next session of the Management Board, as he has writtenly informed you.
1	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	nikol	nikol	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	expressed	express	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	his	he	PRON	PRP$	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	desire	desire	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	ensure	ensure	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	implementation	implementation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	so	so	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	called	call	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	member	member	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	these	this	DET	DT	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	intentions	intention	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	article	article	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	82	82	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	either	either	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	by	by	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	amending	amend	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	Regulation	regulation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
27	that	that	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	exists	exist	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	under	under	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	Direct	direct	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
32	Taxation	Taxation	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
33	Board	Board	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
34	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	Čaušević	Čaušević	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	director	director	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	here	here	ADV	RB	PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	by	by	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	giving	give	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	at	at	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
51	first	first	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
52	next	next	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
53	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
54	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
55	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
56	Management	management	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
57	Board	board	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
58	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
59	as	as	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
60	he	he	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
61	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
62	writtenly	writtenly	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
63	informed	inform	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
64	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
65	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6152.seg0.5
# text = Therefore, if we think there is a need to amend this law in this sense, but that we cannot therefore support what does not have the consent of the Management Board because we think that this could lead to a crisis, that the Constitutional Court, or another court, might, on the basis of a breach of the Transfer of Jurisdiction Agreement, possibly bring that amendment down, but we also appeal to this opportunity to the Management Board of indirect taxation to approve this amendment by adding that we have repeatedly asked to do so.
1	Therefore	therefore	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	if	if	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	think	think	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	there	there	PRON	EX	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	is	be	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	need	need	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	amend	amend	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	sense	sense	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	but	but	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	cannot	cannot	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	therefore	therefore	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	support	support	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	what	what	PRON	WP	PronType=Int	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	does	do	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	have	have	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	consent	consent	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	Management	management	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
33	Board	board	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
34	because	because	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	think	think	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	this	this	PRON	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	could	could	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	lead	lead	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	crisis	crisis	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
44	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	Constitutional	constitutional	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
48	Court	Court	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
49	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	or	or	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
51	another	another	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
52	court	court	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
53	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
54	might	might	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
55	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
56	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
57	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
58	basis	basis	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
59	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
60	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
61	breach	breach	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
62	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
63	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
64	Transfer	transfer	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
65	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
66	Jurisdiction	jurisdiction	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
67	Agreement	agreement	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
68	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
69	possibly	possibly	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
70	bring	bring	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
71	that	that	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
72	amendment	amendment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
73	down	down	ADP	RP	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
74	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
75	but	but	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
76	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
77	also	also	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
78	appeal	appeal	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
79	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
80	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
81	opportunity	opportunity	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
82	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
83	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
84	Management	management	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
85	Board	board	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
86	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
87	indirect	indirect	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
88	taxation	taxation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
89	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
90	approve	approve	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
91	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
92	amendment	amendment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
93	by	by	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
94	adding	add	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
95	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
96	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
97	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
98	repeatedly	repeatedly	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
99	asked	ask	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
100	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
101	do	do	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
102	so	so	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
103	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6152.seg0.6
# text = Thank you.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6206
# newpar id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6206.seg0
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6206.seg0.1
# text = Respecting everything that has been said, especially by counterpart Filipović, I will begin with this last sentence said by a representative of the Council of Ministers.
1	Respecting	respect	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	everything	everything	PRON	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	that	that	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	been	be	AUX	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	said	say	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	especially	especially	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	counterpart	counterpart	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Filipović	Filipović	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	begin	begin	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	last	last	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	sentence	sentence	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	said	say	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	representative	representative	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
27	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
28	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
29	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6206.seg0.2
# text = That's the essence of the whole story.
1	That	that	PRON	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	essence	essence	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	whole	whole	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	story	story	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-BA_2006-07-07-0.u6206.seg0.3
# text = So he insists on adopting a law that the gentleman already knows in advance will need to be repaired.
1	So	so	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	he	he	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	insists	insist	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	on	on	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	adopting	adopt	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	law	law	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	that	that	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	gentleman	gentleman	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	already	already	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	knows	know	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	advance	advance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	need	need	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	repaired	repair	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
