# newdoc id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.u1
# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg1.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.670
# text = Ladies and gentlemen, the meeting begins.
1	Ladies	lady	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	gentlemen	gentleman	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	meeting	meeting	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	begins	begin	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg2
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg2.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.207
# text = I have the honour to inform the House of the topical and urgent question issue of Monday 12 June 2017.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	have	have	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	honour	honour	NOUN	G2.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	inform	inform	VERB	X2.2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	House	House	PROPN	H4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	topical	topical	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
12	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	urgent	urgent	ADJ	A11.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
14	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	issue	issue	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Monday	Monday	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	12	12	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
19	June	June	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	2017	2017	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg3
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg3.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.376
# text = A. PERSONS First Circle Questions (Rule 130(2) and (3) of the Rules of Procedure)
1	A.	A.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	PERSONS	PERSONS	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	First	first	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Circle	Circle	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Questions	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
6	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Rule	rule	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	130	130	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	3	3	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Rules	rule	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
19	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
20	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
21	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg4
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg4.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.034
# text = 1. Under number 941/6-2017, a topical question by MP II of the New Democracy, Mr Spyridonos - Adonidos Georgiadis to the Minister of Education, Research and Religious Affairs, on the subject: "The deterioration of Classical Education is taking place in Greece".
1	1.	1.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Under	under	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	941/6-2017	941/6-2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	topical	topical	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
8	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	MP	MP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	II	ii	NUM	Z1	NumForm=Roman|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	New	New	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
15	Democracy	Democracy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Spyridonos	Spyridonos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Adonidos	Adonidos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
21	Georgiadis	Georgiadis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
22	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	Education	Education	PROPN	P1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
28	Research	Research	PROPN	X2.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
29	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	Religious	Religious	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
32	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
35	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
38	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	deterioration	deterioration	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
40	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	Classical	classical	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
42	Education	Education	PROPN	P1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
43	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
44	taking	take	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
45	place	place	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
46	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	Greece	Greece	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
48	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
49	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg5
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg5.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.169
# text = 2. (') OJ No L 2. 2. 1990, p. 2. Mr. Andreas Loverdus, Member of the Council of Ministers of Foreign Affairs, Minister of Foreign Affairs and Human Rights, asked the Minister of Justice, the Minister of Justice, Transparency and Human Rights about the conspiracy of children.
1	2.	2.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	(')	(')	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	OJ	oj	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	No	no	ADV	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	L	L	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	2	2	NUM	T1.3	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	1990	1990	NUM	T1.3	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	p.	P.	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	2	2	NUM	N1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Andreas	Andreas	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
17	Loverdus	Loverdus	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Member	member	NOUN	S5p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	Council	Council	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
23	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
24	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Foreign	foreign	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
27	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Foreign	foreign	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
32	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
33	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
34	Human	human	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
35	Rights	Right	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
36	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	asked	ask	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
40	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
41	Justice	justice	NOUN	G2.1|S2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
42	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
44	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
45	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	Justice	justice	NOUN	G2.1|S2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
47	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
48	Transparency	transparency	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
49	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
50	Human	human	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
51	Rights	rights	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
52	about	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
53	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
54	conspiracy	conspiracy	NOUN	G2.1n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
55	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	children	child	NOUN	S2|T3n	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
57	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg6
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg6.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.138
# text = 3. The current question by No 923/1-6/2017 of the Member of the People's League - Golden Dawn Mr Christos Pappas to the Minister of Education, Research and Religious Affairs, on "fulfilment of the Tomb of the Nation".
1	3	3	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	current	current	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	No	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	923/1-6/2017	923/1-6/2017	NUM	Z99	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
9	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Member	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	People	People	PROPN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
15	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	League	League	PROPN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Golden	Golden	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Dawn	Dawn	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Christos	Christos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
22	Pappas	Pappas	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
23	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Education	Education	PROPN	P1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Research	Research	PROPN	X2.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
31	Religious	Religious	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
32	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
33	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	fulfilment	fulfilment	NOUN	E4.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
37	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	Tomb	Tomb	PROPN	L1n|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
40	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
41	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
42	Nation	Nation	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
43	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
44	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg7
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg7.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.299
# text = 4. The Question No 919/31-5-2017 by the Member of Parliament of the Communist Party of Greece Mr.Ioannis Giokas to the Ministers for Justice, Transparency and Human Rights and Education, Research and Religious Affairs, on the condemnation of disciples of the 1st High School of Rethymnon to "social work", due to their participation in student mobilisations.
1	4.	4.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	No	no	DET	S8n	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	919/31-5-2017	919/31-5-2017	NUM	Z99	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
6	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Member	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
9	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Communist	Communist	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Greece	Greece	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Mr.Ioannis	Mr.Ioannis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
18	Giokas	Giokas	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
22	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Justice	Justice	PROPN	G2.1|S2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	Transparency	Transparency	PROPN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
26	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
27	Human	human	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
28	Rights	Right	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
29	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	Education	Education	PROPN	P1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
32	Research	Research	PROPN	X2.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
33	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
34	Religious	Religious	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
35	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
36	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	condemnation	condemnation	NOUN	Q2.2|E2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
40	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	disciples	disciple	NOUN	P1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
42	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
44	1st	1st	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
45	High	high	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
46	School	School	PROPN	P1|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
47	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
48	Rethymnon	Rethymnon	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
49	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
50	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
51	social	social	ADJ	S1.1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
52	work	work	NOUN	S1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
53	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
54	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
55	due	due	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	to	to	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
57	their	they	PRON	Z8	Number=Plur|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
58	participation	participation	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
59	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
60	student	student	NOUN	P1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
61	mobilisations	mobilisation	NOUN	A1.5.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
62	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg8
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg8.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.309
# text = 5. The question by No 929/2-6-2017 of the Member of Parliament, Mr Dimitrios Kammenos, about the theft of electricity.
1	5	5	NUM	N1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	No	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	929/2-6-2017	929/2-6-2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Member	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
11	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Dimitrios	Dimitrios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
16	Kammenos	Kammenos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	about	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
20	theft	theft	NOUN	G2.1n|A9p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	electricity	electricity	NOUN	O3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg9
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg9.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 1.915
# text = 6. The question raised by Mr Georgios Amyras at number 931/2-6-2017, concerning the 'SIEMENS' case.
1	6	6	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	raised	raise	VERB	M2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
6	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Georgios	Georgios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
9	Amyras	Amyras	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
10	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	931/2-6-2017	931/2-6-2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	concerning	concern	VERB	E6n	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	SIEMENS	SiemenS	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
18	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	case	case	NOUN	A4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg10
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg10.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.395
# text = B. PERSONS Second Cycle Questions (Rule 130(2) and (3) of the Rules of Procedure)
1	B.	B.	X	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	PERSONS	person	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Second	second	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Cycle	cycle	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Questions	question	NOUN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
6	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	Rule	rule	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	130	130	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	3	3	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Rules	rule	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
19	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
20	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
21	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg11
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg11.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.202
# text = 1. Under number 942-6-2017, a topical question by MP Magnesia of New Democracy, Christou Boukorou, to the Minister of Health, on the subject: "The situation in the Second Pathological Clinic Volos".
1	1.	1.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Under	under	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	942-6-2017	942-6-2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	topical	topical	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
8	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	MP	MP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
11	Magnesia	Magnesia	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	New	New	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Democracy	Democracy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Christou	Christou	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
17	Boukorou	Boukorou	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
22	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Health	Health	PROPN	B2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
31	situation	situation	NOUN	A3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
32	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	Second	second	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
35	Pathological	Pathological	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
36	Clinic	Clinic	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
37	Volos	Volos	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
38	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg12
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg12.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 1.945
# text = 2. (') OJ No L 2. 2. 1990, p. 2. Question No 943/6-6-2017 by MP Larissa of the Democratic Association of PASOK - DIMAR Mr. Konstantinos Bargiotas to the Minister of Health, on 'Is there finally a national and regional strategy for the development of medical tourism'?
1	2.	2.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	(')	(')	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	OJ	oj	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	No	no	ADV	Z1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	L	L	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	2	2	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	2	2	NUM	T1.3	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	1990	1990	NUM	T1.3	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	p.	P.	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	2	2	NUM	N1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	No	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	943/6-6-2017	943/6-6-2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
18	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	MP	MP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
20	Larissa	Larissa	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
21	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Democratic	Democratic	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
24	Association	Association	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
26	PASOK	PASOK	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
27	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	DIMAR	DIMAR	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
29	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	Konstantinos	Konstantinos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
31	Bargiotas	Bargiotas	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
32	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
35	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
36	Health	Health	PROPN	B2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
37	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
39	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
40	Is	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
41	there	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	finally	finally	ADV	N4	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
44	national	national	ADJ	M7|N5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
45	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	regional	regional	ADJ	M7	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
47	strategy	strategy	NOUN	X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
48	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
49	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
50	development	development	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
51	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
52	medical	medical	ADJ	B3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
53	tourism	tourism	NOUN	M1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
54	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
55	?	?	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg13
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg13.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.065
# text = 3. The question by number 924/1-6/2017 of MP II Athens of the People's Association - Golden Dawn Mr Helen Zaroulia to the Minister of Finance regarding the appointment of a judge to the administration of the Supreme Court.
1	3	3	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	924/1-6/2017	924/1-6/2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	MP	MP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
10	II	ii	NUM	Z1	NumForm=Roman|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	Athens	Athens	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	People	People	PROPN	S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
15	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Association	Association	PROPN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Golden	Golden	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Dawn	Dawn	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Helen	Helen	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
22	Zaroulia	Zaroulia	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
23	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Finance	Finance	PROPN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
28	regarding	regard	VERB	X2.1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	appointment	appointment	NOUN	T1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
31	of	of	ADP	N6p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	a	a	DET	N6p	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
33	judge	judge	NOUN	N6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
34	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
36	administration	administration	NOUN	S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
37	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	Supreme	Supreme	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
40	Court	Court	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
41	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg14
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg14.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.023
# text = 4. The question by No 948/6-2017 of the Greek Communist Party MEP, Athanasios Vardalis, about the Greek Vehicle Industry "ELVO ABE".
1	4	4	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	No	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	948/6-2017	948/6-2017	NUM	Z99	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Greek	Greek	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
11	Communist	Communist	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	MEP	MEP	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Athanasios	Athanasios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
16	Vardalis	Vardalis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	about	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Greek	Greek	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
21	Vehicle	Vehicle	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Industry	Industry	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	ELVO	ELVO	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
25	ABE	ABE	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
26	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg15
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg15.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.063
# text = 5. Under number 947-6-2017, a topical question by MP I Thessaloniki of the Communist Party of Greece Mr.Ioannis Delis to the Minister of Education, Research and Religious Affairs, on the subject: "to reopen the Integrated Personal Management System for Personnel Management and B/Training (OPSYD) for those who did not have the time to do so".
1	5.	5.	X	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Under	under	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	947-6-2017	947-6-2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	topical	topical	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
8	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	MP	MP	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
11	I	I	PROPN	Z8	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Thessaloniki	Thessaloniki	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Communist	Communist	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
16	Party	Party	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Greece	Greece	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Mr.Ioannis	Mr.Ioannis	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Delis	Delis	PROPN	Z99	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
24	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
25	Education	Education	PROPN	P1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
27	Research	Research	PROPN	X2.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
28	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Religious	Religious	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	reopen	reopen	VERB	A10p|N6p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
39	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
40	Integrated	integrate	VERB	Z1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
41	Personal	personal	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
42	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
43	System	System	PROPN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
44	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
45	Personnel	Personnel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
46	Management	Management	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
47	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
48	B	B	PROPN	Z5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
49	/	/	PUNCT	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
50	Training	Training	PROPN	P1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
51	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
52	OPSYD	OPSYD	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
53	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
54	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
55	those	that	PRON	Z5	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
56	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
57	did	do	AUX	A1.1.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
58	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
59	have	have	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
60	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
61	time	time	NOUN	T1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
62	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
63	do	do	VERB	S1.1.3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
64	so	so	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
65	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
66	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg16
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg16.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.614
# text = REFERENCES - QUESTIONS (Rule 130(5) of the Rules of Procedure)
1	REFERENCES	reference	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	QUESTIONS	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
4	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	Rule	rule	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	130	130	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	5	5	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	Rules	rule	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
13	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
14	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
15	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg17
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg17.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.073
# text = 1. The question asked by MP Rodopi of the Democratic Incorporation of PASOK - DIMAR Mr. Ahmet Ilhan to the Minister of Education, Research and Religious Affairs about the preservation of the 'dyspherics' category of secondary school units of Sapphire and Iasmos Rodopi.
1	1	1	NUM	Z99	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	asked	ask	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
6	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	MP	MP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	Rodopi	Rodopi	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
9	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Democratic	Democratic	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
12	Incorporation	Incorporation	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	PASOK	PASOK	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
15	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	DIMAR	DIMAR	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
17	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Ahmet	Ahmet	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
19	Ilhan	Ilhan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
20	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	Education	Education	PROPN	P1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
25	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
26	Research	Research	PROPN	X2.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
27	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
28	Religious	Religious	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Affairs	affair	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	about	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
32	preservation	preservation	NOUN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
35	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	dyspherics	dyspherics	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	category	category	NOUN	A4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
39	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	secondary	secondary	ADJ	P1|H1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
41	school	school	NOUN	P1|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
42	units	unit	NOUN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
43	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	Sapphire	Sapphire	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
45	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	Iasmos	Iasmo	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
47	Rodopi	Rodopi	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
48	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg18
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg18.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.210
# text = Ladies and gentlemen, we are entering the debate on QUESTIONS
1	Ladies	lady	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	gentlemen	gentleman	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
6	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
7	entering	enter	VERB	M1	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	debate	debate	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	QUESTIONS	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg19
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg19.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.270
# text = Before we begin the debate on the topical and urgent questions, which is three for today, I am aware that the fourth question under number 925/1-6/2017 of the first cycle of the Evian MP of the People's League - Golden Dawn Mr.Nikolaos Michou to the Minister for the Environment and Energy, on the subject: "The installation of 209 new wind turbines in southern Karyesia threatens biodiversity and economy", will not be debated as a result of an impediment by the relevant Minister and will be redefined for discussion.
1	Before	before	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	begin	begin	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	debate	debate	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	topical	topical	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
9	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	urgent	urgent	ADJ	A11.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
11	questions	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
14	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
15	three	three	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
16	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	today	today	NOUN	T1.1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
20	am	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
21	aware	aware	ADJ	X2.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
22	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	fourth	fourth	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
25	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	under	under	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
28	925/1-6/2017	925/1-6/2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
29	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
31	first	first	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
32	cycle	cycle	NOUN	M3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
35	Evian	Evian	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
36	MP	MP	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
37	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	People	People	PROPN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
40	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
41	League	League	PROPN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
42	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	Golden	Golden	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
44	Dawn	Dawn	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
45	Mr.Nikolaos	Mr.Nikolaos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
46	Michou	Michou	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
47	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
49	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
50	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
51	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
52	Environment	environment	PROPN	W5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
53	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
54	Energy	Energy	PROPN	X5.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
55	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
57	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
58	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
59	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
60	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
61	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
62	installation	installation	NOUN	A1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
63	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
64	209	209	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
65	new	new	ADJ	N1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
66	wind	wind	NOUN	W4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
67	turbines	turbine	NOUN	O2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
68	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
69	southern	southern	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
70	Karyesia	Karyesia	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
71	threatens	threaten	VERB	E3n|Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
72	biodiversity	biodiversity	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
73	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
74	economy	economy	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
75	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
76	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
77	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
78	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
79	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
80	debated	debate	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
81	as	as	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
82	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
83	result	result	NOUN	A2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
84	of	of	ADP	N6p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
85	an	a	DET	N6p	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
86	impediment	impediment	NOUN	N6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
87	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
88	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
89	relevant	relevant	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
90	Minister	minister	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
91	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
92	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
93	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
94	redefined	redefine	VERB	A2.1p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
95	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
96	discussion	discussion	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
97	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg20
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg20.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.260
# text = Also, the first question under number 936-6-2017, first question by the Member of the Dodecanese coalition of the Radical Left, Elias Kamaterou to the Minister for the Environment and Energy, on "Spatial Travel Tourism" will not be discussed due to the absence of the Minister responsible abroad.
1	Also	also	ADV	N5p	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	first	first	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
5	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	under	under	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	936-6-	936-6-	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	2017	2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	first	first	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
12	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Member	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
16	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Dodecanese	Dodecanese	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	coalition	coalition	NOUN	S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	Radical	Radical	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
23	Left	Left	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Elias	Elias	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
26	Kamaterou	Kamaterou	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
27	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
32	Environment	environment	PROPN	W5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
33	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
34	Energy	Energy	PROPN	X5.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
38	Spatial	Spatial	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
39	Travel	Travel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
40	Tourism	Tourism	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
41	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
43	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
45	discussed	discuss	VERB	Q2.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
46	due	due	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	to	to	ADP	A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
49	absence	absence	NOUN	S1.1.3n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
50	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
51	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
52	Minister	minister	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
53	responsible	responsible	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
54	abroad	abroad	ADV	M7	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
55	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg20.2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.499
# text = It's Mr. Stathakis, who's missing in Kazakhstan.
1	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Stathakis	Stathakis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	's	be	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	missing	miss	VERB	A5.3n	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
9	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Kazakhstan	Kazakhstan	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg21
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg21.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 1.690
# text = The same applies to the second, with number 940/6-2017, a top-stage question by MP Florina of New Democracy Mr.Ioannis Antoniadis, to the Minister for the Environment and Energy, on the subject: "The significant delays in the relocation of the settlement of Anthrais N. Florinas puts the life of its residents at risk".
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	same	same	ADJ	A6.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	applies	apply	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	second	second	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	940/6-2017	940/6-2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
13	top-	top-	ADJ	Z99	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	stage	stage	NOUN	T1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	MP	MP	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
18	Florina	Florina	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	New	New	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Democracy	Democracy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Mr.Ioannis	Mr.Ioannis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Antoniadis	Antoniadis	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
28	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
30	Environment	environment	PROPN	W5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
31	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
32	Energy	Energy	PROPN	X5.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
33	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
36	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
40	significant	significant	ADJ	A11.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
41	delays	delay	NOUN	T4n	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
42	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
43	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
44	relocation	relocation	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
45	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
47	settlement	settlement	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
48	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
49	Anthrais	Anthrais	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
50	N.	N.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
51	Florinas	Florinas	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
52	puts	put	VERB	M2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
53	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
54	life	life	NOUN	L1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
55	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	its	its	PRON	Z8	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
57	residents	resident	NOUN	H4|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
58	at	at	ADP	A15n	_	0	_	_	NER=O
59	risk	risk	NOUN	A15n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
60	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
61	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg22
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg22.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.667
# text = As you have heard, there is a letter from the Secretary of Government, Mr Michael Kalogerou.
1	As	as	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	heard	hear	VERB	X3.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	there	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	is	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	letter	letter	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	Secretary	Secretary	PROPN	I3.2|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
13	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Government	Government	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Michael	Michael	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
18	Kalogerou	Kalogerou	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
19	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg23
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg23.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.811
# text = So we begin with our second question, number 971/6-2017, on the need for a second-round question by the Independent MEP, Mr Georgios - Dimitrios Karras, on the need to integrate into the objectives of reducing the problematic debts of small business.
1	So	so	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	begin	begin	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	our	we	PRON	Z8	Number=Plur|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
6	second	second	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
7	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	number	number	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	971/6-2017	971/6-2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	need	need	NOUN	S6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
17	second	second	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	round	round	NOUN	N5	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Independent	independent	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
24	MEP	mep	NOUN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
25	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
27	Georgios	Georgios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
28	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Dimitrios	Dimitrios	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
30	Karras	Karras	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
34	need	need	NOUN	S6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
35	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	integrate	integrate	VERB	A1.8p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
37	into	into	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	objectives	objective	NOUN	X7p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
40	of	of	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	reducing	reduce	VERB	N5n|A2.1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
42	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
43	problematic	problematic	ADJ	A12n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
44	debts	debt	NOUN	I1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
45	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	small	small	ADJ	N3.2n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
47	business	business	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
48	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg23.2
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.582
# text = Mr. Papadimitriou is here and he'll answer.
1	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Papadimitriou	Papadimitriou	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
3	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	here	here	ADV	M6	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	he	he	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	'll	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	answer	answer	VERB	Q2.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg24
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg24.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.472
# text = Mr. Carras has the floor.
1	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	Carras	Carras	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
3	has	have	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	floor	floor	NOUN	H2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.u2
# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg25
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg25.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = positive
# senti_n = 5.080
# text = Thank you very much, Mr President, but above all thank the Minister for his presence.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	very	very	ADV	A13.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	much	much	ADV	A13.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	President	President	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	but	but	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	above	above	ADP	A13.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	all	all	DET	A13.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	thank	thank	VERB	S1.2.4p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	his	he	PRON	Z8	Gender=Masc|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
17	presence	presence	NOUN	M6	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg26
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg26.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.424
# text = Nearly two months ago, I submitted a request for documents to be lodged with the Finance and Finance Ministers and requested the information contained in the 2015 Finance Facility Convention in relation to the objectives of reducing the problem loans.
1	Nearly	nearly	ADV	A13.4	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	two	two	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
3	months	month	NOUN	T1.1.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
4	ago	ago	ADV	T1.1.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	submitted	submit	VERB	A9n	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	request	request	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	documents	document	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
12	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
14	lodged	lodge	VERB	H4	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
15	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
17	Finance	Finance	PROPN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
18	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Finance	Finance	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Ministers	Minister	PROPN	Z1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	requested	request	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	information	information	NOUN	X2.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	contained	contain	VERB	A1.8p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
26	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
28	2015	2015	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Finance	Finance	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
30	Facility	facility	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
31	Convention	Convention	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
32	in	in	ADP	A6.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	relation	relation	NOUN	A6.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
34	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
36	objectives	objective	NOUN	X7p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
37	of	of	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	reducing	reduce	VERB	N5n|A2.1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
39	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
40	problem	problem	NOUN	A12n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
41	loans	loan	NOUN	I1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg26.2
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = negative
# senti_n = 0.329
# text = Unfortunately, so far I have not received any response.
1	Unfortunately	unfortunately	ADV	A1.4n	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	so	so	ADV	T1.1.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	far	far	ADV	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
6	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
7	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	received	receive	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
9	any	any	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	response	response	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg26.3
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = negative
# senti_n = 0.346
# text = Oddly from the Ministry of Economy I have received a document from two lines that does not have any competence.
1	Oddly	oddly	ADV	A6.2n	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
5	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Economy	economy	PROPN	I2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
8	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
9	received	receive	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
10	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
11	document	document	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	two	two	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
14	lines	line	NOUN	O4.4	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
15	that	that	PRON	A13.3	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
16	does	do	AUX	A1.1.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
17	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	have	have	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
19	any	any	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	competence	competence	NOUN	X9.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg26.4
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 0.700
# text = It surprises me, but I'm not going to comment on it now.
1	It	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	surprises	surprise	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	me	I	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	but	but	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	'm	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	going	go	VERB	T1.1.3	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
10	to	to	PART	T1.1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	comment	comment	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
12	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Acc|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
14	now	now	ADV	T1.1.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg26.5
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = negative
# senti_n = 0.431
# text = From the Ministry of Finance, no answer was forthcoming, nor did I have the honour to receive.
1	From	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
5	Finance	Finance	PROPN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	no	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	answer	answer	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
10	forthcoming	forthcoming	ADJ	T1.1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	nor	nor	CCONJ	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	did	do	AUX	A1.1.1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
14	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
15	have	have	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
17	honour	honour	NOUN	G2.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
18	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	receive	receive	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg27
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg27.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.367
# text = After that, I noticed that there was a series of publications, Mr President, which referred to the fact that a series of large-scale business loan arrangements existed and the smaller loans were paid out.
1	After	after	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	that	that	PRON	Z5	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
5	noticed	notice	VERB	X3.4p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	there	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	was	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
9	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	series	series	NOUN	N4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
11	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	publications	publication	NOUN	Q4	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	President	President	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
18	referred	refer	VERB	Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
19	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
21	fact	fact	NOUN	A5.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
24	series	series	NOUN	N4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	large	large	ADJ	N3.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	scale	scale	NOUN	N3.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
29	business	business	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	loan	loan	NOUN	Z9	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
31	arrangements	arrangement	NOUN	Z9	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
32	existed	exist	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
33	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
35	smaller	small	ADJ	N3.2n	Degree=Cmp	0	_	_	NER=O
36	loans	loan	NOUN	I1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
37	were	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
38	paid	pay	VERB	I1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
39	out	out	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
40	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg27.2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.091
# text = I have therefore sought evidence from which to see how the situation is eradicated.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	therefore	therefore	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	sought	seek	VERB	X2.4	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
5	evidence	evidence	NOUN	A5.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
8	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	see	see	VERB	X3.4	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
10	how	how	SCONJ	Z5	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	situation	situation	NOUN	A3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
14	eradicated	eradicate	VERB	A1.1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg27.3
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.092
# text = Because it is important and to deal with the problematic loans of small businesses, because these small businesses are a part of the economy and especially with the current Greek economy, where there is complete deindustrialisation and disinvestment, it is necessary to have small businesses.
1	Because	because	SCONJ	Z5|A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	important	important	ADJ	A11.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	deal	deal	VERB	A1.1.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
8	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	problematic	problematic	ADJ	A12n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
11	loans	loan	NOUN	I1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	small	small	ADJ	N3.2n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
14	businesses	business	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	because	because	SCONJ	Z5|A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	these	this	DET	Z5	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
18	small	small	ADJ	N3.2n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
19	businesses	business	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
20	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
21	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	part	part	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
25	economy	economy	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	especially	especially	ADV	A14	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
30	current	current	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Greek	Greek	ADJ	Z2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
32	economy	economy	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	where	where	SCONJ	M6	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
35	there	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	is	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
37	complete	complete	ADJ	N5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
38	deindustrialisation	deindustrialisation	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
39	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	disinvestment	disinvestment	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
43	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
44	necessary	necessary	ADJ	S6p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
45	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	have	have	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
47	small	small	ADJ	N3.2n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
48	businesses	business	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
49	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg28
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg28.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = negative
# senti_n = 0.454
# text = I have therefore seen that there is no provision for quantifying the forecasts available in relation to the annual quarterly or six-monthly reduction in problem loans, so that we know what goes on to be deleted into small enterprises and what goes on to the large ones.
1	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	therefore	therefore	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	seen	see	VERB	X3.4	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
5	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	there	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	is	be	VERB	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	no	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	provision	provision	NOUN	A9n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	for	for	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	quantifying	quantify	VERB	N3.1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
13	forecasts	forecast	NOUN	Q2.2|T1.1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
14	available	available	ADJ	A3p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
15	in	in	ADP	A6.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	relation	relation	NOUN	A6.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
19	annual	annual	ADJ	N6p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
20	quarterly	quarterly	ADJ	N6	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
21	or	or	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	six	six	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	monthly	monthly	ADJ	N6p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
25	reduction	reduction	NOUN	N5n|A2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	problem	problem	NOUN	A12n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
28	loans	loan	NOUN	I1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	so	so	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
33	know	know	VERB	A5.4p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
34	what	what	PRON	A5.4p	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
35	goes	go	VERB	M1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
36	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
39	deleted	delete	VERB	Q1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
40	into	into	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	small	small	ADJ	N3.2n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
42	enterprises	enterprise	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
43	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	what	what	PRON	Z8	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
45	goes	go	VERB	M1	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
46	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
49	large	large	ADJ	N3.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
50	ones	one	NOUN	Z8	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
51	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg29
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg29.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.115
# text = And it is worth noting, Mr President, for this reason: the Greek State has committed itself to the banks, essentially those which they will write off, because it is offset by the income tax, the so-called deferred tax obligation, the bank losses forecasts.
1	And	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	worth	worth	ADJ	I1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	noting	note	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	President	President	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
10	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
12	reason	reason	NOUN	A2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Greek	Greek	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-LOC
16	State	State	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-LOC
17	has	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
18	committed	commit	VERB	A5.4p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
19	itself	itself	PRON	A5.4p	Case=Acc|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs|Reflex=Yes	0	_	_	NER=O
20	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	banks	bank	NOUN	I1|H1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	essentially	essentially	ADV	S6p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	those	that	PRON	Z5	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
26	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
27	they	they	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
28	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
29	write	write	VERB	Q1.2	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
30	off	off	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	because	because	SCONJ	Z5|A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
34	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
35	offset	offset	VERB	A6.1n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
36	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
38	income	income	NOUN	G1.1|I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
39	tax	tax	NOUN	G1.1|I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
40	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
42	so	so	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
43	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
44	called	call	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
45	deferred	defer	VERB	T1.1.3	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
46	tax	tax	NOUN	I1.1|G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
47	obligation	obligation	NOUN	S6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
48	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
49	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
50	bank	bank	NOUN	I1|H1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
51	losses	loss	NOUN	I1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
52	forecasts	forecast	NOUN	Q2.2|T1.1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
53	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg30
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg30.1
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 0.722
# text = I think, therefore, that this issue should also be addressed to the Minister if the government takes into account that many applications from small businesses are not met by the banks, while large companies are being met with huge write-offs - I do not want to mention in particular - and if the government intends to take such measures, because, as I said, Mr President, it is possible because it outweighs the losses of banks with deferred tax.
1	I	I	PRON	Z4	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
2	think	think	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	therefore	therefore	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
8	issue	issue	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	should	should	AUX	S6p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
10	also	also	ADV	N5p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
12	addressed	address	VERB	Q1.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
13	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Minister	minister	NOUN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	if	if	SCONJ	Z7	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	government	government	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	takes	take	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
20	into	into	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	account	account	NOUN	I1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
22	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	many	many	ADJ	N5p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
24	applications	application	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
25	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	small	small	ADJ	N3.2n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
27	businesses	business	NOUN	I2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
28	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
29	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	met	meet	VERB	S3.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
31	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
33	banks	bank	NOUN	I1|H1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
34	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	while	while	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	large	large	ADJ	N3.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
37	companies	company	NOUN	I2.1|S5p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
38	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
39	being	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
40	met	meet	VERB	S3.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
41	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
42	huge	huge	ADJ	N3.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
43	write	write	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
44	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
45	offs	off	NOUN	M6	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
46	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
48	do	do	AUX	S1.1.3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
49	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
50	want	want	VERB	X7p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
51	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
52	mention	mention	VERB	Q2.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
53	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
54	particular	particular	ADJ	A4.2p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
55	-	-	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
57	if	if	SCONJ	Z7	_	0	_	_	NER=O
58	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
59	government	government	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
60	intends	intend	VERB	X7p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
61	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
62	take	take	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
63	such	such	ADJ	Z5	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
64	measures	measure	NOUN	N3.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
65	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
66	because	because	SCONJ	Z5|A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
67	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
68	as	as	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
69	I	I	PRON	Z4	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
70	said	say	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
71	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
72	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
73	President	President	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
74	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
75	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
76	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
77	possible	possible	ADJ	A7p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
78	because	because	SCONJ	Z5|A2.2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
79	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
80	outweighs	outweigh	VERB	A11.1p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
81	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
82	losses	loss	NOUN	I1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
83	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
84	banks	bank	NOUN	I1|H1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
85	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
86	deferred	defer	VERB	T1.1.3	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
87	tax	tax	NOUN	I1.1|G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
88	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg30.2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.441
# text = The state is therefore one of the three pillars that will regulate these issues.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	state	state	NOUN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	therefore	therefore	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	one	one	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	three	three	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
9	pillars	pillar	NOUN	H2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
10	that	that	PRON	A13.3	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
11	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
12	regulate	regulate	VERB	A1.7p|G1.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
13	these	this	DET	Z5	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
14	issues	issue	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg31
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg31.1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = positive
# senti_n = 4.637
# text = Thank you.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	Z4	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z4	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.u510
# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg1723
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg1723.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.325
# text = The minutes of Thursday 6 April 2017, Friday 7 April 2017, the Great Monday 10 April 2017 and the Great Tuesday 11 April 2017 were validated.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	minutes	minute	NOUN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	Thursday	Thursday	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	6	6	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
6	April	April	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	2017	2017	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Friday	Friday	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	7	7	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
11	April	April	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	2017	2017	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Great	Great	PROPN	T1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Monday	Monday	PROPN	T1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	10	10	NUM	T1.2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
18	April	April	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	2017	2017	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
20	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
22	Great	great	ADJ	T1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Tuesday	Tuesday	PROPN	T1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
24	11	11	NUM	T1.2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
25	April	April	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
26	2017	2017	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
27	were	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
28	validated	validate	VERB	S7.4p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg1724
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg1724.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.447
# text = Ladies and gentlemen, do you accept that we should resolve the meeting here?
1	Ladies	lady	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
2	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	gentlemen	gentleman	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	do	do	AUX	S1.1.3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
7	accept	accept	VERB	A9p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
8	that	that	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
10	should	should	AUX	S6p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	resolve	resolve	VERB	X6p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
13	meeting	meeting	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	here	here	ADV	M6	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	?	?	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.u511
# newpar id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg1725
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GR_2017-06-09-S1-commons.seg1725.1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.646
# text = With the consent of the House at the time of 19.49' the sitting on Monday, June 12, 2017, at 17.00', on the subject of Parliament's work, parliamentary scrutiny: (a) a debate on topical questions, and (b) a debate on the question by No. 26/15-2017 question by the Member of the New Democracy Mr. Konstantinos Achilleas Karamanlis to the Minister of Infrastructure and Transport on the subject: "About the control of the procedure for the collection and reimbursement of sums of SSY, coming from ticketing".
1	With	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
3	consent	consent	NOUN	S7.4p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	House	House	PROPN	H4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	at	at	ADP	T1.1.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	T1.1.1	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	time	time	NOUN	T1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	19.49	19.49	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
14	sitting	sitting	NOUN	M8	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
15	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Monday	Monday	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	June	June	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
19	12	12	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	2017	2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	at	at	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	17.00	17.00	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
25	'	'	PUNCT	N1	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
29	subject	subject	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	work	work	NOUN	I3.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
34	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	parliamentary	parliamentary	ADJ	G1.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
36	scrutiny	scrutiny	NOUN	X2.4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
38	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	a	a	NUM	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
40	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
41	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
42	debate	debate	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
43	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
44	topical	topical	ADJ	T1.1.2	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
45	questions	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
46	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
47	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
49	b	b	NUM	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
50	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
51	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
52	debate	debate	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
53	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
54	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
55	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
56	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
57	No.	no.	NOUN	Z99	Abbr=Yes|Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
58	26/15-2017	26/15-2017	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
59	question	question	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
60	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
61	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
62	Member	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
63	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
64	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
65	New	New	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
66	Democracy	Democracy	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
67	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
68	Konstantinos	Konstantinos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
69	Achilleas	Achilleas	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
70	Karamanlis	Karamanlis	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
71	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
72	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
73	Minister	Minister	PROPN	G1.1|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
74	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
75	Infrastructure	Infrastructure	PROPN	I2.1|S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
76	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
77	Transport	Transport	PROPN	M2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
78	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
79	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
80	subject	subject	NOUN	X4.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
81	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
82	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
83	About	about	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
84	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
85	control	control	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
86	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
87	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
88	procedure	procedure	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
89	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
90	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
91	collection	collection	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
92	and	and	CCONJ	T1.3	_	0	_	_	NER=O
93	reimbursement	reimbursement	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
94	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
95	sums	sum	NOUN	Z2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
96	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
97	SSY	ssy	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
98	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
99	coming	come	VERB	M6	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
100	from	from	ADP	M6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
101	ticketing	ticketing	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
102	"	"	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
103	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

