# newdoc id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.u1
# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg1.1
# text = Dear fellow Members and fellow Members, ladies and gentlemen!
1	Dear	dear	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	fellow	fellow	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Members	member	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	fellow	fellow	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Members	member	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	ladies	lady	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	gentlemen	gentleman	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	!	!	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg2
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg2.1
# text = I begin with the continuation of the 5th meeting of the National Assembly.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	begin	begin	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	continuation	continuation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	5th	5th	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	meeting	meeting	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
13	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg3
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg3.1
# text = I am informed that today's meeting cannot be attended by the following Member and Members: Mag. Jana Jenko, mag. Tanya Zink, mag. Klaudija Markež, Mrs Jelka Godec, Mrs Nada Brinovšek, Mrs Irena Grošelj Kosnik, Mrs Vesna Vervega by 2 p.m., Mr. Marijan Pojbič, Mr. Benedict Kopmajer, Mr. Ivan Hršak from 3 p.m. on, mag. Ange Logar, mag. Marko Pogačnik, Mr Jožef Horvat, Mr Franz Breznik, Mr Marjan Dolinšek, Mr Jože Tanko, Dr Vinko Gorenak and Mag. Branko Grimes.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	am	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	informed	inform	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	today	today	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	meeting	meeting	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	cannot	cannot	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	attended	attend	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	Member	member	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
15	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Members	Member	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
17	:	:	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	Mag.	Magurday	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	Jana	Jana	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
20	Jenko	Jenko	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	mag	mag	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	Tanya	Tanya	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
25	Zink	Zink	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	mag	mag	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	Klaudija	Klaudija	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
30	Markež	Markež	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
31	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	Mrs	Mrs	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	Jelka	Jelka	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
34	Godec	Godec	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	Mrs	Mrs	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	Nada	Nada	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
38	Brinovšek	Brinovšek	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
39	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	Mrs	Mrs	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	Irena	Irena	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
42	Grošelj	Grošelj	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
43	Kosnik	Kosnik	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
44	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	Mrs	Mrs	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	Vesna	Vesna	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
47	Vervega	Vervega	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
48	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	2	2	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	p.m.	p.m.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
51	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
52	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
53	Marijan	Marijan	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
54	Pojbič	Pojbič	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
55	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
56	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
57	Benedict	Benedict	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
58	Kopmajer	Kopmajer	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
59	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
60	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
61	Ivan	Ivan	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
62	Hršak	Hršak	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
63	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
64	3	3	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
65	p.m.	p.m.	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
66	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
67	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
68	mag	mag	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
69	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
70	Ange	Ange	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
71	Logar	Logar	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
72	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
73	mag	mag	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
74	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
75	Marko	Marko	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
76	Pogačnik	Pogačnik	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
77	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
78	Mr	Mr	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
79	Jožef	Jožef	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
80	Horvat	Horvat	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
81	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
82	Mr	Mr	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
83	Franz	Franz	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
84	Breznik	Breznik	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
85	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
86	Mr	Mr	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
87	Marjan	Marjan	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
88	Dolinšek	Dolinšek	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
89	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
90	Mr	Mr	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
91	Jože	Jože	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
92	Tanko	Tanko	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
93	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
94	Dr	Dr	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
95	Vinko	Vinko	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
96	Gorenak	Gorenak	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER
97	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
98	Mag.	Magurday	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
99	Branko	Branko	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
100	Grimes	Grimes	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
101	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg4
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg4.1
# text = I welcome everyone here.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	welcome	welcome	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	everyone	everyone	PRON	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	here	here	ADV	RB	PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg5
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg5.1
# text = We're moving on to 27.
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	're	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	moving	move	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	on	on	ADP	RP	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	27	27	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg5.2
# text = On the day-to-day basis, that is to say the proposal for a decision on amendments and amendments to the decision on the reshaping of the University of Maribor.
1	On	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	day	day	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	day	day	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	basis	basis	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	that	that	PRON	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	is	be	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	say	say	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	decision	decision	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	amendments	amendment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	amendments	amendment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	decision	decision	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	reshaping	reshaping	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	University	University	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
32	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
33	Maribor	Maribor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
34	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg6
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg6.1
# text = The draft decree was tabled by the Government.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	draft	draft	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	decree	decree	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	was	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	tabled	tab	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Government	Government	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg6.2
# text = I give the floor to the representative of the Government, the State Secretary at the Ministry of Education, Science and Sport, Dr Petr Macko, to further explain the motion for a decree.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	give	give	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	floor	floor	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	representative	representative	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Government	Government	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	State	State	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
14	Secretary	Secretary	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	at	at	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
18	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Education	Education	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Science	Science	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
22	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
23	Sport	Sport	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	Dr	Dr	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	Petr	Petr	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
27	Macko	Macko	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	further	further	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	explain	explain	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	motion	motion	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	decree	decree	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.u2
# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg7
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg7.1
# text = Mr President, thank you very much for your words.
1	Mr	Mr	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	President	President	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	thank	thank	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	very	very	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	much	much	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	your	you	PRON	PRP$	Person=2|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	words	word	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg7.2
# text = Dear Members and Members!
1	Dear	dear	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
2	Members	member	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
3	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
4	Members	Member	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
5	!	!	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg8
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg8.1
# text = The proposed decree amending and supplementing the Decree on the Conversion of the University of Maribor changes the seat of the Medical Faculty, which moved to a new building on Taborska ulica 8, Maribor, before Slomškov trg 15.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	proposed	propose	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	decree	decree	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	amending	amend	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	supplementing	supplement	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Decree	Decree	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Conversion	conversion	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	University	University	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	Maribor	Maribor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	changes	change	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	seat	seat	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	Medical	Medical	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
23	Faculty	Faculty	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	moved	move	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	new	new	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	building	building	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	Taborska	Taborska	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
33	ulica	ulica	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	8	8	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	Maribor	Maribor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
37	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	before	before	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	Slomškov	Slomškov	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
40	trg	trg	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	15	15	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg8.2
# text = In addition, the headquarters of the Faculty of Tourism, which changed the title of the seat on the Road of the First Fighters 36 in Brežice, before the Market of Evictions 12, Brežice.
1	In	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	addition	addition	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	headquarters	headquarters	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Faculty	Faculty	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
9	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Tourism	Tourism	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	changed	change	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	title	title	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	seat	seat	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	Road	Road	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
22	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
24	First	first	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
25	Fighters	Fighter	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
26	36	36	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	Brežice	Brežice	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
29	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	before	before	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	Market	Market	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
33	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
34	Evictions	Eviction	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
35	12	12	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
36	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	Brežice	Brežice	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
38	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg8.3
# text = The name of the Faculty of Construction in the Faculty of Construction, Transport Engineering and Architecture is further changed, which describes the field of study and research activities of the Faculty on the proposal of the University of Maribor.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	name	name	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Faculty	Faculty	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
6	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	Construction	Construction	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Faculty	Faculty	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	Construction	Construction	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Transport	Transport	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	Engineering	Engineering	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Architecture	Architecture	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	further	further	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	changed	change	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	describes	describe	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	field	field	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	study	study	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	research	research	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	activities	activity	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	Faculty	Faculty	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	University	University	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
40	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
41	Maribor	Maribor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
42	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg8.4
# text = Finally, in a decree with the Statute of the University of Maribor, a number of areas are aligned with the areas which have been added to the Statute on the basis of the fifth paragraph of Article 6 of the Decree on the Conversion of the University of Maribor.
1	Finally	finally	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	decree	decree	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Statute	Statute	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
9	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
11	University	University	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Maribor	Maribor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	number	number	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	areas	area	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	aligned	align	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	areas	area	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	been	be	AUX	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	added	add	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	Statute	statute	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	basis	basis	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	fifth	fifth	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	paragraph	paragraph	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	Article	article	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	6	6	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	Decree	Decree	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	Conversion	conversion	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
47	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
48	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
49	University	University	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
50	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
51	Maribor	Maribor	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
52	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg8.5
# text = Thank you very much.
1	Thank	thank	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	very	very	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	much	much	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.u160
# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg564
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg564.1
# text = Dear President, all of you, good-bye!
1	Dear	dear	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	President	President	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	all	all	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	good	good	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	bye	bye	INTJ	UH	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	!	!	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg565
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg565.1
# text = In mid-January this year, the members of the Commission of the National Council for the Control of Public Finance, on the basis of the Court of Auditors' audit, found that the country was not effective in drawing on European funds for flood measures.
1	In	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	mid-January	mid-January	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	year	year	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	members	member	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Commission	Commission	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
13	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
14	Council	Council	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
15	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
17	Control	Control	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Public	Public	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Finance	Finance	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	basis	basis	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	Court	Court	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
28	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
29	Auditors	Auditor	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
30	'	'	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	audit	audit	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	found	find	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	country	country	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	was	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	effective	effective	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	in	in	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	drawing	draw	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	on	on	ADP	RP	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	European	European	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
44	funds	fund	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	flood	flood	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	measures	measure	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
48	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg565.2
# text = In principle, the Desus Group agrees with this finding, but flood protection is not the only area where the Republic of Slovenia is unsuccessful in drawing on European funds.
1	In	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	principle	principle	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	Desus	Desus	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
6	Group	Group	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	agrees	agree	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	finding	finding	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	but	but	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	flood	flood	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	protection	protection	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	only	only	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	area	area	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	where	where	SCONJ	WRB	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	Republic	Republic	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
23	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-LOC
24	Slovenia	Slovenia	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-LOC
25	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	unsuccessful	unsuccessful	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	in	in	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	drawing	draw	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	on	on	ADP	RP	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	European	European	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
31	funds	fund	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
32	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg565.3
# text = Despite the efforts of the Environment Ministry, flood protection is still not sufficient.
1	Despite	despite	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	efforts	effort	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Environment	environment	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
7	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	flood	flood	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	protection	protection	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	still	still	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	sufficient	sufficient	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg565.4
# text = We are of the opinion that before today's debate we should wait for the Ministry of Environment and Space's response report, which will give us answers to most of the questions raised by the Commission's conclusion.
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	opinion	opinion	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	before	before	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	today	today	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	debate	debate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	should	should	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	wait	wait	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
17	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
18	Environment	environment	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	Space	Space	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
21	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	response	response	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	report	report	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	give	give	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	us	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	answers	answer	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	most	most	ADJ	JJS	Degree=Sup	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	questions	question	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	raised	raise	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	by	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	Commission	commission	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
39	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	conclusion	conclusion	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
41	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg565.5
# text = We will find out what measures to reduce the flood threat the Ministry has already taken and what further steps it is preparing.
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	find	find	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	out	out	ADP	RP	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	what	what	DET	WDT	PronType=Int	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	measures	measure	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	reduce	reduce	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	flood	flood	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	threat	threat	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
14	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	already	already	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	taken	take	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	what	what	DET	WDT	PronType=Int	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	further	further	ADJ	JJR	Degree=Cmp	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	steps	step	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	it	it	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	is	be	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	preparing	prepare	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg565.6
# text = We will be able to read the measures relating to the preparation of projects for the new 2014-2020 programming period, and medium- and long-term plans for flood safety measures, changes to place more effectively in space and to reorganise the water sector are also being prepared for the ILO.
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	able	able	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	read	read	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	measures	measure	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	relating	relate	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	preparation	preparation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	projects	project	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	new	new	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	2014	2014	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	2020	2020	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	programming	programming	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	period	period	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	medium	medium	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	long	long	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	term	term	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	plans	plan	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	flood	flood	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	safety	safety	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	measures	measure	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
36	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	changes	change	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	place	place	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	more	more	ADV	RBR	Degree=Cmp	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	effectively	effectively	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	space	space	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	reorganise	reorganise	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	water	water	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	sector	sector	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
51	also	also	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
52	being	be	AUX	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
53	prepared	prepare	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
54	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
55	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
56	ILO	ILO	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
57	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg566
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg566.1
# text = The resources available have not always been used sufficiently carefully.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	resources	resource	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	available	available	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	always	always	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	been	be	AUX	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	used	use	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	sufficiently	sufficiently	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	carefully	carefully	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg566.2
# text = Under the Operational Programme on Environment and Transport Infrastructure for the 2007-2013 programming period, €66 million was allocated for the purpose of water regulation.
1	Under	under	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	Operational	operational	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
4	Programme	Programme	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
6	Environment	environment	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
7	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Transport	Transport	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	Infrastructure	Infrastructure	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
10	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	2007	2007	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	2013	2013	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	programming	programming	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	period	period	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	€	€	SYM	$	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	66	66	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	million	million	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	was	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	allocated	allocate	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	purpose	purpose	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	water	water	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	regulation	regulation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg566.3
# text = All funds are distributed and investments are being developed in areas where flood threats are the largest.
1	All	all	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	funds	fund	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	distributed	distribute	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	investments	investment	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	being	be	AUX	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	developed	develop	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	areas	area	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	where	where	SCONJ	WRB	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	flood	flood	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	threats	threat	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	largest	large	ADJ	JJS	Degree=Sup	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg566.4
# text = The Ministry recognises that the implementation of flood safety projects has indeed taken place later than it would have wanted, not in the search for culprits, but in all its efforts to implement projects to ensure that funds are spent in line with the deadlines foreseen.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	recognises	recognise	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	implementation	implementation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	flood	flood	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	safety	safety	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	projects	project	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	indeed	indeed	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	taken	take	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	place	place	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	later	late	ADV	RBR	Degree=Cmp	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	than	than	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	it	it	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	would	would	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	have	have	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	wanted	want	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	search	search	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	culprits	culprit	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
28	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	but	but	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	all	all	DET	PDT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	its	its	PRON	PRP$	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	efforts	effort	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	implement	implement	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	projects	project	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	ensure	ensure	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	funds	fund	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	spent	spend	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	line	line	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	deadlines	deadline	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	foreseen	foreseen	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
49	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg567
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg567.1
# text = In its audit, the Court of Auditors concluded, inter alia, that at the beginning of the previous financial perspective, there was no basis for the preparation of projects and that in the first three years of the perspective the Ministry did nothing on these projects.
1	In	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	its	its	PRON	PRP$	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	audit	audit	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Court	Court	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Auditors	Auditor	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
9	concluded	conclude	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	inter	inter	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	alia	alia	X	FW	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	at	at	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	beginning	beginning	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	previous	previous	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	financial	financial	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	perspective	perspective	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
23	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	there	there	PRON	EX	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	was	be	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	no	no	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	basis	basis	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	preparation	preparation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	projects	project	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	first	first	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	three	three	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	years	year	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	perspective	perspective	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	did	do	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	nothing	nothing	PRON	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	these	this	DET	DT	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	projects	project	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
50	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg567.2
# text = The country has notified three projects for European co-financing with delay, the upgrade of the Beber Water Analysis System and the anti-floating measures in Savinja and Drava.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	country	country	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	has	have	AUX	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	notified	notify	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	three	three	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	projects	project	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	European	European	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
9	co-financing	co-financing	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	delay	delay	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	upgrade	upgrade	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	Beber	Beber	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
18	Water	Water	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Analysis	Analysis	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
20	System	System	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
21	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	anti-floating	anti-floating	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	measures	measure	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	Savinja	Savinja	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC
27	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	Drava	Drava	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
29	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg567.3
# text = By the end of 2013, 22.5% of the available resources had been used for these three projects.
1	By	by	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	end	end	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	2013	2013	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	22.5	22.5	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	%	%	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	available	available	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	resources	resource	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	had	have	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	been	be	AUX	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	used	use	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	these	this	DET	DT	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	three	three	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	projects	project	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg567.4
# text = As we were informed at the meeting of the Commission, they are counting on the Ministry to draw 62 of the €77 million available for these projects.
1	As	as	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	we	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	were	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	informed	inform	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	at	at	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	meeting	meeting	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	Commission	commission	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	they	they	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=3|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	counting	count	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	Ministry	Ministry	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	draw	draw	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	62	62	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	€	€	SYM	$	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
24	77	77	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	million	million	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	available	available	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	these	this	DET	DT	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	projects	project	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
30	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg568
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg568.1
# text = The Court of Auditors also drew attention to the inefficiency of the State in the collection of concession fees and water rights that fill the water fund and in the use of funds for regular activities in flood-prone areas.
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	Court	Court	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
3	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
4	Auditors	Auditor	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
5	also	also	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	drew	draw	VERB	VBD	Mood=Ind|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	attention	attention	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	inefficiency	inefficiency	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	State	State	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	collection	collection	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	concession	concession	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	fees	fee	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	water	water	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	rights	rights	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	that	that	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	fill	fill	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	water	water	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	fund	fund	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	use	use	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	funds	fund	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	regular	regular	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	activities	activity	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	flood	flood	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	-	-	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
40	prone	prone	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	areas	area	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg568.2
# text = We estimate that one of the key reasons for poor flood safety is that water fund resources are not used for the purpose for which the fund was established to build anti-flood infrastructure.
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	estimate	estimate	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	one	one	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	key	key	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	reasons	reason	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	poor	poor	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	flood	flood	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	safety	safety	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	is	be	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	water	water	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	fund	fund	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	resources	resource	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	not	not	PART	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	used	use	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	purpose	purpose	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	fund	fund	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	was	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	established	establish	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	build	build	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	anti-flood	anti-flood	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	infrastructure	infrastructure	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
34	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg568.3
# text = According to the Visionary Act on the terms of the concession for the exploitation of the energy potential of the lower Sava, the bulk of the resources collected from the water fund are intended for the completion of hydroelectric power plants on the lower Sava.
1	According	accord	VERB	VBG	ExtPos=ADP|VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	Visionary	visionary	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
5	Act	Act	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
6	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	terms	term	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	concession	concession	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	exploitation	exploitation	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	energy	energy	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	potential	potential	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	lower	low	ADJ	JJR	Degree=Cmp	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	Sava	Sava	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
23	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	bulk	bulk	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	resources	resource	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	collected	collect	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	water	water	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	fund	fund	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	intended	intend	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	completion	completion	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	hydroelectric	hydroelectric	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	power	power	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	plants	plant	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	lower	low	ADJ	JJR	Degree=Cmp	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	Sava	Sava	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-LOC|SpaceAfter=No
47	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg568.4
# text = Thus, between 2004 and 2014, €294 million was raised in the water fund, with 150 million being diverted to the construction of these projects and 53.5 million unintendedly spent in the past decade.
1	Thus	thus	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	between	between	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	2004	2004	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	2014	2014	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	€294	€294	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	million	million	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	was	be	AUX	VBD	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	raised	raise	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	water	water	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	fund	fund	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	with	with	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	150	150	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	million	million	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	being	be	AUX	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	diverted	divert	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	construction	construction	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	these	this	DET	DT	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	projects	project	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	53.5	53.5	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	million	million	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	unintendedly	unintendedly	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	spent	spend	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	past	past	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	decade	decade	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
37	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg569
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg569.1
# text = Desus fully agrees with the Court of Auditors' conclusions that there will be a need to reform a number of things – I will end with the fact that the Group of Members will vote against most.
1	Desus	Desus	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-PER
2	fully	fully	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	agrees	agree	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	Court	court	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Auditors	Auditor	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	'	'	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	conclusions	conclusion	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	there	there	PRON	EX	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	be	be	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	need	need	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	reform	reform	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	number	number	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	things	thing	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	–	–	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	end	end	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	fact	fact	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	that	that	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	Group	Group	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
33	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
34	Members	Member	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
35	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	vote	vote	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	against	against	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	most	most	ADJ	JJS	Degree=Sup	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
39	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.u161
# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg570
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg570.1
# text = We have concluded by presenting the views of the groups of Members.
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	have	have	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	concluded	conclude	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	by	by	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	presenting	present	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	views	view	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	groups	group	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	Members	Member	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg571
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg571.1
# text = We are moving on to the debate on the decision and the amendment tabled, which will be carried out on the basis of a review of the amendment tabled. 3. This Decision shall enter into force on the twentieth day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.
1	We	we	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	are	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	moving	move	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	on	on	ADP	RP	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	to	to	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	debate	debate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	decision	decision	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	amendment	amendment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	tabled	tab	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	carried	carry	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	out	out	ADP	RP	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
22	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	basis	basis	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	review	review	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
27	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	amendment	amendment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	tabled	tab	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
31	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	3	3	NUM	LS	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	This	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	Decision	decision	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	shall	shall	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	enter	enter	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	into	into	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	force	force	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
40	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
41	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
42	twentieth	twentieth	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
43	day	day	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
44	following	follow	VERB	VBG	VerbForm=Ger	-1	-	_	NER=O
45	that	that	PRON	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
46	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
47	its	its	PRON	PRP$	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
48	publication	publication	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
49	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
50	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
51	Official	official	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
52	Journal	Journal	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
53	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
54	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
55	European	European	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
56	Union	Union	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
57	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg572
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg572.1
# text = I am putting forward a proposal for a decision and an amendment from the SDS Group.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	am	be	AUX	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	putting	put	VERB	VBG	Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Part	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	forward	forward	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	proposal	proposal	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	a	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	decision	decision	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	an	a	DET	DT	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	amendment	amendment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	from	from	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	SDS	SDS	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
16	Group	Group	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
17	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg572.2
# text = Anybody want to talk?
1	Anybody	anybody	PRON	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	want	want	VERB	VB	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	talk	talk	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	?	?	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg572.3
# text = No, no, no.
1	No	no	INTJ	UH	Polarity=Neg	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	no	no	INTJ	UH	Polarity=Neg	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	no	no	INTJ	UH	Polarity=Neg	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg573
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg573.1
# text = Since no one wants to discuss it anymore, I conclude the debate.
1	Since	since	SCONJ	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	no	no	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	one	one	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	wants	want	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	discuss	discuss	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	it	it	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	anymore	anymore	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	conclude	conclude	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	debate	debate	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg573.2
# text = The amendment will be decided on Monday, 9th, in accordance with the timing of the meeting of the National Assembly. 3. 2015, in the context of the votes
1	The	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	amendment	amendment	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	decided	decide	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	Monday	Monday	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
8	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	9th	9th	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	accordance	accordance	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	with	with	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	timing	timing	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	meeting	meeting	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
22	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
23	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	3	3	NUM	LS	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
25	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	2015	2015	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	context	context	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	votes	vote	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg574
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg574.1
# text = This concludes this agenda item.
1	This	this	PRON	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	concludes	conclude	VERB	VBZ	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	this	this	DET	DT	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	agenda	agenda	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	item	item	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg575
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg575.1
# text = Dear citizens, allow me to congratulate you, like Members and Servants of the National Assembly, on the International Women's Day.
1	Dear	dear	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	citizens	citizen	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	allow	allow	VERB	VB	Mood=Imp|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	me	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	congratulate	congratulate	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	you	you	PRON	PRP	Case=Acc|Person=2|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	like	like	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	Members	Member	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	Servants	Servant	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
17	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	International	International	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-MISC
22	Women	woman	PROPN	NNPS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
23	's	's	PART	POS	_	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC
24	Day	Day	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
25	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg575.2
# text = However, I call on citizens, Members and civil servants of the National Assembly to do everything in our country, and therefore also yours, the power for real equality and gender equality everywhere and every day.
1	However	however	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	call	call	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	citizens	citizen	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	Members	member	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
10	civil	civil	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
11	servants	servant	NOUN	NNS	Number=Plur	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
15	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG
16	to	to	PART	TO	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	do	do	VERB	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	everything	everything	PRON	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
19	in	in	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	our	we	PRON	PRP$	Number=Plur|Person=1|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	country	country	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
23	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
24	therefore	therefore	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
25	also	also	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
26	yours	yours	PRON	PRP	Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=2|Poss=Yes|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
28	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
29	power	power	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
30	for	for	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
31	real	real	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=O
32	equality	equality	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
33	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
34	gender	gender	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
35	equality	equality	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
36	everywhere	everywhere	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
37	and	and	CCONJ	CC	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
38	every	every	DET	DT	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
39	day	day	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
40	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg576
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-SI_2015-03-06-SDZ7-Redna-05.ana.seg576.1
# text = I also adjourn the fifth session of the National Assembly, which will be resumed on Monday 9. Three o'clock.
1	I	I	PRON	PRP	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	-1	-	_	NER=O
2	also	also	ADV	RB	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
3	adjourn	adjourn	VERB	VBP	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
5	fifth	fifth	ADJ	JJ	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	-1	-	_	NER=O
6	session	session	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
7	of	of	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	DT	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	-1	-	_	NER=O
9	National	National	ADJ	NNP	Degree=Pos	-1	-	_	NER=B-ORG
10	Assembly	Assembly	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
12	which	which	PRON	WDT	PronType=Rel	-1	-	_	NER=O
13	will	will	AUX	MD	VerbForm=Fin	-1	-	_	NER=O
14	be	be	AUX	VB	VerbForm=Inf	-1	-	_	NER=O
15	resumed	resume	VERB	VBN	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	-1	-	_	NER=O
16	on	on	ADP	IN	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
17	Monday	Monday	PROPN	NNP	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O
18	9	9	NUM	CD	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
19	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O
20	Three	three	NUM	CD	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	-1	-	_	NER=O
21	o'clock	o'clock	NOUN	NN	Number=Sing	-1	-	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
22	.	.	PUNCT	Z	_	-1	-	_	NER=O

