# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.u1
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg1
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg1.s1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = positive
# senti_n = 4.592
# text = Good afternoon.
1	Good	good	ADJ	Z4	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
2	afternoon	afternoon	NOUN	Z4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
3	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg2
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg2.s1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = mixed positive
# senti_n = 3.832
# text = The session is open.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	session	session	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	open	open	ADJ	A10p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg2.s2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.398
# text = The agenda is published in the Official Gazette of Parliament of 19 May 2022, so it is not read.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	agenda	agenda	NOUN	Q1.2|X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	published	publish	VERB	Q4	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
5	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	Official	official	ADJ	T1.3	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
8	Gazette	Gazette	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
9	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	19	19	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
13	May	May	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	2022	2022	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	so	so	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	it	it	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Gender=Neut|Number=Sing|Person=3|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
18	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
19	not	not	PART	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	read	read	VERB	Q3	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
21	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg3
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg3.s1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.942
# text = There's no justification for non-attendance and we're on the agenda.
1	There	there	PRON	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	's	be	VERB	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	no	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	justification	justification	NOUN	G2.2p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
5	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	non-attendance	non-attendance	NOUN	S1.1.3n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
9	're	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
10	on	on	ADP	A7p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	A7p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	agenda	agenda	NOUN	A7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg4
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg4.s1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.561
# text = The only point of this plenary is the appointment of two senators or senators representatives of the Autonomous Community of Galicia to replace Ms Elena Muñoz Fonteriz and Mr Juan Carlos Serrano López.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	only	only	ADJ	A14	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
3	point	point	NOUN	Q2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
6	plenary	plenary	NOUN	S1.1.3p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	appointment	appointment	NOUN	T1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	two	two	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
12	senators	senator	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
13	or	or	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	senators	senator	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
15	representatives	representative	NOUN	Q2.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Autonomous	Autonomous	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
19	Community	Community	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Galicia	Galicia	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
22	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	replace	replace	VERB	A2.1p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
24	Ms	Ms	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
25	Elena	Elena	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
26	Muñoz	Muñoz	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
27	Fonteriz	Fonteriz	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
28	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	Juan	Juan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
31	Carlos	Carlos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
32	Serrano	Serrano	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
33	López	López	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
34	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg5
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg5.s1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.747
# text = Designation of two senators or senators representatives of the Autonomous Community of Galicia to replace Da Elena Muñoz Fonteriz and Juan Carlos Serrano López
1	Designation	designation	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	two	two	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
4	senators	senator	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
5	or	or	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	senators	senator	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
7	representatives	representative	NOUN	Q2.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	Autonomous	Autonomous	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
11	Community	Community	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	Galicia	Galicia	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
14	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	replace	replace	VERB	A2.1p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Da	Da	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
17	Elena	Elena	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
18	Muñoz	Muñoz	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
19	Fonteriz	Fonteriz	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
20	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	Juan	Juan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
22	Carlos	Carlos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
23	Serrano	Serrano	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
24	López	López	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.u2
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg6
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg6.s1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.723
# text = The agreement of the Bureau and the Speakers' Board of 18 May began the procedure for the appointment of two senators or senators representing the Autonomous Community of Galicia as the replacement of Ms Elena Muñoz Fonteriz and Mr Juan Carlos Serrano López, appointed by this Chamber on 19 November 2019 and on 26 October 2021 respectively and on a proposal from the People's Parliamentary Group.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	agreement	agreement	NOUN	A6.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Bureau	Bureau	PROPN	G1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
6	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
7	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
8	Speakers	Speakers	PROPN	Q2.1|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
9	'	'	PUNCT	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
10	Board	board	NOUN	S7.1p|S5p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
11	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
12	18	18	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
13	May	May	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
14	began	begin	VERB	T2p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	procedure	procedure	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
17	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
19	appointment	appointment	NOUN	T1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	two	two	NUM	N1	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
22	senators	senator	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
23	or	or	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
24	senators	senator	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
25	representing	represent	VERB	Q1.1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Autonomous	Autonomous	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
28	Community	Community	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
29	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
30	Galicia	Galicia	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
31	as	as	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
33	replacement	replacement	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
34	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
35	Ms	Ms	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
36	Elena	Elena	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
37	Muñoz	Muñoz	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
38	Fonteriz	Fonteriz	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
39	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
40	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
41	Juan	Juan	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
42	Carlos	Carlos	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
43	Serrano	Serrano	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
44	López	López	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
45	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
46	appointed	appoint	VERB	S7.1p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
47	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
48	this	this	DET	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
49	Chamber	Chamber	PROPN	H2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
50	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
51	19	19	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
52	November	November	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
53	2019	2019	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
54	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
55	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
56	26	26	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
57	October	October	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
58	2021	2021	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
59	respectively	respectively	ADV	A6.1n	_	0	_	_	NER=O
60	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
61	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
62	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
63	proposal	proposal	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
64	from	from	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
65	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
66	People	People	PROPN	S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
67	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
68	Parliamentary	Parliamentary	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
69	Group	Group	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
70	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg6.s2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.951
# text = All of this is done in accordance with Article 165(4) of the Rules of Procedure.
1	All	all	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	this	this	PRON	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
4	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	done	do	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
6	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	accordance	accordance	NOUN	S7.1n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	Article	article	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
10	165	165	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
11	(	(	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
12	4	4	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	)	)	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Rules	rule	NOUN	G2.1	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
17	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
18	Procedure	procedure	NOUN	X4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC|SpaceAfter=No
19	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg7
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg7.s1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.039
# text = By resolution of the Presidency of 23 May 2022, candidates for senators representing the Autonomous Community of Galicia were accepted by Mr Alberto Núñez Feijóo and Mr Miguel Ángel Tellado Filgueira.
1	By	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	resolution	resolution	NOUN	X6p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Presidency	Presidency	PROPN	S7.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	23	23	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
8	May	May	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	2022	2022	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	candidates	candidate	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
12	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	senators	senator	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
14	representing	represent	VERB	Q1.1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
15	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
16	Autonomous	Autonomous	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
17	Community	Community	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
18	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
19	Galicia	Galicia	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	were	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
21	accepted	accept	VERB	A9p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
22	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
24	Alberto	Alberto	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
25	Núñez	Núñez	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
26	Feijóo	Feijóo	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
27	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
29	Miguel	Miguel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
30	Ángel	Ángel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
31	Tellado	Tellado	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
32	Filgueira	Filgueira	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg7.s2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.741
# text = The election shall be made by ballot in accordance with Article 91 of the Galician Parliament's Regulation.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	election	election	NOUN	G1.2|X7p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	shall	shall	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
5	made	make	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
6	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	ballot	ballot	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	accordance	accordance	NOUN	S7.1n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Article	article	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
12	91	91	NUM	Z2	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=I-MISC
13	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Galician	Galician	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
16	Parliament	Parliament	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	's	's	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Regulation	Regulation	PROPN	G2.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
19	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg7.s3
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.021
# text = For these purposes, the House services have drawn up a paper with the name of the proposed candidates, which will mark with a stamp the box of the candidate or of the candidates to whom the support is given.
1	For	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	these	this	DET	Z5	Number=Plur|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
3	purposes	purpose	NOUN	X7p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	House	House	PROPN	T1.3	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
7	services	service	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
8	have	have	AUX	A9p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
9	drawn	draw	VERB	C1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
10	up	up	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	paper	paper	NOUN	Q4.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
15	name	name	NOUN	Q2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	proposed	propose	VERB	Q2.2|X7p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
19	candidates	candidate	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
20	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
22	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
23	mark	mark	VERB	O4.2n	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
24	with	with	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
26	stamp	stamp	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
27	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
28	box	box	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
29	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
31	candidate	candidate	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
32	or	or	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
33	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
35	candidates	candidate	NOUN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
36	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
37	whom	whom	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
38	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
39	support	support	NOUN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
40	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
41	given	give	VERB	A9n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
42	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg7.s4
# senti_3 = Negative
# senti_6 = mixed negative
# senti_n = 1.137
# text = If no box is marked, a blank vote will be considered; and if any amendments, ransomed or any other additions are introduced, a null vote will be declared.
1	If	if	SCONJ	Z7	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	no	no	DET	Z6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	box	box	NOUN	O2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
4	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	marked	mark	VERB	O4.2n	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
8	blank	blank	ADJ	O4.1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
9	vote	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
11	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
12	considered	consider	VERB	X2.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
13	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
14	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	if	if	SCONJ	Z7	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	any	any	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	amendments	amendment	NOUN	A2.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	ransomed	ransom	VERB	I1.3	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
20	or	or	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
21	any	any	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	other	other	ADJ	A6.1n	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
23	additions	addition	NOUN	N5p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
24	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
25	introduced	introduce	VERB	S1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
26	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	a	a	DET	Z5	Definite=Ind|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
28	null	null	ADJ	Z99	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
29	vote	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
30	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
31	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
32	declared	declare	VERB	Q2.2	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg8
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg8.s1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.595
# text = When all Members are already in possession of the papers, we shall proceed to the vote, which will be on call and which will be made by the Secretary of the House, Ms Corina Porro.
1	When	when	SCONJ	Z5	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
2	all	all	DET	N5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	Members	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
4	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
5	already	already	ADV	T1.1.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	possession	possession	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
8	of	of	ADP	A5.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	A5.1p	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	papers	paper	NOUN	A5.1p	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
11	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
13	shall	shall	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
14	proceed	proceed	VERB	A1.1.1	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
15	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
17	vote	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
18	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
20	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
21	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
22	on	on	ADP	I3.1	_	0	_	_	NER=O
23	call	call	NOUN	I3.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
24	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	which	which	PRON	Z5	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
26	will	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
27	be	be	AUX	A3p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
28	made	make	VERB	A1.1.1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
29	by	by	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
31	Secretary	Secretary	PROPN	I3.2|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
32	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
33	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
34	House	House	PROPN	H4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
35	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
36	Ms	Ms	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
37	Corina	Corina	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
38	Porro	Porro	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
39	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg8.s2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral negative
# senti_n = 2.398
# text = And for this I pray the second vice president and the vice secretary, Mrs. Prado Cores and Mrs. Ortega, who stand next to the urn to pick up the paperwork.
1	And	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
2	for	for	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	this	this	PRON	M6	Number=Sing|PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
4	I	I	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Sing|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
5	pray	pray	VERB	S9|Q2.2	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=1|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
6	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
7	second	second	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos|NumType=Ord	0	_	_	NER=O
8	vice	vice	NOUN	S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
9	president	president	NOUN	S7.1p|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
12	vice	vice	NOUN	G2.2n	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
13	secretary	secretary	NOUN	I3.2|S2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
14	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Mrs.	Mrs.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
16	Prado	Prado	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
17	Cores	Cores	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
18	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
19	Mrs.	Mrs.	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
20	Ortega	Ortega	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER|SpaceAfter=No
21	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	who	who	PRON	Z8	PronType=Rel	0	_	_	NER=O
23	stand	stand	VERB	M6	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
24	next	next	ADV	N4	_	0	_	_	NER=O
25	to	to	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
26	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
27	urn	urn	NOUN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
28	to	to	PART	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
29	pick	pick	VERB	X7p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
30	up	up	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
31	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
32	paperwork	paperwork	NOUN	Q1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
33	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg9
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg9.s1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 2.738
# text = Whenever you wish, Madam Secretary, you can start by calling Members and Members.
1	Whenever	whenever	SCONJ	Z5	PronType=Int	0	_	_	NER=O
2	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
3	wish	wish	VERB	X7p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=2|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
4	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
5	Madam	madam	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
6	Secretary	Secretary	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	you	you	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Person=2|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O
9	can	can	AUX	A7p	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
10	start	start	VERB	T2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
11	by	by	SCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
12	calling	call	VERB	Q2.2	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
13	Members	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
14	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	Members	Member	PROPN	S5p|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
16	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.u4
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg13
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg13.s1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.118
# text = The result is the following: votes in favour of Mr. Alberto Núñez Feijóo, 41; votes in favour of Mr. Miguel Ángel Tellado Filgueira, 41; votes in favour of Mr.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	result	result	NOUN	A2.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	is	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
5	following	follow	VERB	M1	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
6	:	:	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
7	votes	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
8	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
9	favour	favour	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
10	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	Alberto	Alberto	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
13	Núñez	Núñez	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
14	Feijóo	Feijóo	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
15	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
16	41	41	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
17	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
18	votes	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
19	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
20	favour	favour	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
21	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
22	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Miguel	Miguel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
24	Ángel	Ángel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
25	Tellado	Tellado	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
26	Filgueira	Filgueira	PROPN	Z99	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
27	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
28	41	41	NUM	N1	NumForm=Digit|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
29	;	;	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
30	votes	vote	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O
31	in	in	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
32	favour	favour	NOUN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
33	of	of	ADP	Z2	_	0	_	_	NER=O
34	Mr.	Mr.	PROPN	Z2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O

# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg14
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg14.s1
# senti_3 = Positive
# senti_6 = positive
# senti_n = 4.787
# text = The voting was favourable.
1	The	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
2	voting	voting	NOUN	G1.2	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
3	was	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Past|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
4	favourable	favourable	ADJ	A5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
5	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg14.s2
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.265
# text = So, having reached the support of the House, Senators are appointed on behalf of the Autonomous Community of Galicia Fr Alberto Núñez Feijóo and Mr Miguel Ángel Tellado Filgueira.
1	So	so	ADV	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
2	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
3	having	have	AUX	A9p	VerbForm=Ger	0	_	_	NER=O
4	reached	reach	VERB	M1	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part	0	_	_	NER=O
5	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
6	support	support	NOUN	S8p	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
7	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
8	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
9	House	House	PROPN	H4	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG|SpaceAfter=No
10	,	,	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O
11	Senators	Senator	PROPN	G1.2|S2	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=B-MISC
12	are	be	AUX	A3p	Mood=Ind|Number=Plur|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
13	appointed	appoint	VERB	S7.1p	Tense=Past|VerbForm=Part|Voice=Pass	0	_	_	NER=O
14	on	on	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
15	behalf	behalf	NOUN	S1.1.1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
16	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
17	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
18	Autonomous	Autonomous	ADJ	Z1	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=B-ORG
19	Community	Community	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
20	of	of	ADP	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
21	Galicia	Galicia	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-ORG
22	Fr	Fr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
23	Alberto	Alberto	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
24	Núñez	Núñez	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
25	Feijóo	Feijóo	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
26	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
27	Mr	Mr	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
28	Miguel	Miguel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=B-PER
29	Ángel	Ángel	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
30	Tellado	Tellado	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER
31	Filgueira	Filgueira	PROPN	Z1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=I-PER|SpaceAfter=No
32	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

# newdoc id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.u5
# newpar id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg15
# lang = en
# sent_id = ParlaMint-ES-GA_2022-05-24-DSPG082.seg15.s1
# senti_3 = Neutral
# senti_6 = neutral positive
# senti_n = 3.346
# text = Here ends this full and we'll start the next one in two minutes.
1	Here	here	ADV	M6	PronType=Dem	0	_	_	NER=O
2	ends	end	VERB	T2n	Mood=Ind|Number=Sing|Person=3|Tense=Pres|VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
3	this	this	ADV	M6	_	0	_	_	NER=O
4	full	full	ADJ	N5.1p	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
5	and	and	CCONJ	Z5	_	0	_	_	NER=O
6	we	we	PRON	Z8	Case=Nom|Number=Plur|Person=1|PronType=Prs	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
7	'll	will	AUX	T1.1.3	VerbForm=Fin	0	_	_	NER=O
8	start	start	VERB	T2p	VerbForm=Inf	0	_	_	NER=O
9	the	the	DET	Z5	Definite=Def|PronType=Art	0	_	_	NER=O
10	next	next	ADJ	N4	Degree=Pos	0	_	_	NER=O
11	one	one	NOUN	N1	Number=Sing	0	_	_	NER=O
12	in	in	ADP	A2.1p	_	0	_	_	NER=O
13	two	two	NUM	A2.1p	NumForm=Word|NumType=Card	0	_	_	NER=O
14	minutes	minute	NOUN	T1.3	Number=Plur	0	_	_	NER=O|SpaceAfter=No
15	.	.	PUNCT	Z9	_	0	_	_	NER=O

